<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?><rss version='2.0' xmlns:dc='http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/'><channel>

<title>Hundred Rabbits</title>
<link>https://100r.co</link>
<description>Rek and Devine project updates</description>
 <image>
<url>https://100r.co/media/services/rss.jpg</url>
<title>Hundred Rabbits</title>
<link>https://100r.co</link>
</image>

<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for December 2024</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/log.html#dec2024</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>log.html#dec2024</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone!</p><p>This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects during the month of December.</p>

<img src="../media/content/videos/december_2024.jpg" alt="a seal in a halfmoon position" loading="lazy" width="1200" height="679">

<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>

<ul>
  <li><b>100r.co</b>, updated the documentation for our various <a href="https://100r.co/site/projects.html">projects</a>.</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://100r.co/site/left.html">Left</a></b>, added support for <a href="https://merveilles.town/@neauoire/113671244114664911" target="_blank">unicode input</a>(Mastodon).</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://100r.co/site/rabbit_waves.html">Rabbit Waves</a></b>, added a page on <a href="https://rabbitwaves.ca/site/aircraft.html" target="_blank">Air to Ground Signals</a>.</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://eli.li/december-adventure" target="_blank">December Adventure</a></b>, collected <a href="https://rabbits.srht.site/decadv/#2024" target="_blank">Devine's code experiments</a>.</li>
</ul>

<p>Before diving into the ins and outs of the past year, we'd like to begin by sending our very warmest thanks to everyone who generously hosted us, drove us to the hardware store, invited us out for fries to cheer us up, fixed typos in the books, improved the documentation, lent us power-tools, donated to the studio, spent hours to show us how to fix broken things and corrected us when we were wrong.</p>

<p>During the first few weeks of the year, we were busy with planning our upcoming sail north to Alaska, during which a DDoS attack took down many of our repositories and precipitated our decentralizing of the project source files. Mirroring our projects across multiple forges and diversifying the means in which they were available became necessary.</p>

<p>In preparation for the heavy weather up north, we strengthened the <a href="https://100r.co/site/chainplates.html">chainplates</a> and replaced a few <i>experienced</i> halyards. In fact, our most vivid memories of the early spring was of the blisters we made splicing dyneema. We've also built ourselves a <a href="https://100r.co/site/gimballed_stove.html">gimballed stove</a> with space for an <a href="https://100r.co/site/open_pantry.html">open pantry</a> allowing us to store more fresh vegetables by doing away with the oven.</p>

<p>Our summer was spent exploring the Northern Canada and Alaskan coastline to test the recent <a href="https://100r.co/site/boat_projects.html">boat projects</a>, a sort of shakedown if you will, in preparation for plans we may divulge in a future update. During our transit, we began writing down notes on various forms of analog communication which have now mostly fallen into obscurity. These notes later became an integral part of the <a href="https://100r.co/site/rabbit_waves.html">Rabbit Waves</a> project, created with the hope of sparking an interest in these valuable but vanishing skillsets.</p>

<p>Through it all, we continued improving the <a href="https://100r.co/site/uxn.html">Uxn</a> ecosystem documentation and toolchain, which has played a central role in our work now for four years! We've also explored other enticing avenues where small robust virtual machines could be used for knowledge preservation, namely Conway's <a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/fractran.html' target='_blank'>Fractran</a>, which all came together into the <a href="https://100r.co/site/shining_sand.html">Shining Sand</a> talk given at the the year's end.</p>

<p>We're looking cautiously forward to the challenges that awaits us all in 2025. Approaching these adversarial forces with collective tactical preparedness and clarity is more important than ever, and we shall all rise to the occasion!</p>

<p>We had a lot of really good wildlife moments this year, and so the last drawing of 2024 is of a half-mooning seal.</p>

<p><b>Book Club:</b> This month we are reading <i>The Secret History</i> by Donna Tartt. Our favorite book this year was <b>West with the Night</b> by Beryl Markham, see all of the other <a href="../site/library.html#2024">books</a> we read in 2024.</p>

<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/log.html#dec2024' target='_blank'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for November 2024</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/log.html#nov2024</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>log.html#nov2024</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone!</p><p>This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects during the month of November.</p>

<img src="../media/content/videos/november_2024.jpg" alt="6 algae-eared rabbits posing and playing together" loading="lazy">

<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>

<ul>
  <li><b>100r.co</b>, added an article named <a href="https://100r.co/site/shining_sand.html">A Shining Place Built Upon The Sand</a>, and <a href="https://100r.co/site/victoria_to_sitka_logbook.html#week6">Week 6</a> to the <a href="https://100r.co/site/victoria_to_sitka_logbook.html">Victoria to Sitka Logbook</a>.</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://100r.co/site/rabbit_waves.html">Rabbit Waves</a></b>, added a page on <a href="https://rabbitwaves.ca/site/morse.html" target="_blank">Morse Code</a> and on <a href="https://rabbitwaves.ca/site/morse_flags.html" target="_blank">Morse Code with flags</a>.</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://100r.co/site/left.html">Left</a></b>, redesigned with a <a href="https://100r.co/media/content/stream/2024_leftfont.jpg">bigger font</a>, for aging eyes.</li>
</ul>

<p>Our website has a new look! The illustrated algae-eared rabbit nav helped solve the problem of navigating on mobile. We added a lot of information to this wiki over the years, creating separate portals for its evergrowing content was inevitable, we hope you like the re-design. Some of the content has shifted, and we've simplified many of the pages.</p>

<p>A couple of folks on <a href="https://merveilles.town" target="_blank">Merveilles</a> got together recently and made a Diablo Tribute tape. A limited run of physical cassettes are currently in production, but in the meantime the tribute album is available to download on <a href="https://spectralepoch.bandcamp.com/album/a-tribute-to-diablo" target="_blank">Bandcamp</a>.</p>

<p>Next month on December 6th, Devine will share the stage with Iszoloscope, Oddie(Orphx) & Creature at Foufounes Electriques in Montréal as part of <a href="https://ampindustrialevents.com/index.html" target="_blank">AMP Industrial Events</a>. Then on the 7th, we will both(remotely) present a summary of all the interesting analog communication schemes that inspired and found their way into <a href="https://100r.co/site/rabbit_waves.html">Rabbit Waves</a> and <a href="https://100r.co/site/wiktopher.html">Wiktopher</a> for <a href="https://creativecodingutrecht.nl/en/calendar/iterations-2024" target="_blank">Iterations 2024</a> organized by Creative Coding Utrecht.</p>

<p>Devine's talk for Handmade Seattle 2024 entitled A Shining Palace Built Upon the Sand was <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OfnEfFb8yks&t=1908s" target="_blank">released online</a>(YouTube), we also released the <a href="https://100r.co/site/shining_sand.html">written transcript</a>.</p>

<p>Due to the ongoing Canada Post strike we had to close the sale of stickers in our <a href="https://100r.co/site/store.html">store</a>, we'll let you know once we resume operations (this also applies to Patreon supporters, we'll ship perks your way as soon as we can).</p>

<p><b>Book Club:</b> This month we are still reading <i>The Memoirs of Sherlock Holmes</i> by Arthur Conan Doyle.</p>

<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/log.html#nov2024' target='_blank'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for October 2024</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/log.html#oct2024</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>log.html#oct2024</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone!</p><p>This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects during the month of October.</p>

<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>
<img src="https://100r.co/media/content/videos/october_2024.jpg" alt="little ninj has carved a pumpkin, saying BEE-HOLD! The pumpkin is smiling, in a non-threatening and eager kind of way. A bowl with pumpkin pulp and a knife are laying nearby with some fallen tree leaves scattered on the ground" loading="lazy">

<ul>
  <li><b>100r.co</b>, added <a href="https://100r.co/site/rabbit_waves.html">Rabbit Waves</a> and <a href="https://100r.co/site/logbooks.html">Logbooks</a>. Updated <a href='https://100r.co/site/woodstove_installation.html#oct2024'>woodstove installation</a>, <a href="https://100r.co/site/no_windlass.html">no windlass</a> with <a href="https://100r.co/media/content/knowledge/anchoring_gloves_old.jpg" target="_blank">1 photo</a>, <a href="https://100r.co/site/mini_dodger.html#october2023">mini dodger</a> and <a href="https://100r.co/site/victoria_to_sitka_logbook.html">Victoria to Sitka logbook</a> with Week <a href="https://100r.co/site/victoria_to_sitka_logbook.html#week3">3</a> and <a href="https://100r.co/site/victoria_to_sitka_logbook.html#week4">4</a>.</li>
</ul>

<p>Pino is back in Victoria. Being back in a city also means that we are shipping <a href="https://100r.co/site/store.html#stickers">sticker sheets</a> again! Devine found a spirograph set at a thrift store for 5$, we now make <a href="https://100r.co/media/content/stream/2024_spiro.jpg">patterns</a> on every letter we ship.</p>

<p>We are happy to announce the official release of <a href="https://100r.co/site/rabbit_waves.html">Rabbit Waves</a>! The idea for the project came after discussing the disappearance of certain traditional seasteading skills and maritime communication knowledge that we believe are valuable when electronics misbehave, but that are also just generally fun to learn and use. The world of the micro-site will grow as we think of new ideas to expand it.</p>

<p>Devine participated in <a href='https://forum.merveilles.town/thread/101/drawtober-2024-109/' target='_blank'>Drawtober</a> again this year and completed a <a href="https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/pocket_rewriting.html" target="_blank">zine</a> that teaches the basics of multiset rewriting with examples, it also includes the source for a tiny Fractran interpreter. Since its release, many people have printed their own. Avanier went a step further and <a href="https://100r.co/media/content/stream/2024_joshavanier_zine.jpg" target="_blank">re-drew the zine</a> on black paper! Devine also released an <a href="https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/tote.html" target="_blank">interactive version</a>, and CapitalEx created with it a <a href='https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5yiso80ANlc'>beautiful little world to explore</a>! <a href='https://handmadecities.com/seattle/'>Handmade Seattle 2024</a> is coming up, Devine will be there to talk about weird computer stuff, and will hand out copies of the zine too.</p>

<p>This year, we carved a Calcifer <a href="https://100r.co/media/content/inventory/pumpkin_calcifer_01.jpg" target="_blank">pumpkin</a> (see our other <a href="https://100r.co/site/halloween_pumpkins.html">Halloween pumpkins</a>).</p>

<p><b>Book Club:</b> This month we read <i>The Memoirs of Sherlock Holmes</i> by Arthur Conan Doyle.</p>

<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/log.html#oct2024' target='_blank'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for September 2024</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/log.html#sep2024</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>log.html#sep2024</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone!</p><p>This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects during the month of September.</p>

<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>
<img src="https://100r.co/media/content/videos/september_2024.jpg" alt="rek, dev and little ninj sitting around a small fire" loading="lazy">

<ul>
  <li><b><a href="https://100r.co">100r.co</a></b>, added a new page: <a href="https://100r.co/site/victoria_to_sitka_logbook.html">Victoria to Sitka logbook</a>.</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/m291.html" target="_blank">M291</a></b>, added support for <a href="https://100r.co/media/content/stream/2024_cyrillic_m291.jpg" target="_blank">Cyrillic glyphs</a>.</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/fractran.html">Fractran</a></b>, released what might be the most in-depth documentation of Conway's programming language out there.</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/now_lie_in_it.html" target="_blank">Now Lie In It</a></b>, a look back at what has happened with <a href="https://100r.co/site/uxn.html">Uxn</a> since its creation 4 years ago.</li>
</ul>

<p>September started off warm, but got cold and windy fast, we spent lots of time sitting by the woodstove drinking tea. As promised, we have begun transcribing the <a href="https://100r.co/site/victoria_to_sitka_logbook.html">Victoria to Sitka logbook</a> digitally, we release one week's worth of logs at a time. We populated the logs with photos and Rek's sketches(also sourced from the handwritten logbook). End of the month, we closed our <a href="https://100r.co/site/western_canada.html#2024">summer 2024</a> sailing route, Pino has traveled very far this year! We made 76(!!!) stops over a period of 5 months, sailing 1900 NM.</p>

<p>We announced a new project this month named <a href="https://rabbitwaves.ca" target="_blank">Rabbit Waves</a>. It will serve as a vessel to expand, in a playful way, on some of our favourite things. Expect lots of art featuring root vegetable root-shaped sailboats, rabbits, and seabirds! The website will host more content next month.</p>

<p>For 3 years now, we've had a monthly <a href="https://100r.co/media/content/stream/2024_calendar.jpg">hand-drawn calendar</a> in the galley that we cover with doodles, at the end of the year, Rek binds the 12 pages together, and it makes it easy to look back at where we were, what we were doing at a previous time. Everyday has some kind of highlight or other. It's one of our favourite habits.</p>

<p>Listen to Devine's remix of SOPHIE's <a href="https://soundcloud.com/neauoire/sophie-one-more-time" target="_blank">One More Time feat. Popstar</a>.</p>

<p><b>Book Club:</b> This month we read <i>Project Hail Mary</i> by Andy Weir. We are forever in love with Rocky.</p>

<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/log.html#sep2024' target='_blank'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for August 2024</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/log.html#aug2024</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>log.html#aug2024</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone!</p><p>This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects during the month of August.</p>

<img src="https://100r.co/media/content/videos/august_2024.jpg" loading="lazy">

<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>
<ul>
  <li><b>100r.co</b>, added new pages: <a href="https://100r.co/site/sointula.html">Sointula</a>, <a href="https://100r.co/site/johnstone_strait_anchorages.html">Johnstone Strait anchorages</a>, and <a href="https://100r.co/site/central_coast_anchorages.html">Central coast anchorages</a>. Updated existing pages: added <a href="https://100r.co/site/yuculta_and_dent_rapids.html">Yuculta and Dent rapids</a> with <a href="https://100r.co/site/yuculta_and_dent_rapids.html#southbound">southbound tactics</a>, <a href="https://100r.co/site/no_windlass.html">no windlass</a> with 3 new photos, <a href="https://100r.co/site/lpg.html">lpg</a> with <a href="https://100r.co/site/lpg.html#troubleshoot">troubleshooting</a>, and <a href="https://100r.co/site/gimballed_stove.html">gimballed stove</a> with <a href="https://100r.co/site/gimballed_stove.html#performance">performance tests</a>.</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://100r.co/site/left.html">Left</a></b>, added support for macros.</li>
  <li><b><a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/uxnfor.html' target='_blank'>Uxnfor</a></b>, added support for macros.</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://100r.co/site/uxn.html">Uxn</a></b>, found a tiny optimization that makes things a bit faster.</li>
  <li><b><a href='https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/uxn-utils/tree/main/item/gui/m291' target='_blank'>M291</a></b>, started a little music player for <a href='https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/uxn11' target='_blank'>Uxn11</a>.</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://100r.co/site/wiktopher.html">Wiktopher</a></b>, updated some Solresol words in the <a href="https://kokorobot/site/ilken.html" target="_blank">Ilken songs</a> featured in the book.</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/hakum.html" target="_blank">Hakum</a></b>, added a new comic named <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/smile.html" target="_blank">Smile</a>.</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/wunderland_rabbits.html" target="_blank">Wunderland Rabbits</a></b>, added a new <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/wunderland_14_full.jpg" target="_blank">rabbit pic</a>.</li>
</ul>

<p>This month, Pino reached the northern tip of Vancouver Island, sailed south through Johnstone Strait, and into calmer, familiar waters on the 11th of August. Both of us were eager for a taste of summer weather, we hoped to catch what was left of it. Our legs demanded an anchorage with options for walking, so we chose to anchor in <a href="https://100r.co/site/hathayim_marine_park.html">Hathayim Marine Park</a>. The lovely people on the sailboat Nanamuk were anchored here too, they <a href="https://100r.co/site/hathayim_marine_park.html#aug2024">mapped many of the trails</a> in the area, even the overgrown, less-traveled routes. We <a href="https://100r.co/site/western_canada.html#2024">updated our summer route map</a> through northern B.C.</p>

<p>From May 1st to August 11th, like with our book <a href="https://100r.co/site/busy_doing_nothing.html">Busy Doing Nothing</a>, Rek kept a detailed logbook of daily happenings onboard. We hope to publish these notes to this wiki soon.</p>

<p><b>Book Club:</b> This month we are reading <i>The Adventures of Sherlock Holmes</i> by Arthur Conan Doyle, <i>The Design of Everyday Things</i> by Don Norman, and <i>Everyday Utopia: What 2000 years of Wild Experiments Can Teach Us About the Good Life</i> by Kristen R. Ghodsee.</p>

<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/log.html#aug2024' target='_blank'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for July 2024</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/log.html#jul2024</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>log.html#jul2024</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone!</p><p>This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects during the month of July.</p>

<img src="https://100r.co/media/content/videos/july_2024.jpg" loading="lazy">

<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>
<ul>
  <li><b>100r.co</b>, added <a href="https://100r.co/site/sitka.html" target="_blank">Sitka</a>, and completed route in <a href="https://100r.co/site/us_se_alaska.html">us se alaska</a>.</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://100r.co/site/left.html" target="_blank">Left</a></b>, can now paste binary directly from programs like <a href="https://100r.co/site/nasu.html" target="_blank">Nasu</a>.</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/hakum.html" target="_blank">Hakum</a></b>, added two drawings to the <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/hakum.html#characters">Characters</a> section, and a new very short comic called <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/hakum_shoes.jpg" target="_blank">Shoes</a>.</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://100r.co/site/wiktopher.html" target="_blank">Wiktopher</a></b>, fixed some typos.</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://100r.co/site/markl.html" target="_blank">Markl</a></b>, we don't have much of anything to show for it yet, but who knows, maybe this time <a href='https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/markl' target='_blank'>it will work out</a>!</li>
  <li><a href='https://rabbits.srht.site/solrela/#cat' target='_blank'>Solrela</a>, expanded Solresol dictionary.</li>
  <li><a href='https://forum.malleable.systems/t/fearless-extensibility-extending-think-pascal/213' target='_blank'>Malleable Systems</a>, wrote a little thing about extending compiled software with devtools.</li>
</ul>

<p>Pino and crew have moved a lot in the past month. On the first of July, we were in Sitka, Southeast Alaska, and then on the last day of the month we were back in Millbrook Cove, very near to the top of Vancouver Island. We sailed 590 NM and stopped in 15 different anchorages.</p>

<p>Leaving Sitka, we sailed along the west coast of Southeast Alaska for a few days to try and take advantage of a good weather window, we had some engine issues which too motivated the need for such a long passage(see our <a href="https://100r.co/media/content/maps/sealaska_2024.jpg" target="_blank">track</a>)—we spent two days troubleshooting the issue while anchored in Port Bazan, a bay far from everything, with no internet connection or way to talk to anybody, we were glad to have the physical engine manual on board. Sailing on open waters is always nice, we saw black-footed albatrosses, horned puffins, a whale per hour, and many more sea otters(Port Bazan was full of them).</p>

<p>After checking back into <a href="https://100r.co/site/prince_rupert.html" target="_blank">Prince Rupert</a>, the way back south through Northern Canada was plagued with unfavorable winds, we had to beat into it, or travel on quiet waters to make progress. We resorted to doing short hops between anchorages, conditions did not permit for long distances. Doing short hops though did allow us to discover beautiful places we might have otherwise missed. We spent many grey days waiting for weather, reading, drawing, and beginning work on <a href="https://100r.co/site/markl.html" target="_blank">markl</a>, we're giving it another go).</p>

<p><b>Book Club:</b> This month we read <i>Erewhon</i> by Samuel Butler, <i>Technophilia and Its Discontents</i> by Ellen Ullman, <i>The Democracy Of Species</i> by Robin Wall Kimmerer, <i>I Will Fight No More Forever</i> by Merrill D. Beal, <i>In Cold Blood</i> by Truman Capote, and <i>Mrs Dalloway</i> by Virginia Woolf.</p>

<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/log.html#jul2024' target='_blank'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for June 2024</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/log.html#jun2024</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>log.html#jun2024</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone!</p><p>This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects during the month of June.</p>

<img src="https://100r.co/media/content/videos/june_2024.jpg" loading="lazy">

<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>
<ul>
  <li><b>100r.co</b>, added <a href="https://100r.co/site/ketchikan.html" target="_blank">Ketchikan</a>, <a href="https://100r.co/site/snug_cove.html" target="_blank">Snug Cove</a>, <a href="https://100r.co/site/ratz_harbor.html" target="_blank">Ratz Harbor</a>, <a href="https://100r.co/site/frosty_bay.html" target="_blank">Frosty Bay</a>, <a href="https://100r.co/site/berg_bay.html" target="_blank">Berg Bay</a>, <a href="https://100r.co/site/wrangell.html" target="_blank">Wrangell</a>, <a href="https://100r.co/site/petersburg.html" target="_blank">Petersburg</a> and <a href="https://100r.co/site/ruth_island_cove.html" target="_blank">Ruth Island Cove</a>. Updated <a href="https://100r.co/site/library.html" target="_blank">library</a>.</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/oekaki.html" target="_blank">Oekaki</a></b>, optimized and added a selection tool.</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://100r.co/site/nasu.html">Nasu</a></b>, fixed selection issue.</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://rabbits.srht.site/uxn5/" target="_blank">Uxn5</a></b>, redesigned and made responsive for mobile.</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/uxn-utils/tree/main/item/cli/uxndis" target="_blank">Uxndis</a></b>, wrote a disassembler.</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://wiki.xxiivv.com/etc/uxnrepl/" target="_blank">Uxnrepl</a></b>, added step-by-step evaluation.</li>
</ul>

<p>We spent all of June cruising through Southeast Alaska, we visited 4 cities and stopped by 14 different anchorages. On June 27th, 420 nautical miles later, we arrived in the beautiful town of Sitka — our favorite city so far.</p>

<p>We have sailed as far north as we are willing to go this year, at 57°N — the same latitude as Kodiak. Sailing in these waters has been challenging, there is a lot of current, and the wind is often light, or absent. Because of these frequent calms, <a href="https://100r.co/site/engine_care.html" target="_blank">Calcifer II</a> has seen a lot of use this year. We will now slowly make our way back south, exploring new anchorages along the west coast of Southeast Alaska all the while. We continue to update our path in Alaska <a href="https://100r.co/site/us_se_alaska.html" target="_blank">here</a>, when we cross back into Canada we'll resume updates <a href="https://100r.co/site/western_canada.html#2024" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>

<p><b>Book Club:</b> This month we are reading <i>West With the Night</i> by Beryl Markham.</p>
<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/log.html#jun2024' target='_blank'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for May 2024</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/log.html#may2024</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>log.html#may2024</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone!</p><p>This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects during the month of May.</p>

<img src="https://100r.co/media/content/videos/may_2024.jpg" loading="lazy">

<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>
<ul>
  <li><b>100r.co</b>, added <a href="https://100r.co/site/frances_bay.html">Frances Bay</a>, <a href="https://100r.co/site/yuculta_and_dent_rapids.html">Yuculta and Dent Rapids</a>, <a href="https://100r.co/site/shoal_bay.html">Shoal Bay</a>, <a href="https://100r.co/site/port_neville.html">Port Neville</a>, <a href="https://100r.co/site/telegraph_cove.html">Telegraph Cove</a>, <a href="https://100r.co/site/port_mcneill.html">Port McNeill</a>, <a href="https://100r.co/site/fury_cove.html">Fury Cove</a>, <a href="https://100r.co/site/prince_rupert.html">Prince Rupert</a>, <a href="https://100r.co/site/bc_north_coast_anchorages.html">B.C. north coast anchorages</a>, <a href="https://100r.co/site/us_se_alaska.html">US Southeast Alaska</a> and <a href="https://100r.co/site/united_states.html">United States</a>.</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://100r.co/site/paradise.html">Paradise</a></b>, implemented paradise <a href='https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/parade/tree/main/item/src/paradise.modal' target='_blank'>in Modal</a>.</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/uxn-utils/tree/main/item/gui/notepad" target="_blank">Note Pad</a></b>, added <a href='https://merveilles.town/@neauoire/112528189068328657' target='_blank'>pen tool and line styles</a>.</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/oekaki" target="_blank">Oekaki</a></b>, rect tool uses brush settings.</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://100r.co/site/adelie.html">Adelie</a></b>, tga images are now dithered.</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://100r.co/site/left.html">Left</a></b>, fixed issue for non-qwerty keyboards.</li>
</ul>

<p>We spent this month moving northward through both southern and northern British Columbia. We've been moving almost every day, stopping every night to anchor, sleep and recuperate. Sailing near land is not as relaxing as sailing offshore, this reef-strewn coast requires careful navigation. We've had many long days of endless tacking from one side of the channel to the other, almost all the way to Port McNeill, then after that we started to get more weather from the south for some mostly pleasant, but cold and rainy, downwind sailing. We've been using our woodstove a lot, in evenings it helps warm the boat after a long sail.</p>

<p>On May 29th, 623 nautical miles miles after leaving Victoria, we arrived in Prince Rupert, our last major port in British Columbia before we head north to Southeast Alaska. Then, on June 2nd, we arrived in Ketchikan, Southeast Alaska. Most of our updates this month detail some of the places we've been(see the above list). To see our path, look at <a href="https://100r.co/site/western_canada.htm">Western Canada</a> and <a href="https://100r.co/site/us_se_alaska.html">us se alaska</a>. We update the map as we find internet.</p>

<p>We've seen sea otters, lots of humpback whales, two pods of orcas(one pod had a baby tagging along), eagles, and lots of mountains. In other non-travel related news, Devine is going to speak again at <a href="https://handmadecities.com/seattle/" target="_blank">Handmade Seattle</a> this upcoming November!</p>

<h3>Pino book & movie club</h3>

<p><b>Book Club:</b> This month we are reading The Martian by Andy Weir.</p>
<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/log.html#may2024' target='_blank'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for April 2024</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/log.html#apr2024</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>log.html#apr2024</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone!</p><p>This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects during the month of April.</p>

<img src="https://100r.co/media/content/videos/april_2024.jpg" loading="lazy">

<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>
<ul>
  <li><b>100r.co</b>, added <a href="https://100r.co/site/twilight.html">Twilight</a>, updated our notes on <a href="https://100r.co/site/chainplates.html#april2024">chainplates</a>, <a href="https://100r.co/site/wheel_to_tiller_conversion.html#apr2024">wheel to tiller conversion</a>, <a href="https://100r.co/site/dc_electrical_refit.html#apr2024">cabin lights</a> <a href="https://100r.co/site/standing_rigging_replacement.html#apr2024">standing rigging replacement</a>, <a href="https://100r.co/site/princess_louisa_inlet.html">Princess Louisa Inlet</a>(added maps), <a href="https://100r.co/site/goji_no_chaimu.html">Goji no Chaimu</a>(added maps), and <a href="https://100r.co/site/sailing_in_japan.html">Sailing to Japan</a>(fixed some dead links).</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/hakum.html" target="_blank">Hakum</a></b>, released a new comic sequence called <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/kaizah.html" target="_blank">Kaizah</a>.</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/wunderland_rabbits.html" target="_blank">Wunderland Rabbits</a></b>, released a new <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/wunderland_13_full.jpg" target="_blank">Rabbit travel photo</a></li>
  <li><b><a href="https://100r.co/site/orca.html" target="_blank">Orca</a></b>, added a note on the repository for the Javascript version titled <a href='https://github.com/hundredrabbits/Orca/issues/297' target='_blank'>Is Orca dead?</a></li>
</ul>

<p>Devine has been busy working on the <a href='https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/modal' target='_blank'>implementation</a> and <a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/modal'>documentation</a> of <a href='https://wryl.tech/' target='_blank'>wryl</a>'s fantastic programming language <i>Modal</i>. Rewriting systems are a <a href='https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Abstract_rewriting_machine' target='_blank'>computation paradigm</a> that is generally unknown and under-explored that might have some fascinating features that might be able help us to tackle some of our future projects.</p>

<p>In other news, Pino is ready to head northward! We finished all of our boats projects and left the dock on May 1st. See a <a href="https://100r.co/media/content/travel/se_ak_01.jpg" target="_blank">photo</a> of our first day of the year on the water, taken as we exited Enterprise Channel, just north of Trial Island south of Victoria. On our travels we will continue to push updates every month like usual, but the updates will only go live when we find internet, and this may or may not coincide with the start of every month. We will keep a log of our travels, populated with plenty of drawings!</p>

<h3>Pino book & movie club</h3>

<p><b>Book Club:</b> This month we are reading The Fountainhead by Ayn Rand.</p>
<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/log.html#apr2024' target='_blank'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for March 2024</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/log.html#mar2024</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>log.html#mar2024</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone!</p><p>This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects during the month of March.</p>

<img src="https://100r.co/media/content/videos/march_2024.jpg" loading="lazy">

<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>

<ul>
  <li><b>100r.co</b>, added <a href="https://100r.co/site/chainplates.html" target="_blank">chainplates</a>, <a href="https://100r.co/site/knots.html" target="_blank">knots</a>, <a href="https://100r.co/site/washing_dishes.html" target="_blank">washing dishes</a>, <a href="https://100r.co/site/receiving_mail.html" target="_blank">receiving mail</a>, updated our notes on <a href="https://100r.co/site/diy_carbonation_system.html" target="_blank">diy carbonation system</a>, and <a href="https://100r.co/site/refrigeration.html" target="_blank">refrigeration</a>.</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://100r.co/site/uxn.html" target="_blank">Uxn</a></b>, added <a href="https://lists.sr.ht/~rabbits/uxn/%3C6a8207b3-9261-4a1a-9850-6ed56a6540c5%40100r.co%3E" target="_blank">2 new commands</a> to Varvara's System/expansion port and rewrote uxnasm.</li>
  <li><b>Some toys</a></b>, made a two-player implementation of <a href="https://merveilles.town/@neauoire/112147254470345655" target="_blank">Pong</a>, and an <a href="https://merveilles.town/@neauoire/112028761735298073" target="_blank">orca that follows the cursor</a> like that old classic flash web toy.</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://100r.co/site/left.html" target="_blank">Left</a></b>, improved the <a href="https://merveilles.town/@neauoire/112067416270979772" target="_blank">object inspector</a>, it's much prettier now!</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://kokorobot.ca" target="_blank">Kokorobot</a></b> has a new splash page.</li>
</ul>

<h3>News</h3>

<p>Pino now has all-new chainplates! We removed the original ones earlier this month to inspect them and found some pit corrosion(as well as a small crack), replacing them was necessary. With the chainplates gone, we removed the entire starboard side cabinet to see what was behind it—it's always nice to see parts of our boat we've never seen. We also replaced 3 old halyards on Pino. Devine earned themself a couple of blisters <a href="https://100r.co/media/content/boat_projects/dyneema_halyard_splice.jpg" target="_blank">splicing dyneema</a> onto some of our existing halyards.</p>

<p>Sejo revisited the <a href="https://compudanzas.net/maintenance_practice.html" target="_blank">Uxn tutorial</a>, and appended corrections. The most important change is that the tutorial is now targeting the <a href="https://metasyn.srht.site/learn-uxn/" target="_blank">learn-uxn platform</a>(online) maintained by <a href="https://metasyn.pw/" target="_blank">metasyn</a>. Now, people can jump right in and experiment without having to set up a dev environment. Tsoding, someone who can code in front of the camera in a language they've never used or read the docs for, did a pretty funny session in Uxntal, you can watch it <a href='https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=d41KIL4cjQM' target="_blank">here</a>.</p>

<p>There has been too many exciting Uxn projects coming out these past few days, so we'll just put <a href='https://merveilles.town/tags/uxn' target="_blank">a link to the hashtag</a>. Someone also created a <a href='https://discord.gg/QKapkAxsg9' target="_blank">Discord channel</a>, it's a good place to learn about other concatenative languages and an alternative for people who have trouble with #uxn, in <b>irc.libera.chat</b>.</p>

<h3>Pino book & movie club</h3>

<p>This month we are reading <b>The Last Great Sea</b> by Terry Glavin, and we watched the movie Tenet.</p>
<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/log.html#mar2024' target='_blank'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for February 2024</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/log.html#feb2024</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>log.html#feb2024</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone!</p><p>This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects during the month of February.</p>

<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>
<ul>
  <li><b>100r.co</b>, added <a href="https://100r.co/site/gimballed_stove.html">gimballed stove</a>, <a href="https://100r.co/site/open_pantry.html">open pantry</a>, <a href="https://100r.co/site/little_ninj.html">Little Ninj</a> and <a href="https://100r.co/site/lpg_fume_detection_system.html">LPG fume detection system</a>. Updated <a href="https://100r.co/site/galley_refit.html">galley refit</a> and <a href="https://100r.co/site/western_canada.html">Western Canada</a>(includes tidal/current resources).</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://100r.co/site/uxn.html">Uxn</a></b>, with the help of the community, we defined a <a href='https://lists.sr.ht/~rabbits/uxn/%3C2ead8c73-a3f9-4ded-80b9-96a80d06d688%40100r.co%3E' target='_blank'>specification</a> on how labels and sublabels should be nested into each other. Assemblers were updated to reflect that change, including the <a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/etc/uxnrepl/' target='_blank'>Uxn REPL</a>.</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://100r.co/site/left.html">Left</a></b>, added <a href="https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/utf8.html" target="_blank">accented latin characters</a> support, so you can read and write French and Spanish text files.</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/potato.html" target="_blank">Potato</a></b>, released a final version, added a <a href="https://merveilles.town/@neauoire/111973239737050713" target="_blank">screensaver</a>(Mastodon).</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/hakum.html" target="_blank">Hakum</a></b>, finished <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/ruler_of_the_taiga.html" target="_blank">Ruler of the Taiga</a>.</li>
</ul>

<h3>News</h3>

<p>Late last month we started re-modeling part of our galley, the work is now complete! It's subtle, but the splash image for the log now includes the re-design. We will test our new galley when we go out cruising.</p>

<p>Pino will be adventuring a bit more north this summer, we're planning to explore the north coast of British Columbia, all the way to Prince Rupert, or possibly Ketchikan(AK), areas with little to no cell coverage. How far we go depends on what we find on the way. If the seas and winds are kind, and if we have time, we might go farther. We spend our days studying charts, gathering supplies, and fixing up the boat to make sure the passage is safe and pleasant. More updates on our plans soon!</p>

<p>Want to see something cool? Xsodect made <a href="https://layer8.space/@vacuumbeef/111908425456442451" target="_blank">Tetris</a>(Mastodon) in <a href="https://100r.co/site/orca.html">Orca</a>.</p>

<h3>Pino book & movie club</h3>

<p>This month we watched The Race to Alaska Movie.</p>
<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/log.html#feb2024' target='_blank'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for January 2024</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/log.html#jan2024</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>log.html#jan2024</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone!</p><p>This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects during the month of January.</p>

<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>
<ul>
  <li><b><a href="https://100r.co">100r.co</a></b>, added <a href="https://100r.co/site/galley_refit.html" target="_blank">galley refit</a>, updated <a href="https://100r.co/site/lifelines.html#dec2023">lifelines</a>, <a href="https://100r.co/site/making_seamed_box_cushions.html#trapezoid">seamed box cushions</a>, and <a href="https://100r.co/site/moisture_prevention_underliner.html">moisture prevention underliner</a>.</li>
  <li><b><a href="http://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/permacomputing.html" target="_blank">Permacomputing</a></b>, revamped the page.</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/uxn-games/tree/main/item/flap/flap.tal">Flappy Bird</a></b>, released an <a href="https://100r.co/site/uxn.html">Uxn</a> version of the Flappy Bird game.</li>
  <li><a href="https://100r.co/site/grimgrains.html" target="_blank">Grimgrains</a>, released a new basic recipe: <a href="https://grimgrains.com/site/whole_wheat_pancakes.html" target="_blank">Whole Wheat Pancakes</a>.</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://soundcloud.com/neauoire" target="_blank">Aliceffekt</a></b>, Devine wrote some new music. </li>
</ul>

<p>On January 10th the forge that we use to host our projects was taken down by DDoS attacks and was struggling to come back online(it's back now, read the <a href="https://sourcehut.org/blog/2024-01-19-outage-post-mortem/" target="_blank">post-mortem</a>), the event reminded us that we ought to host mirrors and release versions of these source files ourselves. We have begun to <a href="http://wiki.xxiivv.com/etc/" target="_blank">host copies</a> across our various websites. The builds are still accessible through <a href="https://hundredrabbits.itch.io/" target="_blank">itch.io</a>. These will be automatically updated as we work on them in their individual repositories, but mirrored there for reliability. We are thankful for Sourcehut's tireless work on resolving the issue and for taking the time to communicate important changes.</p>

<p>In keeping with the spirit of improving the resilience of the tools we use we've taken a moment to write a kind of pocket version of the console emulator and <a href="http://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/drifblim.html" target="_blank">self-hosted assembler</a> as to see how many lines are needed to start from the seed assembler and replicate it. A copy of the pocket emulator, the source for the assembler and its hexadecimal representation have been <a href="http://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/uxn.html" target="_blank">documented</a>.</p>

<p>On January 17th <a href="https://100r.co/site/victoria.html" target="_blank">Victoria</a> got its first <a href="https://100r.co/media/content/stream/2024_snow.jpg" target="_blank">snowfall</a>, with it came temperatures below freezing. We got to test our recent improvements, like a new <a href="https://100r.co/media/content/boat_projects/vent.jpg" target="_blank">louvered closet vent</a> to help ventilate the space(there are also two existing vents at the top, one on each side). The closet has been dry for the first time in 3 years. We've made an effort not to keep too many items on the floor so the area can breathe. We got ice inside of the windows for the first time ever though... not ideal.</p>

<p>See Uxn running on a <a href="https://loutre.info/@Hiro/111784989319495175" target="_blank">Zaurus Husky</a>(Mastodon).</p>

<h3>Pino book club</h3>

<p>This month we are reading <b>The Haunting of Hill House</b> by Shirley Jackson.</p>
<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/log.html#jan2024' target='_blank'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for December 2023</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/log.html#dec2023</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>log.html#dec2023</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone!</p><p>This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects during the month of December.</p>

<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>
<ul>
  <li><b>100r.co</b>, added <a href="https://100r.co/site/solar_cooking_experiment.html" target="_blank">solar cooking experiment</a>, <a href="https://100r.co/site/making_seamed_box_cushions.html" target="_blank">making seamed box cushions</a>, <a href="https://100r.co/site/making_saloon_cushions.html" target="_blank">making saloon cushions</a>, <a href="https://100r.co/site/moisture_prevention_underliner.html" target="_blank">moisture prevention underliner</a>, and <a href="https://100r.co/site/board_games.html" target="_blank">board games</a>. Updated <a href="https://100r.co/site/charging_electronics.html#dec2023" target="_blank">charging electronics</a>, and <a href="https://100r.co/site/upholstery.html" target="_blank">upholstery</a>.</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://100r.co/site/wiktopher.html" target="_blank">Wiktopher</a></b>, released the book on <a href="https://www.lulu.com/shop/rek-bell-and-devine-lu-linvega/wiktopher/paperback/product-m22wv96.html?page=1&pageSize=4" target="_blank">paperback</a>.</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/wunderland_rabbits.html" target="_blank">Wunderland Rabbits</a></b>, added a new <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/wunderland_12.jpg" target="_blank">photo</a>.</li>
  <li><b><a href="http://grimgrains.com" target="_blank">GrimGrains</a></b>, added <a href="http://grimgrains.com/site/millet_dumplings.html" target="_blank">millet dumplings</a>, and <a href="http://grimgrains.com/site/vegetable_curry.html" target="_blank">vegetable curry</a>.</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://rabbits.srht.site/decadv/" target="_blank">December Adventure</a></b>, Devine wrote a daily devlog for the month, documenting various projects like Porporo(an OS).</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/lispkit" target="_blank">Lispkit</a></b>, wrote a <a href="http://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/lisp.html" target="_blank">PureLisp</a> compiler and emulator for the <a href="http://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/secd.html" target="_blank">SECD stack-machine</a>.</li>
  <li><b><a href="http://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/grail.html" target="_blank">Grail</a></b>, made a little shorthand calligraphy and interpreter.</li>
</ul>

<h3>News</h3>

<p>Wiktopher was released on paperback! Our small collection of <a href="https://100r.co/media/content/inventory/wik_bdn.jpg" target="_blank">self-published books</a> is growing.</p>

<p>We finished the upholstery in the saloon, Pino feels like a new boat. We also published an article on this past summer's <a href="https://100r.co/site/solar_cooking_experiment.html" target="_blank">Solar Cooking Experiment</a>.</p>

<p>Last September Devine and a group of people went on a 3-day train ride from Seattle to St Louis for the last edition of <a href="https://thestrangeloop.com/" target="_blank">Strange Loop 2023</a>. This <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9qVT0URkkGE" target="_blank">video</a> documents that journey.</p>

<p>As mentionned in November's update, <a href="https://tinyletter.com/hundredrabbits" target="_blank">Tinyletter</a>, the service we use to send out our monthly newsletter, is <b>shutting down</b> in February 2024. We will now be using Sourcehut to send our monthly updates. With this new system our emails will be leaner than ever, using plain text(no html). We cannot transfer accounts to this new list ourselves, so <b>if you want to keep receiving updates by email please <a href="https://lists.sr.ht/~rabbits/newsletter" target="_blank">sign up again here</a></b>. Clicking on the subscribe button will open your email client, you can leave the body and subject of the email blank. We will keep sending newsletters with TinyLetter until the end of January 2024, so as to give people time to make the switch. If you sign up to this new list, unsuscribe from the old newsletter to avoid getting two emails with the same content for December and January. We hope you continue to follow our updates.</p>

<p>Note that since it's our first time sending updates with the new newsletter format, it may look a little wonky. We'll improve on it next month.</p>

<p>2023 was kind to us, we look forward to seeing what 2024 brings! We hope the coming year treats you all well.</p>

<h3>Pino book & movie club</h3>

<p>This month we are reading <b>The Tartar Steppe</b> by Dino Buzzati, and we went to see <b>君たちはどう生きるか(The Boy and the Heron)</b>.</p>
<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/log.html#dec2023' target='_blank'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for November 2023</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/log.html#nov2023</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>log.html#nov2023</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone!</p><p>This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects during the month of November.</p>

<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>
<ul>
  <li><b><a href="https://100r.co/site/wiktopher.html" target="_blank">Wiktopher</a></b>, drew some <a href="https://merveilles.town/@rek/111342263287492914" target="_blank">new art</a>(Mastodon), finalized a <a href="https://merveilles.town/@rek/111343213701036541" target="_blank">few translations</a>(Mastodon), and released it the project on <a href="https://hundredrabbits.itch.io/wiktopher-desert-tales" target="_blank">Itchio</a>!</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://100r.co/site/thousand_rooms.html" target="_blank">Thousand Rooms</a></b>, <a href="https://merveilles.town/@neauoire/111427947623485478" target="_blank">translated the book</a>(Mastodon) into Solresol.</li>
  <li><b>100r.co</b>, added a still map of our Pacific circumnavigation in <a href="https://100r.co/site/where.html" target="_blank">where</a>, added <a href="https://100r.co/site/repair.html" target="_blank">repair</a>, <a href="https://100r.co/site/effect_of_combining_dissimilar_metals.html" target="_blank">effect of combining dissimilar metals</a>, <a href="https://100r.co/site/bikes_on_a_boat.html" target="_blank">bikes on a boat</a>, <a href="https://100r.co/site/upholstery.html" target="_blank">upholstery</a> and updated <a href="https://100r.co/site/lifelines.html" target="_blank">lifelines</a>.</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://100r.co/site/busy_doing_nothing.html" target="_blank">Busy Doing Nothing</a></b>, added <a href="https://merveilles.town/@rek/111365215195099215" target="_blank">GPS coordinates</a>(Mastodon) for every listed day of travel.</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/hakum.html" target="_blank">Hakum</a></b>, designed handwritten font for the comic and <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/making_a_font.html" target="_blank">wrote a post</a> about the process.</li>
  <li><b><a href='https://beldamrecords.bandcamp.com/album/elmet-brae-the-land' target='_blank'>Elmet Brae</a></b>, released a collaborative album with members of the Merveilles community and friends. Made the album cover in collaboration with <a href="https://nchrs.xyz" target="_blank">Rostiger</a>, who also
made the <a href="https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/varvara_zine.html">Varvara Zine</a>.</li>
  <li><b><a href='https://rabbits.srht.site/solrela/' target='_blank'>Solrela</a></b>, released a Solresol translator website to replace the now defunct Sidosi translator.</li>
</ul>

<h3>News</h3>

<p><a href="https://100r.co/site/wiktopher.html" target="_blank">Wiktopher</a> is finally finished. We started this book in 2017 while in <a href="https://100r.co/site/french_polynesia.html" target="_blank">French Polynesia</a>, constrained by power limitations and hardware failures. Writing demanded less energy than drawing digitally, Rek could use the Chromebook to work (see <a href="https://100r.co/site/tools_ecosystem.html" target="_blank">tools ecosystem</a>). You can read the first two chapters of the finished story <b><a href="https://100r.co/media/content/projects/wiktopher_preview.pdf">here</a>[4.1 MiB]</b> as a PDF. If you liked what you've read, we hope you'll consider <a href="https://hundredrabbits.itch.io/wiktopher-desert-tales" target="_blank">reading the rest</a>!</p>

<p>We treated ourselves this month to new saloon cushions(see <a href="https://100r.co/site/upholstery.html" target="_blank">upholstery</a>). We sleep and live on these, it's so nice to have plump cushions again!</p>

<p><b>IMPORTANT</b>. <i>You may have heard but the service we use to send our newsletter(TinyLetter) is shutting down early next year (Feb 2024). We are in the process of setting up an alternative, we'll provide details on that in December's newsletter and on this website.</i></p>

<h3>Pino book & movie club</h3>

<p>We are reading Thomas Pynchon's <b>The Crying of Lot 49</b>, and enjoyed watching <b>Close Encounters of the Third Kind</b>.</p>
<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/log.html#nov2023' target='_blank'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for October 2023</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/log.html#oct2023</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>log.html#oct2023</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 09:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of October. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.</p>

<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>
<ul>
  <li><b><a href="https://100r.co/site/thousand_rooms.html">Thousand Rooms</a></b>, added a Brazilian Portuguese version.</li>
  <li><b><a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/wunderland_rabbits.html' target='_blank'>Wunderland Rabbits</a></b>, traveled to a <a href='https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/wunderland_11.jpg' target='_blank'>botanical garden</a>, and went to <a href='https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/wunderland_10.jpg' target='_blank'>pick apples</a>.</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/uxn5/" target="_blank">Uxn5</a></b>, <a href="https://alexw.nyc" target="_blank">Alex W.</a> is writing a <a href="https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/uxn5/" target="_blank">Vanilla JS</a> implementation, in which you can <a href="https://merveilles.town/@neauoire/111303032307412150" target="_blank">drag roms into the window</a>(Mastodon) to play them. <a href="http://plastic-idolatry.com/erik/" target="_blank">Eiríkr</a> wrote an guide on how to use  <a href="http://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/uxntal_signed" target="_blank">signed numbers</a>.</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/hakum.html" target="_blank">Hakum</a></b>, added <a href="https://kokorobot.ca/site/night_terror.html" target="_blank">3 pages</a>.</li>
  <li><b>100r.co</b>, added 3 travel maps in <a href="https://100r.co/site/western_canada.html" target="_blank">Western Canada</a>.</li>
</ul>

<h3>News</h3>

<p>This month <a href='https://merveilles.town/@ritualdust/111191488456801990' target='_blank'>we got tattooed</a>(Mastodon) by the very talented <a href='https://ritualdust.com/' target='_blank'>Lizbeth</a>. Check out her <a href='https://ritualdust.com/tattoo/' target='_blank'>tattoo art</a>.</p>

<p>Devine's <a href='https://thestrangeloop.com' target='_blank'>Strange Loop 2023</a> talk was released online, watch it <a href='https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=T3u7bGgVspM&feature=youtu.be' target='_blank'>here</a>(YouTube). We also released the talk as a text version, <a href="https://100r.co/site/computing_and_sustainability.html">Computing and sustainability</a>, for those who prefer to read. We talked with the members of <a href="https://frugarilla.fr/" target="_blank">Frugarilla</a> on their <a href='https://soundcloud.com/numeriques-essentiels/episode-9' target='_blank'>latest podcast</a>(French), in which we finally admit that our whole thing is a sneaky way of getting programmers interested in food preservation.</p>

<p>Every year we carve <a href="https://100r.co/site/halloween_pumpkins.html" target="_blank">halloween pumpkins</a>, this year we made a <a href="https://100r.co/media/content/inventory/pumpkin_uxn_01.jpg" target="_blank">Uxn pumpkin</a>!</p>

<p>See <a href="https://100r.co/site/oquonie.html" target="_blank">Oquonie</a> running on a <a href="https://merveilles.town/@consumtariat/111194557961333890" target="_blank">linux handheld</a>(Mastodon).</p>

<h3>Pino book club</h3>

<p>We are reading Selma Lagerlöf's <b>The Wonderful Adventures of Nils</b>.</p>
<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/log.html#oct2023' target='_blank'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for September 2023</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/log.html#sep2023</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>log.html#sep2023</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of September. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.</p>

<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>

<ul>
  <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/wiktopher.html' target='_blank'>Wiktopher</a></b>, adapted <a href='http://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/solresol.html' target='_blank'>Solresol</a>, edited other conlangs.</li>
  <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/niju.html' target='_blank'>Niju</a></b>, fixed a drawing bug.</li>
  <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/oquonie.html' target='_blank'>Oquonie</a></b>, working on the Playdate version.</li>
</ul>

<h3>News</h3>

<p>Pino returned to the Victoria docks a little early this year so Devine could go to <a href='https://thestrangeloop.com' target='_blank'>Strange Loop 2023</a>. We had a lovely sail that day, with clear skies, and 10 kts on the beam. Despite being a little food and sleep deprived, Devine's presentation went well, we will share the recording here once it is released.</p>

<p>Rek has been busy editing <a href='https://100r.co/site/wiktopher.html' target='_blank'>Wiktopher</a>, finessing the conlangs featured in the story. One of the featured languages is Ilken, a whistled language, designed for long-distance communication, and playable with instruments. A few years ago Devine designed a language for it, but we decided to instead use a modern variation of <a href='http://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/solresol.html' target='_blank'>Solresol</a>, a musical language by Jean-François Sudre. Rek <a href='http://wiki.xxiivv.com/media/refs/mimi.jpg' target='_blank'>drew a fanart of the mascot of Solresol</a>, and Devine a <a href='http://wiki.xxiivv.com/media/diary/826.jpg' target='_blank'>communication lantern</a>.</p>

<p>Currently, Devine is working at translating <a href='https://100r.co/site/thousand_rooms.html' target='_blank'>Thousand Rooms</a>(Famimi Remisolla) in Solresol as practice. We're also editing a Brazilian Portuguese version, to be released next month.</p>

<p>We've been toying with the idea of making an audiobook for the story, and asked <a href='https://pbat.ch/' target='_blank'>Paul B.</a> to use their voice synthesis tool <a href='https://pbat.ch/wiki/gesture/' target='_blank'>Gesture</a> to try and hear what <a href='https://merveilles.town/@patchlore/111042127852885392' target='_blank'>a poem in Ilken(Solresol)</a> sounds like. The result was so lovely that it made Rek cry of joy.</p>

<p>Rek's <a href='https://merveilles.town/@rek/110934243447981216' target='_blank'>sketch thread</a>(Mastodon) is still going. Devine will be producing a lot more art next month for Drawtober!</p>

<h3>Pino book club</h3>

<p>We are reading J.D. Salinger's <b>Catcher in the Rye</b>, and B. F. Skinner's <b>Walden Two</b>.</p>

<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/log.html#sep2023' target='_blank'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for August 2023</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/log.html#aug2023</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>log.html#aug2023</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of August. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.</p>

<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>

<ul>
  <li><b>100r.co</b>, added <a href='https://100r.co/site/heriot_bay.html' target='_blank'>Heriot Bay</a>, <a href='https://100r.co/site/ballet_bay.html' target='_blank'>Ballet Bay</a> <a href='https://100r.co/site/octopus_islands.html' target='_blank'>Octopus Islands</a>, and updated <a href='https://100r.co/site/hathayim_marine_park.html#jul2023'>Hathayim Marine Park</a>, <a href='https://100r.co/site/rain.html' target='_blank'>rain</a>, and <a href='https://100r.co/site/boom_tent.html#aug2023' target='_blank'>boom tent</a>.</li>
  <li><b><a href='https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/oekaki' target='_blank'>Oekaki</a></b>, released a new drawing program.</li>
  <li><b><a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/varvara.html' target='_blank'>Varvara</a></b>, began <a href='https://lists.sr.ht/~rabbits/uxn/%3CCAE2DaST7RrdsVgGr86PKH+sopcNQqF7D3uDygmAV_5QjSNGZRg%40mail.gmail.com%3E' target='_blank'>versioning</a>.</li>
</ul>

<h3>News</h3>

<p>Pino sailed a bit more northward this month and went all the way to the <a href='https://100r.co/site/octopus_islands.html' target='_blank'>Octopus Islands</a>. We visited this place during a very windy week, with winds blowing 30-35 kts the entire time. We got acquainted with a few northern rapids, like Hole in the Wall and Surge Narrows. It is a bit of a mindfuck to think that in these waters the tide ebbs north and floods south.</p>

<p>This summer has been especially arid, and because of it the province has seen a lot forest fires (see pictures of <a href='https://100r.co/site/sturt_bay.html#aug2023' target='_blank'>our smokey transit</a>). Trails that we know and love on Cortes Island, that are usually wet and muddy, were bone dry this year. We had a few days of hard rain, during that time we collect <a href='https://100r.co/site/rain.html' target='_blank'>rain</a> water and go for walks to  look for <a href='https://100r.co/site/hathayim_marine_park.html#jul2023' target='_blank'>slugs and snails</a>.</p>

<p>Both of us have been drawing a lot this month, see this <a href='https://merveilles.town/@neauoire/110982150120018215' target='_blank'>Neoneve portrait</a>(Mastodon) by Devine (drawn with <a href='https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/oekaki' target='_blank'>Oekaki</a>), and this <a href='https://merveilles.town/@rek/110934243447981216' target='_blank'>sketch thread</a>(Mastodon) by Rek..</p>

<h3>Pino book club</h3>

<p>We have read Adam Wisniewski-Snerg's <b>Robot</b>, George Orwell's <b>Homage to Catalonia</b>, and Michael A. Hiltzik's <b>Dealers of Ligthning</b>.</p>

<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/log.html#aug2023' target='_blank'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>


<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for July 2023</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/log.html#jul2023</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>log.html#jul2023</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of July. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.</p>

<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>

<ul>
  <li><b>Slide Rule</b>, released a little <a href='https://merveilles.town/@neauoire/110664076683550080' target='_blank'>slide rule toy</a>(Mastodon).</li>
  <li><b>100r.co</b>, added <a href='https://100r.co/site/roscoe_bay.html' target='_blank'>roscoe bay</a>, updated <a href='https://100r.co/site/lpg_refit.html#jul2023'>LPG refit</a>.</li>
  <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/wiktopher.html' target='_blank'>wiktopher</a></b>, we finished doing the entire first pass of corrections.</li>
  <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/left.html' target='_blank'>Left</a></b>, made a couple of interface improvements, it's not only prettier now, but faster.</li>
  <li><b><a href='https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/drifblim' target='_blank'>Drifblim</a></b>, added support for lambdas in Uxntal, now also supported in <a href='https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/uxn/tree/main/item/src/uxnasm.c' target='_blank'>uxnasm</a>.</li>
</ul>

<h3>News</h3>

<p>We spent many quiet days in <a href='https://100r.co/site/roscoe_bay.html' target='_blank'>Roscoe Bay</a>, and then wandered over to <a href='https://100r.co/site/melanie_cove.html#jul2023' target='_blank'>melanie cove</a> for a few days before moving to our favorite anchorage in Desolation Sound, <a href='https://100r.co/site/hathayim_marine_park.html#jul2023' target='_blank'>Hathayim Marine Park</a>. This inlet is quiet, and not overly busy, it is ideal for focusing on projects. We walk the 3 km trail to Squirrel Cove everyday.</p>

<p>We have been hard at work reviewing <a href='https://100r.co/site/wiktopher.html' target='_blank'>Wiktopher</a>, and we're happy to announce that we've finished the first pass of corrections! We'll be doing many more passes, but this was a very big step. Rek has been <a href='https://merveilles.town/@rek/110788283194637214' target='_blank'>drawing</a>(Mastodon) a lot, and Devine has been working on their presentation for <a href='https://thestrangeloop.com/2023/sessions.html' target='_blank'>Strange Loop 2023</a>.</p>

<p>Check out this amazing <a href='https://github.com/weeble/uxn-cheatsheet' target='_blank'>Uxn cheat sheet</a> by Nettie!</p>

<h3>Pino book & movie club</h3>

<p>We are reading Lewis Carrol's <b>Bruno and Sylvie</b>. We re-watched Vampire Hunter D for the hundredth time.</p>

<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/log.html#jul2023' target='_blank'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for June 2023</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/log.html#jun2023</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>log.html#jun2023</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of June. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.</p>

<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>
<ul>
  <li><b>100r.co</b>, added <a href='https://100r.co/site/propeller_maintenance.html' target='_blank'>propeller maintenance</a>, <a href='https://100r.co/site/maple_bay.html' target='_blank'>Maple Bay</a>, <a href='https://100r.co/site/telegraph_cove.html' target='_blank'>Telegraph Cove</a>, <a href='https://100r.co/site/smuggler_cove.html' target='_blank'>Smuggler Cove</a> and <a href='https://100r.co/site/princess_louisa_inlet.html' target='_blank'>Princess Louisa Inlet</a>.</li>
  <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/wiktopher.html' target='_blank'>Wiktopher</a></b>, added back the revised/corrected version of <a href='http://wiktopher.ca/site/chapter_10.html' target='_blank'>Chapter 10</a>, back online, and Chapter 11 has been corrected but is not yet live.</li>
  <li><b><a href='https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/uxnfor' target='_blank'>UxnFor</a></b>, created an uxntal <a href='https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/uxnfor'>code formatter</a>.</li>
  <li><b><a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/bicycle.html' target='_blank'>Bicycle</a></b>, added lots of <a href='https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/bicycle'>little improvements</a>.</li>
  <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/adelie.html' target='_blank'>Adelie</a></b>, added <a href='https://100r.co/site/adelie.html#speaker'>speaker's notes</a> and a pen mode.</li>
</ul>

<h3>News</h3>

<p>Pino spent the first few days of the month on land, having its bottom re-painted, and its various bits serviced and checked. We took our propeller apart for the first time.</p>

<p>We've added a few write-ups of our travels so far (see above entry with links under 100r.co), but the most significant one is our 46nmi sail up to <a href='https://100r.co/site/princess_louisa_inlet.html' target='_blank'>Princess Louisa Inlet</a>, a long fjord on British Columbia's Sunshine Coast, with an incredible gem at the end. It is an amazing, and unique place. We're glad we finally got to go. As we write this, we are in Roscoe Bay on West Redonda Island, tethering off a phone hoisted up the mast (it works quite well).</p>

<p>This summer we are <a href='https://100r.co/site/power.html' target='_blank'>power</a> stable. We had issues last year because of parisitic draws due to old wiring (see <a href='https://100r.co/site/dc_electrical_refit.html' target='_blank'>DC electrical refit</a>), but now everything is working as it should. We're charging our computers without an inverter, and that too is working out quite well so far (see <a href='https://100r.co/site/charging_electronics.html' target='_blank'>charging electronics</a>).</p>

<p>Together, Hikari and Lynn made <a href='https://github.com/lynn/chibicc' target='_blank'>chibicc-uxn</a>, a c compiler for Uxn, and with it also released a <a href='https://github.com/hikari-no-yume/oneko-uxn' target='_blank'>port</a> of the classic software <a href='https://social.noyu.me/@hikari/statuses/01H46X10WKDGC55ZZ3S4R5KA6X' target='_blank'>Neko</a>(xneko, oneko sakura).</p>

<h3>Pino book & movie club</h3>

<p>We are reading Arkady and Boris Strugatsky's <b>Roadside Picnic</b>. We've been re-watching Kaamelott(the series, book 1 though 6) for the hundredth time.</p>


<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/log.html#jun2023' target='_blank'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for May 2023</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/log.html#may2023</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>log.html#may2023</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 09:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of May. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.</p>

<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>
<ul>
  <li><b>100r.co</b>, updated <a href='https://100r.co/site/jib_cars.html#may2023' target='_blank'>jib cars</a>, and added new recommendations on the <a href="https://100r.co/site/offshore_checklist.html">offshore checklist</a>(new entries labelled with dates).</li>
  <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/donsol.html' target='_blank'>Donsol</a></b>, <a href='https://asie.pl/' target='_blank'>Asie</a> made some <a href='https://merveilles.town/@neauoire/110305853534721465' target='_blank'>3DS and NDS roms</a>(Mastodon).</li>
  <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/wiktopher.html' target='_blank'>Wiktopher</a></b>, added the revised and corrected version of <a href='http://wiktopher.ca/site/chapter_08.html' target='_blank'>Chapter 8</a>, and <a href='http://wiktopher.ca/site/chapter_09.html' target='_blank'>Chapter 9</a>, back online.</li>
  <li><b><a href='https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/uxnbal' target='_blank'>Uxnbal</a></b>, wrote a type-checker, it's still very experimental, but it can infer most imbalancing stack-effects.</li>
  <li><b><a href='https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/bicycle' target='_blank'>Bicycle</a></b>, created a little interactive evaluator designed to be a teaching aid.</li>
</ul>

<h3>News</h3>

<p>Pino is off the dock, and spending time at anchor. The weather has been excellent, and with days of full comes sun solar cooking! We baked some <a href='https://100r.co/media/content/cooking/solar_baguette.jpg' target='_blank'>bread</a>, and roasted some <a href='https://100r.co/media/content/cooking/coffee_solar_01.jpg' target='_blank'>green coffee beans</a> in the sun. We are enjoying some quiet days before we haul the boat out of the water at the start of June.</p>

<p>Devine's talk proposal to <a href='https://thestrangeloop.com/2023/sessions.html' target='_blank'>Strange Loop 2023</a> has been accepted, so parts of the summer will be collecting our notes and writing slides for the presentation in September.</p>

<p>The recording for the show Devine(Alicef) did with <a href='https://www.anjusingh.com/about/' target='_blank'>Anju Singh</a> and <a href='https://www.instagram.com/apex_twink_/' target='_blank'>Reylinn</a>(visuals) last march for Biosonic on Galiano Island is online, watch it <a href='https://youtu.be/ZH9WlqCD61s' target='_blank'>here</a>.</p>

<p>We had a small impromptu logo jam event on Merveilles this month. Members of the community re-interpreted the logo, with illustrations, photo collages, and even food. See <a href='https://garden.bouncepaw.com/hypha/merveilles_logo' target='_blank'>all of the entries</a> so far. Nf just completed <a href='https://github.com/nf/fourtette' target='_blank'>Fourtette</a>, a block game. Devine provided guidance, Rek made the title screen art, and <a href='http://plastic-idolatry.com/erik/' target='_blank'>d6</a> provided music.</p>

<h3>Pino book & movie club</h3>

<p>We went to the theater for the first time in a long time, to see <b>Suzume(2023)</b>. We have also finished reading Saint-Exupery's <b>Courrier Sud</b>.</p>

<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/log.html#may2023' target='_blank'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for April 2023</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/log.html#apr2023</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>log.html#apr2023</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 09:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of April. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.</p>

<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>
<ul>
    <li><b>100r.co</b>, added <a href='https://100r.co/site/charging_electronics' target='_blank'>charging electronics</a>, <a href='https://100r.co/site/solar_cooking.html' target='_blank'>solar cooking</a> and <a href='https://100r.co/site/solar_evacuated_tube_cooking.html' target='_blank'>solar evacuated tube cooking</a>, and updated <a href='https://100r.co/site/insulation.html#apr2023' target='_blank'>insulation</a>, <a href='https://100r.co/site/thruhulls.html#apr2023' target='_blank'>thruhulls</a>.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/oquonie.html' target='_blank'>Oquonie</a></b>, released the game for Uxn. We have a <a href='https://merveilles.town/@voxel/110189746091696167' target='_blank'>Windows95+ compatible version</a>[Mastodon video].</li>
  <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/left.html' target='_blank'>Left</a></b>, various UX improvements, including negative length selection.</li>
  <li><b>Note Pad</b>, ported the <a href='https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Fp6io-G6dQQ' target='_blank'>classic macintosh Note Pad</a> application to Varvara, download it <a href='https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/uxn-utils/tree/main/item/gui/notepad/notepad.tal' target='_blank'>here</a>.</li>
  <li><b><a href="https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/turye.html" target="_blank">Turye</a></b>, total <a href='https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aRa7fI53w_0' target='_blank'>redesign</a>.</li>
  <li><b><a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/beetbug.html' target='_blank'>Beetbug</a></b>, added support for <a href='https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vd3bcRCjNVg' target='_blank'>comments</a> in symbol files.</li>
</ul>

<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/oquonie.html' target='_blank'>Oquonie</a> is out and it is playable! A big thank you to those who helped us test the game on a variety of devices and systems all the way to Windows95. This version of Oquonie differs a little from the original, in that some of the puzzles and secrets have changed. We hope that those who played the original will too enjoy this one. We have a special build of the game on <a href='https://hundredrabbits.itch.io/oquonie' target='_blank'>itchio</a> with the emulator and rom combined, if you have a false-negative virus warning on Windows 10, you will need to use the standard uxn32 emulator and rom.</p>

<p>We have watched as people implemented <a href='https://github.com/hundredrabbits/awesome-uxn' target='_blank'>their own emulators</a> and were able to play Oquonie on a Varvara of their own making. The current <a href='http://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/varvara.html' target='_blank'>implementation documentation</a> might need to be improved, if you have feedback for things that could be clearer, please let us know!</p>

<p>We published our experiments with <a href='https://100r.co/site/solar_cooking.html' target='_blank'>solar cooking</a> this month, and wrote a more detailed post on <a href='https://100r.co/site/solar_evacuated_tube_cooking.html' target='_blank'>solar evacuated tube cooking</a>. The real test will happen this summer. We plan to keep a log of everything we cook, how long it takes, and the conditions(sun, overcast, temp etc).</p>

<p>We're still closing a few projects aboard Pino, to get it ready for some summer sailing. Our plans for now are loose, we're hauling the boat out of the water in early June, with plans to sail back towards Desolation Sound afterward, with a possible stop by Jervis Inlet.</p>

<h3>Pino book & movie club</h3>

<p>We're watching <b> La Belle Verte</b> by Coline Serreau.</p>

<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/log.html#apr2023' target='_blank'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for March 2023</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/log.html#mar2023</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>log.html#mar2023</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 09:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects during the month of March.</p>

<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>
<ul>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/donsol.html' target='_blank'>Donsol</a></b>, added 100r logo to splash screen on the rom.</li>
    <li><b>100r.co</b>, added a new page: <a href='https://100r.co/site/diy_carbonation_system.html' target='_blank'>diy carbonation system</a>. Updated <a href='https://100r.co/site/saving_fuel.html' target='_blank'>Saving fuel</a>, <a href='https://100r.co/site/engine_rebuild.html' target='_blank'>Engine rebuild</a> and <a href='https://100r.co/site/sprouting.html' target='_blank'>sprouting</a>.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://grimgrains.com' target='_blank'>Grimgrains</a></b>, added two new recipes: <a href='http://grimgrains.com/site/beet_sauce_pasta.html'>Beet Sauce Pasta</a>, and <a href='http://grimgrains.com/site/mac_and_faux_cheese.html'>Mac and Faux Cheese</a>.</li>
  <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/left.html' target='_blank'>Left</a></b>, added all sorts of fun new things like <a href='https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VqHjfjddQ4U' target='_blank'>routine definition highlight</a> and <a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/gly_format.html' target='_blank'>graphics support</a>.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/hakum.html' target='_blank'>Hakum</a></b>, new comics named <a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/whodidwhat.html' target='_blank'>Who Did What</a> and <a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/disengaging.html' target='_blank'>Disengaging</a>.</li>
  <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/orca.html' target='_blank'>Orca</a></b>, added <a href='https://llllllll.co/t/orca-livecoding-tool/17689/1838' target='_blank'>$bpm command</a> to the uxn version.</li>
  <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/uxn.html' target='_blank'>Uxn</a></b>, revamped <a href='http://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/uxntal.html' target='_blank'>Uxntal documentation</a> based on the feedback from the community (thanks everyone).</li>
  <li><b>Interaction Nets</b>, spent time in the <a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/interaction_nets.html' target='_blank'>deep-end of the pool</a>.</li>
</ul>

<h3>News</h3>

<p>We spent the first half of March on Galiano Island in the Salish Sea for <a href='https://activepassive.ca/index.html' target='_blank'>BioSonic</a>(by ActivePassive), an event series exploring the intersections of music, art and biodiversity. On March 10th we gave a talk titled <b>What Are Computers For?</b>, see <a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/biosonic.html' target='_blank'>the art</a> from the talk. The next day, Devine and <a href='https://www.anjusingh.com/about/' target='_blank'>Anju Singh</a> performed together using <a href='https://100r.co/site/orca.html' target='_blank'>Orca</a>, with Reylinn on visuals. A video of the perfomance and of the talk will be released soon, in the meantime, see photos of the <a href='https://100r.co/media/content/events/talkbiosonic1.jpg' target='_blank'>talk</a> and of the <a href='https://100r.co/media/content/events/showbiosonic2.jpg' target='_blank'>show</a>, taken by photographer <a href='https://www.daynaszyndrowski.com/' target='_blank'>Dayna Szyndrowski</a>.</p>

<p>We are still working on re-releasing <a href='https://100r.co/site/oquonie.html' target='_blank'>Oquonie</a>. We spent the month of March playing the game, finding bugs, and fixing them. Oquonie will be playable next month.</p>

<p>This month we've been experimenting with solar cooking, to try to save on cooking fuel this summer. We are currently making tests, gathering data, and hope to share this with you all end of April. In the meantime, enjoy this <a href='https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLrFxn8U2oUqjVHkMxpondbAI6eywqXXlP' target='_blank'>amazing music</a> by Xsodect, made using <a href='https://100r.co/site/orca.html' target='_blank'>Orca</a>.</p>

<h3>Pino book club</h3>

<p>We're reading <b> Structure and Interpretation of Computer Programs (SICP)</b> by Harold Abelson, Gerald Jay and Julie Sussman.</p>

<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/log.html#mar2023'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>


<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for February 2023</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/log.html#feb2023</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>log.html#feb2023</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 09:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of February. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.</p>

<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>
<ul>    
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/wiktopher.html' target='_blank'>Wiktopher</a></b>, added back corrected chapters 1-7 to <a href='https://wiktopher.ca/' target='_blank'>online</a>.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/left.html' target='_blank'>Left</a></b>, made a ton of improvements including a new directory navigation, better navbar labels and performance.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/orca.html' target='_blank'>Orca</a></b>, fixed an issue where copy/paste/drag would move characters off-screen.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/catclock' target='_blank'>Catclock</a></b>, ported to new opcodes and improved monochromatic mode.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/beetbug' target='_blank'>Beetbug</a></b>, added an interactive mode that interprets uxntal on the fly.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/hakum.html' target='_blank'>Hakum</a></b>, added a comic sequence named <a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/tracking.html' target='_blank'>Tracking</a>.</li>
    <li><b>100r.co</b>, added updates to <a href='http://100r.co/site/dc_electrical_refit.html#batteryconnections'>battery connections</a>.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/grimgrains.html' target='_blank'>Grimgrains</a></b>, added some notes on <a href='http://grimgrains.com/site/lactofermentation.html#temp' target='_blank'>Temperature for lacto-fermentation</a>.</li>
</ul>

<h3>News</h3>

<p>On February 14th, we celebrated our 7th year living aboard our beloved Pino. It's also around this time 10 years ago that we were still living in Odaiba(Japan), and beginning our work on what would be our first game collaboration: <a href='https://100r.co/site/oquonie.html' target='_blank'>oquonie</a>.</p>

<p>The <a href='https://100r.co/site/uxn.html' target='_blank'>uxn</a> port of Oquonie has advanced in incredible leaps this month. Rek has finished re-doing all of the assets. Devine is now working on the music, and finalizing some of the levels. We are testing the game as we go, and hope to release it sometime next month. Oquonie will be playable on a number of platforms, including the <a href='https://merveilles.town/@neauoire/109887931570318719' target='_blank'>Nintendo DS</a>(Mastodon), as well as the <a href='http://100r.co/media/content/stream/2023_oquonie.jpg' target='_blank'>Playdate</a>. See a small <a href='https://merveilles.town/@neauoire/109904081987266827' target='_blank'>preview</a>(Mastodon).</p>

<p>Early next month we are traveling to Galiano Island in the Salish Sea for <a href='https://activepassive.ca/index.html' target='_blank'>BioSonic</a>(by ActivePassive). We'll be part of an event series exploring the intersections of music, art and biodiversity. We'll give a talk on March 10th, and Devine will perform with <a href='https://100r.co/site/orca.html' target='_blank'>Orca</a> on the 11th at the Galiano South Hall.</p>

<p>Watch <a href='https://youtu.be/p5mBG1hlDQU' target='_blank'>Devine's set</a> for <a href='https://lovebyte.party/' target='_blank'>Lovebyte 2023</a>.</p>

<h3>Pino book club</h3>

<p>We're reading <b>Courrier Sud</b> by Antoine de Saint-Exupéry.</p>

<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/log.html#feb2023'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for January 2023</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/log.html#jan2023</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>log.html#jan2023</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 09:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of January. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.</p>

<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>

<ul>    
    <li><b>100r.co</b>, added <a href='https://100r.co/site/electrical_refit.html' target='_blank'>electrical refit</a>(portal for AC & DC electrical refit), and updated <a href='https://100r.co/site/lpg_refit.html' target='_blank'>LPG refit</a>.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/wiktopher.html' target='_blank'>Wiktopher</a></b>, corrected chapter 8, and nearly done with lexicon.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/weathering_software_winter.html' target='_blank'>Weathering software winter</a></b>, <a href='https://guide.handmade-seattle.com/c/2022/weathering-software-winter/' target='_blank'>video</a>(Vimeo) now has closed-captionning (same goes for <a href='https://youtu.be/9TJuOwy4aGA' target='_blank'>YouTube version</a>). Rek spent time cleaning up the auto-generated transcript.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/uxn.html' target='_blank'>Uxn</a></b>, Andrew released <a href='https://github.com/randrew/uxn32/releases/tag/2.0' target='_blank'>Uxn32 2.0</a>.</li>
    <li><b><a href='http://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/potato.html' target='_blank'>Potato</a></b>, added updates, potato can now assemble roms from tal files.</li>
</ul>

<h3>News</h3>

<p>This month, we started porting <a href='https://100r.co/site/oquonie.html' target='_blank'>Oquonie</a> to Uxn. This is a long time coming, but we weren't sure if it was possible to do, and we still had a lot to learn before even thinking of taking it on. Now, we think we are ready. We are <a href='https://merveilles.town/@neauoire/109753175335217737' target='_blank'>re-drawing the sprites</a>(Mastodon), and they look amazing. This is an important test for us, and for Uxn.</p>

<p>Here is a very adorable <a href='https://merveilles.town/@neauoire/109689586631044117' target='_blank'>little Uxn sprite</a> for Potato that comes up when a rom path was mistyped, see it also on the <a href='https://100r.co/site/uxn.html' target='_blank'>Uxn</a> page.</p>

<h3>Pino book club</h3>

<p>We're reading <b>The Journey Home: Some Words in Defense of the American West</b> by Edward Abbey.</p>

<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/log.html#jan2023'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for December</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/log.html#dec2022</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>log.html#dec2022</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 09:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of December. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.</p>

<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>

<ul>	
	<li><b>100r.co</b>, added a new page: <a href='https://100r.co/site/electrical_refit.html' target='_blank'>electrical refit</a>, <a href='https://100r.co/site/fuel_sensor.html' target='_blank'>fuel sensor</a>, <a href='https://100r.co/site/marine_wire_termination.html' target='_blank'>marine wire termination</a>, also added updates to XPS and EPS in <a href='https://100r.co/site/winter_insulation.html' target='_blank'>winter insulation</a>.</li>
	<li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/orca.html' target='_blank'>Orca</a></b>, released a new build that improves the look and feel, added <a href='https://merveilles.town/@neauoire/109498859357833815' target='_blank'>app icon</a>(Mastodon) to the about modal.</li>
	<li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/busy_doing_nothing.html' target='_blank'>Busy Doing Nothing</a></b>, released a new version, in which we fixed extra typing errors (thanks Igor), and added explanations for certain sailing terms like reefing, etc.</li>
<li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/wiktopher.html' target='_blank'>Wiktopher</a></b>, corrected chapter 6 and 7.</li>
	<li><a href='http://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/beetbug.html' target='_blank'>Beetbug</a>, added break-point and <a href='http://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/symbols.html'>symbols</a> supports.</li>
	<li>Took a detour into computer science to learn about <a href='https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wIx1aCiRZl8' target='_blank'>arity testing and stack effect</a> checking, learn more about it <a href='https://docs.factorcode.org/content/article-inference.html' target='_blank'>here</a>.</li>
	<li>TinyCode2022, spent some time doing <a href='https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=V1eQV_DKRl0' target='_blank'>demoscene experiments</a>.</li>
</ul>

<h3>News</h3>

<p>The rabbits are re-wiring Pino. So far this month, we spent entire afternoons removing, and passing new wires into the boat's walls and ceiling. This project has taken up most of our time this month. For updates on the project, see <a href='https://100r.co/site/electrical_refit.html' target='_blank'>electrical refit</a>. We also released an edited transcript of Devine's talk <a href='https://100r.co/site/weathering_software_winter.html' target='_blank'>weathering software winter</a>, for those who prefer to read.</p>

<p>We forgot to mention it in the last update, but Compudanzas just released a new version of their <a href='https://compudanzas.itch.io/introduction-to-uxn-programming/devlog/451234/version-104-launcher-and-raw-runes' target='_blank'>introduction to uxn programming book</a>! The <a href='https://compudanzas.net/uxn_tutorial.html' target='_blank'>online tutorial</a> also had some updates.

<p>Happy new year everyone! See more photos of <a href='https://100r.co/media/content/stream/2022_gvha02.jpg' target='_blank'>Pino</a>(on the far left) and <a href='https://100r.co/media/content/stream/2022_gvha01.jpg' target='_blank'>friends</a> decorated for the occasion. </p>

<h3>Pino book club</h3>

<p>We're reading <b>Le Péril Bleu</b> by Maurice Renard.</p>

<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/log.html#dec2022'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for November</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/2022.html#nov2022</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>2022.html#nov2022</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of November. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.</p>

<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>

<ul>
	<li><b><a href='https://grimgrains.com' target='_blank'>GrimGrains</a></b>, added a <a href='http://grimgrains.com/site/quick_grilled_cheese.html' target='_blank'>quick grilled cheese</a> recipe.</li>
	<li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/noodle.html' target='_blank'>Noodle</a></b>, updated the guide, and added <a href='https://merveilles.town/@neauoire/109280995419859430' target='_blank'>app icon</a>(Mastodon) to the about modal.</li>
	<li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/nasu.html' target='_blank'>Nasu</a></b>, added <a href='https://merveilles.town/@neauoire/109282043310182229' target='_blank'>app icon</a>(Mastodon) to the about modal.</li>
	<li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/store.html' target='_blank'>Store</a></b>, added sheets of <a href='https://100r.co/site/store.html#stickers2'>Ecosystem Rabbit Stickers(gen2)</a> to the store.</li>
	<li><b><a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/uxntal.html' target='_blank'>Uxntal</a></b>, created a list of Uxntal examples with equivalent C sources, you can find them <a href='https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/uxntal-examples' target='_blank'>here</a>.</li>
	<li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/wiktopher.html' target='_blank'>Wiktopher</a></b>, made a progress bar (50% in the correction process) on the project page. We have finished processing chapter 5, and are currently applying corrections to chapter 6 & 7.</li>
	<li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/donsol.html' target='_blank'>Donsol</a></b>, updated GBA rom with a few fixes.</li>
	<li><b>Soroban</b>, made a little <a href='https://merveilles.town/web/@neauoire/109417640512376459' target='_blank'>desktop graphical abacus</a>(Mastodon).</li>
	<li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/uxn.html' target='_blank'>Uxn</a></b>, ported to <a href='https://git.sr.ht/~vdupras/duskos' target='_blank'>DuskOS</a>(SourceHut).</li>
	<li><b><a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/dexe.html' target='_blank'>Dexe</a></b>, redesigned and <a href='https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/dexe' target='_blank'>much faster</a>(SourceHut).</li>
</ul>

<p>We put some <a href='https://100r.co/media/content/stream/2022_11xmas.jpg' target='_blank'>red lights</a> on Pino, to help combat winter gloom. We also started growing another lion's mane mushroom on board(we grew the same variety last fall), it already has a little <a href='https://100r.co/media/content/stream/2022_11lionmanes2.jpg' target='_blank'>tuft</a>!</p>

<p>Devine's talk <b>Weathering Software Winter</b> for Handmade Seattle was recorded, watch it <a href='https://vimeo.com/771406693#t=85m30s' target='_blank'>here</a>(Vimeo). The video is for the entire first day of the conference, so for your convenience Devine's talk starts at 1h25min.</p>

<p>A little while ago <a href='https://nchrs.xyz/' target='_blank'>Rostiger</a> drew an amazing <a href='https://nchrs.xyz/uxn_notes.html' target='_blanl'>series of illustrations</a> explaining Uxn, and how it works. <a href='https://mineralexistence.com/about.html' target='_blank'>Ben</a> made a zine out of it and <a href='https://100r.co/media/content/stream/uxnzine.jpg' target='_blank'>gave us a copy</a>. Make your own Uxn zine using <a href='https://mineralexistence.com/files/uxn-zine.pdf' target='_blank'>this PDF</a>[1.38 MB].

<h3>Pino book club</h3>

<p>We're reading <b>Gulliver's Travels</b> by Jonathan Swift, and <b>How to Blow Up a Pipeline</b> by Andreas Malm.</p>

<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/2022.html#nov2022'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for October</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/2022.html#oct2022</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>2022.html#oct2022</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of October. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.</p>

<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>
<ul>
    <li><b><a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/basic.html' target='_blank'>TinyBASIC</a></b>, implemented <a href='
https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/tiny-basic' target='_blank'>TinyBASIC</a> in Uxntal.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/left.html' target='_blank'>Left</a></b>, added a variant of the <a href='https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/left/tree/main/item/etc/cream.uf2' target='_blank'>Smalltalk-76 font</a>.</li>
    <li><b><a href='http://kokorobot.ca/site/hakum.html' target='_blank'>Hakum</a></b>, released a short comic sequence called <a href='http://kokorobot.ca/site/chase.html' target='_blank'>Chase</a>.</li>
    <li><b><a href='http://kokorobot.ca/site/wunderrabbits.html' target='_blank'>Wunderland Rabbits</a></b>, added a new <a href='http://kokorobot.ca/media/content/wunderland_9.jpg' target='_blank'>rabbit pic</a>.</li>
    <li><b>100r.co</b>, updated <a href='https://100r.co/site/galley_plumbing.html' target='_blank'>galley plumbing</a>(serviced our water pump) and <a href='https://100r.co/site/curtains.html' target='_blank'>curtains</a>(modified the design). Added <a href='https://100r.co/site/lazy_jacks.html' target='_blank'>lazy lazy jacks</a>.</li>
</ul>

<h3>News</h3>

<p>Pino is in Victoria again, and we're diving back into our favorite fall activities like pumpkin carving (see <a href='https://100r.co/site/halloween_pumpkins.html' target='_blank'>halloween pumpkins</a>), and fruit picking. The boat is now filled with <a href='http://grimgrains.com/site/chunky_apple_jam.html' target='_blank'>apple jam</a>. October was a drawing month for the both of us. Devine participated in drawtober and completed <a href='https://forum.merveilles.town/thread/58/drawtober-92/#bottom' target='_blank'>28 drawings</a> using <a href='https://100r.co/site/noodle.html' target='_blank'>Noodle</a>. Rek finished a <a href='http://kokorobot.ca/site/chase.html' target='_blank'>sequence</a> for the ongoing comic project <a href='http://kokorobot.ca/site/hakum.html' target='_blank'>Hakum</a>.</p>

<p>For those in the Pacific Northwest, Devine will be giving a talk called <b>Weathering Software Winter</b> at <a href='https://handmade-seattle.com/' target='_blank'>Handmade Seattle</a> on November 17th.</p>

<p>As you know, we share a community online with a fantastic group of people. Some months ago Lizbeth designed a burgee for Merveilles and this month we decided to make one for Pino. See the <a href='https://100r.co/site/burgee.html' target='_blank'>Merveilles burgee</a>.</p>

<h3>Pino book club</h3>

<p>We're reading <b>Life, the Universe and Everything</b> by Douglas Adams, and <b>What The Doormouse Said</b> by John Markoff.</p>

<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/2022.html#oct2022'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for September</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/2022.html#sep2022</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>2022.html#sep2022</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of September. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.</p>

<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>
<ul>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/uxn.html' target='_blank'>Uxn</a></b>, updated <a href='
https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/uxn-playdate' target='_blank'>Playdate implementation</a> to the latest core, started <a href='https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/uxn-arduboy' target='_blank'>emulator</a> for Arduino.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/left.html' target='_blank'>Left</a></b>, added lots of little improvements for various reported drawing bugs.</li>
    <li><b><a href='http://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/bouc.html' target='_blank'>Bouc</a></b>, wrote a document reader.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/orca.html' target='_blank'>Orca</a></b>, added <a href='https://llllllll.co/t/orca-livecoding-tool/17689/1801' target='_blank'>monochromatic mode</a>.</li>
    <li><b><a href='http://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/cccc.html' target='_blank'>CCCC</a></b>, added monochromatic mode.</li>
    <li><b><a href='http://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/catclock.html' target='_blank'>Catclock</a></b>, added <a href='https://old.reddit.com/r/PlaydateConsole/comments/xsxyq4/a_little_cat_clock_for_the_playdate/' target='_blank'>monochromatic mode</a>(Reddit).</li>
    <li><b>100r.co</b>, added <a href='https://100r.co/site/lifelines.html' target='_blank'>lifelines</a> in <a href='https://100r.co/site/boat_projects.html' target='_blank'>boat projects</a>.</li>
</ul>

<h3>News</h3>

<p>The days are getting shorter, and so is the time that we can spend on the computer, due to our batteries depleting earlier a bit each day. So, Devine spends evenings proof-reading the <a href='https://100r.co/site/wiktopher.html' target='_blank'>wiktopher</a> manuscript, reading and messing around with the Playdate, and Rek continues ink work on an <a href='https://merveilles.town/@rek/109031721721868768' target='_blank'>upcoming project</a>(Mastodon, no project page yet).</p>

<p>While cleaning up the boat, Devine found two small black notebooks. We started paging through them, to see if we should keep them. The notebooks were full of sketches, interspersed with shopping lists, and incomplete logs from earlier sailing trips we'd done. We found logs detailing our very first attempt at sailing offshore, our sail down the US West Coast and Mexico, and our passage from Tonga to New Zealand. We read the logs, and decided to transcribe and publish them online. Read the <a href='https://100r.co/site/lost_logbook.html' target='_blank'>lost logbook</a>.</p>

<p>Devine wrote a little <a href='https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/arduino-cookbook/tree/main/item/adafruit-playground/teatime.ino' target='_blanl'>timer program</a> for the Adafruit Playground. </p>

<h3>Pino book club</h3>

<p>We're reading <b>Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy</b> by Douglas Adams.</p>

<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/2022.html#sep2022'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for August</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/2022.html#aug2022</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>2022.html#aug2022</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of August. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.</p>

<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>
<ul>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/left.html' target='_blank'>Left</a></b>, added a navigation bar to navigate larger codebases.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/potato.html' target='_blank'>potato</a></b>, implemented file system APIs so new files can be renamed, copied and deleted.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/noodle.html' target='_blank'>Noodle</a></b>, added various optimizations, improved TGA support.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/drifblim.html' target='_blank'>Drifblim</a></b>, completed rewrite. The assembler is now used to build all of our projects, with no more dependence on the C toolchain to make roms.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/uxnlin' target='_blank'>Uxnlin</a></b>, added a lot of recipes, making it better at finding possible code optimizations.</li>
</ul>

<h3>News</h3>

<p>Pino is back in the land of faster internet, and our boat's belly has been re-filled with food. We returned to the Gulf Islands, and are busy eating as many wild blackberries as we can stomach ('tis the season).</p>

<p>Our last anchorage in Desolation Sound was <a href='https://100r.co/site/tenedos_bay.html' target='_blank'>Tenedos Bay</a>, a really lovely place with an amazing (vertical) hike, and clear, clear waters. We also wrote a post on <a href="https://100r.co/site/sturt_bay.html" target="_blank">Sturt Bay</a> on Texada Island, a place we stopped on the way up earlier this year, and again when we traveled back south.</p>

<p>As mentioned brieftly in our last post, Devine has been working on an OS called <a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/potato.html' target='_blank'>Potato</a>. Rek drew a <a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/media/generic/potato.png' target='_blank'>mascot</a>, and another illustration featuring <a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/media/generic/varvara.potato.png' target='_blank'>Varvara and Potato together</a>. Potato is for the Varvara computer, designed to fill the gaps where a host device might not have an underlying file system, like handheld consoles (many people use <a href='https://100r.co/site/uxn.html' target='_blank'>Uxn</a> on Nintendo DS).</p>

<p>Rek has been drawing a lot, their winter will consist of scanning and processing a sketchbook-full of art. We are still proofreading <a href='https://100r.co/site/wiktopher.html' target='_blank'>Wiktopher</a>. A recent stop in Sidney permitted us to <a href='https://100r.co/media/content/projects/wiktopher_05.jpg' target='_blank'>print the entire book on paper</a> to make it easier (and more pleasant) to make corrections. The result is 70 (double-sided) pages of text. As of today, we have gone over and marked in red the first chapter (out of 12). Editing books is never easy or fast, but we'll get there.</p>

<p>We know a couple of people have made <a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/hako.html' target='_blank'>hako</a> dice sets, so we feel bad for "patching" a physical game, but the face organization of the die has changed somewhat, now, the opposing sides are always of equal value. If any of you are looking for a simple 2-player boardgame to play, try <a href='http://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/phutball.html' target='_blank'>Conway's Phutball</a>. Devine transcribed the rules on their wiki.</p>

<h3>Pino book club</h3>

<p>We're reading <b>Mathematical Puzzles & Diversions</b> by Martin Gardner.</p>

<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/2022.html#aug2022'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for July</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/2022.html#july2022</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>2022.html#july2022</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of July. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.</p>

<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>
<ul>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/adelie.html' target='_blank'>Adelie</a></b>, added image maps, animation controls, and wrote a guide. Rek also drew an Adelie penguin mascot.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/cccc.html' target='_blank'>Cccc</a></b>, created a graphical calculator.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/orca.html' target='_blank'>Orca</a></b>, added new font to make it easier to discern letters and numbers from afar (if projected onto a screen).</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/noodle.html' target='_blank'>Noodle</a></b>, re-designed noodle.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/minesweeper' target='_blank'>Minesweeper</a></b>, completed the game.</li>
</ul>

<h3>News</h3>

<p>Sometimes we find an anchorage that is so nice, so ideal, that we end up staying for weeks. We stayed in Von Donop Bay (<a href='https://100r.co/site/hathayim_marine_park.html' target='_blank'>hathayim marine park</a>) for well over a month. The southernmost anchorage is near many trails that snake and branch out deep into the woods, and the bay is so large that we kept finding new corners to explore by dinghy. The water in the area is warmer than in Victoria, we can dive, and check Pino's bottom without freezing. This is our first real summer on the boat, when we have no big boat projects to do, nor big transits to plan, and it feels amazing.</p>

<p>We have stretched our food stores to the limit (it has been 2 months since we last stocked up in full). A 5 km trek through the woods takes us to a little General Store, they never have fresh produce (or it gets bought out before we get there) but we go once in a while to replenish our stock of potatoes and onions. We are relying on sprouts a lot (see <a href='https://100r.co/site/growing_food.html' target='_blank'>growing food</a>).</p>

<p>This month, we made a <a href='https://nime2022.org/' target='_blank' class='external'>Keynote talk for Nime 2022</a>, and Devine started work on a little OS project called <a href='https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/potato' target='_blank'>Potato</a>, see <a href='https://merveilles.town/@neauoire/108744100597665776' target='_blank'>some footage</a>(Mastodon). There is no documentation yet, but soon.</p>

<h3>Pino book club</h3>

<p>We're reading <b>The Stories of Ray Bradbury</b> by Ray Bradbury.</p>

<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/2022.html#july2022'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for June</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/2022.html#june2022</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>2022.html#june2022</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of June. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.</p>

<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>
<ul>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/uxn.html' target='_blank'>Uxn</a></b>, improved the <a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/uxntal_reference.html' target='_blank'>Uxntal reference sheet</a> and improved the <a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/uxntal_cheatsheet.html' target='_blank'>Uxntal cheatsheet</a>.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/dexe.html' target='_blank'>Dexe</a></b>, added menu bar.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/nasu.html' target='_blank'>Nasu</a></b>, added menu bar.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/noodle.html' target='_blank'>Noodle</a></b>, added menu bar.</li>
    <li><b>100r.co</b>, updated <a href='https://100r.co/site/boom_tent.html' target='_blank'>boom tent</a>, and added <a href='https://100r.co/site/lpg_refit.html' target='_blank'>lpg refit</a> (backdated update).</li>
</u>

<h3>News</h3>

<p>Pino is currently in Desolation Sound, enjoying the quiet. We've written a few posts about some of the anchorages we've visited, like <a href="https://100r.co/site/melanie_cove.html">melanie cove</a>, <a href="https://100r.co/site/grace_harbour.html">grace harbour</a> and <a href="https://100r.co/site/hathayim_marine_park.html">hathayim marine park</a>. We're updating <a href='https://100r.co/site/about_us.html#where' target='_blank'>our track</a> as we go.</p>

<p>Devine has been adding a lot of notes to the <a href='https://permacomputing.net' target='_blank'>permacomputing wiki</a> this month. We also started a little arcade game named Inle, something that we could play together on the boat in the style of Gunbound/Tank Wars... but with rabbits (we finished reading Watership Down last month, so we blame that, haha). We don't have a project page yet for it, but we shared some images on the post for <a href='https://100r.co/site/grace_harbour.html' target='_blank'>grace harbour</a>, where we started working on the game.</p>

<p>Rek produced a video about <a href='https://youtu.be/cfrB4Gvpj8c' target='_blank'>image optimization</a> for the Photographer's Gallery (as part of their <a href='https://thephotographersgallery.org.uk/green-hacks' target='_blank'>Green Hacks</a> video series) last month.</p>

<h3>Pino book club</h3>

<p>We're reading <b>The Man who Mistook his Wife for a Hat</b> by Oliver Sacks.</p>

<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/2022.html#june2022'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for May</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/2022.html#may2022</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>2022.html#may2022</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of May. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.</p>

<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>
<ul>
    <li><b><a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/logic.html' target='_blank'>Combinatory Logic</a></b>, wrote a guide to combinatory logic, using talking birds.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/uxn.html' target='_blank'Uxn</a></b>, released a <a href='https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/uxnlin' target='_blank'>linter</a>, and optimized uxnasm.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/dexe.html' target='_blank'>Dexe</a></b>, released an updated version.</li>
    <li><b>100r.co</b>, added <a href='https://100r.co/site/batteries.html' target='_blank'>batteries</a>, and <a href='https://100r.co/site/regulator.html' target='_blank'>regulator</a>.</li>
</ul>

<h3>News</h3>

<p>From this month until next October, our updates may be delayed. We are sailing northward, towards Desolation Sound and the Broughtons, where cell towers are few. We will wander in and out of such regions all summer. So far, we sailed up to the Gulf Islands, and over to Nanaimo from Victoria, and then crossed the Strait of Georgia over to the Sunshine Coast(close-reaching in 20-knot winds). This was a good shakedown for Pino, a good way to re-awaken our little vessel. All went well, but we ought to have secured our produce better... some of our potatoes escaped their nest and went out for an afternoon roll around the cabin floor.</p>

<p>Start of May, we had some issues with our batteries. They've been acting out for some time, we think because of a dead cell. We have been operating at half battery capacity for a month, and realized that yet again we don't need that much power, especially in the summer when the days are long.</p>

<p>The combinatory logic guide is the first of many projects we plan to release this summer. We also released an <a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/uxntal_reference.html' target='_blank'>sign language version of Uxntal</a>.</p>

<p>In other news, a <a href='https://github.com/schierlm/collapseos-uxn' target='_blank'>version of Collapse OS</a> was ported to Uxn.</p>

<h3>Pino book club</h3>

<p>We're reading <b>Watership Down</b> by Richard Adams.</p>

<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/2022.html#may2022'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for April</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/2022.html#apr2022</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>2022.html#apr2022</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of April. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.</p>

<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>

<ul>
    <li><b><a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/bicycle.html' target='_blank'>Bicycle</a></b>, released an Uxntal playground. See <a href='https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/project/uxn/11.full.jpg' target='_blank'>Varvara riding a Sinclair bike</a>.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/uxn.html' target='_blank'>Uxn</a></b>, wrote a <a href='https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/uxn11' target='_blank'>linux native implementation</a> of Varvara, as well as an <a href='https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/uxn5' target='_blank'>HTML5 implementation</a> of the virtual machine.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/turquoise.html' target='_blank'>Turquoise</a></b>, released a little line plotting system.</li>
    <li><b>100r.co</b>, added <a href='https://100r.co/site/liveaboard.html#sewing' target='_blank'>sewing</a>, <a href='https://100r.co/site/shimoda.html' target='_blank'>Shimoda</a>, <a href='https://100r.co/site/cathedral_grove.html' target='_blank'>Cathedral Grove</a>, and <a href='https://100r.co/site/mini_dodger.html' target='_blank'>mini dodger</a>.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/nebu.html' target='_blank'>Nebu</a></b>, working on a spreadsheet editor in Uxn.</li>
</ul>

<h3>News</h3>

<p>The month of April was a time of boat projects. We built a <a href='https://100r.co/site/mini_dodger.html' target='_blank'>mini dodger</a> to cover the companionway, and installed a large <a href='https://100r.co/media/content/boat_projects/spindle_01.jpg' target='_blank'>spindle</a> for floating rope on Pino's stern (marine stores give those spindles away for free, usually). In these waters, it is often necessary to stern tie to shore when anchoring and the spindle will make it easier to uncoil the line.</p>

<p>We also took some time off to visit some ancient trees in <a href='https://100r.co/site/cathedral_grove.html' target='_blank'>Cathedral Grove</a> on Vancouver Island.</p>

<p>Devine found some slide rules and wrote a guide on <a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/slide_rule.html' target='_blank'>how to use them</a>.</p>

<p>If you want to play <a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/catpot.html' target='_blank'>Catpot</a>, the little Hypercard game we made for <a href='https://itch.io/jam/merveilles-hyperjam/entries' target='_blank'>Merveilles Hyperjam 2020</a>, you can play it with this <a href='https://hypercardsimulator.com' target='_blank'>Hypercard Simulator</a> (thank you Dan).</p>

<h3>Pino book club</h3>

<p>We're reading <b>The Stranger</b> by Albert Camus.</p>

<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/2022.html#apr2022'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for March</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/2022.html#mar2022</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>2022.html#mar2022</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of March. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.</p>
<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>
<ul>
    <li><b>100r</b>, released a guide to diesel <a href='https://100r.co/site/engine_care.html' target='_blank'>Engine Care</a>.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/wunderrabbits.html' target='_blank'>Wunderland Rabbits</a></b>, released a <a href='https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/wunderland_8.png' target='_blank'>new rabbit image</a>.</li>
    <li><b>Toys</b>, finished re-creating the <a href='https://merveilles.town/@neauoire/108036742103495267' target='_blank'>classic bouncing ball</a> for the Amiga for Uxn.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/uxn.html' target='_blank'>Uxn</a></b>, released <a href='https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/uxn11' target='_blank'>a 23kb implementation of the Varvara emulator</a> in plain X11(without SDL2), started a <a href='https://lists.sr.ht/~rabbits/uxn' target='_blank'>mailing list & newsletter</a> to document changes, events and exciting projects, released a <a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/varvara_devlog.html' target='_blank'>second devlog</a>, and wrote a little single-file uxntal assembler called <a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/drifblim.html' target='_blank'>Drifblim</a>.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/noodle.html' target='_blank'>Noodle</a></b>, re-worked entire tool, added <a href='https://merveilles.town/@neauoire/107900953148955327' target='_blank'>native TGA import</a>(Mastodon), implemented <a href='https://merveilles.town/@neauoire/107900062095605176' target='_blank'>file size loading specified in the pathname</a>(Mastodon), added the possiblity to <a href='https://merveilles.town/@neauoire/107888596799755319' target='_blank'>drag the canvas to resize it</a>(Mastodon), and implemented a <a href='https://merveilles.town/@neauoire/107878818327914910' target='_blank'>floating tool pane</a>(Mastodon) etc.</li>
</ul>

<h3>News</h3>

<p>A major update to our wiki is that we've put together a text with our stance on various political aspects. Because of the decentralized nature of some of our work, and because of the overlap of libertarians and right-wing doomsday preppers and our documenting survivalism at sea, there were things that just had to be spelled out quite clearly. See <a href='https://100r.co/site/philosophy.html' target='_blank'>philosophy</a>. We've appended a notice to our <a href='https://100r.co/site/off_the_grid.html' target='_blank'>off the grid</a> page too, since it gets shared the most.</p>

<p>A lot of our time this month was dedicated to preparing for our keynote talk for <a href='https://libreplanet.org/2022/program/' target='_blank'>LibrePlanet 2022</a> called Software Doldrums. If you missed it the talk was recorded, watch it <a href='https://media.libreplanet.org/u/libreplanet/m/software-doldrums/' target='_blank'>here</a>. Rek illustrated all of the slides for the presentation, gathered <a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/fsftalk.html' target='_blank'>here</a>. These images are now scattered on our wiki. Devine built the <a href='https://100r.co/site/uxn.html' target='_blank'>Uxn</a> slideshow program <a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/adelie.html' target='_blank'>Adelie</a> for that presentation, we plan to use it again for all future talks.</p>

<p>The day prior, Devine gave a <a href='https://youtu.be/h1eC8czDAkk' target='_blank'>short performance</a>(YouTube) for <a href='https://ten.algorave.com/' target='_blank'>Algorave's 10-year anniversary</a>, alongside over 140+ artists. The event was 24 hours, with everyone playing a 10-minute set.</p>

<p>Uxn was featured on The Verge, in an article entitled <a href='https://www.theverge.com/22935074/hundred-rabbits-uxn-roms-preservation' target='_blank'>These artists are making tiny ROMs that will probably outlive us all</a>. And Devine was <a href='https://medium.com/behind-the-screens-challenge/behind-the-screens-aliceffekt-3394fa66e625' target='_blank'>interviewed</a>(Medium) for <a href='https://medium.com/behind-the-screens-challenge' target='_blank'>Behind the Screens</a>.</p>

<p>In other news, we finally made some <a href='https://100r.co/site/store.html#stickers' target='_blank'>Uxn sticker sheets</a>!</p>

<h3>Pino book club</h3>

<p>We're reading <b>We Have Always Lives in the Castle</b> by Shirley Jackson.</p>

<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/2022.html#mar2022'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for February</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/2022.html#feb2022</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>2022.html#feb2022</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of February. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.</p>
<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>

<ul>
    <li><b><a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/adelie.html' target='_blank'>Adelie</a></b>, released a program to create slideshows.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://grimgrains.com' target='_blank'>GrimGrains</a></b>, added a new recipe: <a href='https://grimgrains.com/site/bean_chili.html' target='_blank'>Bean chili</a>.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/thousand_rooms.html' target='_blank'>Thousand Rooms</a></b>, released <a href='https://hundredrabbits.itch.io/thousand-rooms/devlog/352502/catalan-version' target='_blank'>Catalan version</a>, a translation by Dani Sevilla.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co' target='_blank'>100r.co</a></b>, added a new project: <a href='https://100r.co/site/gravity_water_filter.html' target='_blank'>Gravity water filter</a>.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/uxn.html' target='_blank'>Uxn</a></b>, Cancel(Andrew R.) released a new version of <a href='https://github.com/randrew/uxn32/releases' target='_blank'>uxn32</a> with complete step debugging tools. Added <a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/varvara.html' target='_blank'>new art</a> for the Varvara docs.</a>.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/orca.html' target='_blank'>Orca</a></b>, implemented <a href='https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oXmKJ_tYg34&feature=youtu.be' target='_blank'>injections</a>(YouTube), and <a href='https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xIBTzswUmzY' target='_blank'>J and Y wiring</a>(YouTube).</li>
    <li><b>Toys</b>, released <a href='https://100r.co/site/uxn.html' target='_blank'>Uxn</a> versions of <a href='https://merveilles.town/@neauoire/107868108987441439' target='_blank'>Minesweeper</a>(Mastodon), and <a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/wireworld.html' target='_blank'>Wireworld</a>.</li>
</ul>

<h3>News</h3>

<p>This month it was announced that we joined <a href='https://libreplanet.org/2022/program/' target='_blank'>LibrePlanet 2022</a> as <a href='https://www.fsf.org/news/artist-collective-hundred-rabbits-to-keynote-libreplanet-living-liberation' target='_blank'>keynote speakers</a>. The annual technology and social justice conference will be held virtually on March 19 and 20, 2022, with the theme Living Liberation. Our talk is named Software Doldrums.</p>

<p>Rek is putting the finishing touches to <a href='https://100r.co/site/wiktopher.html' target='_blank'>Wiktopher</a>, and Devine designed a game that the people of Irideri could be playing. The result was a dice game combining the capture mechanism of Go and the randomness of the Domino. Learn to play <a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/hako.html' target='_blank'>Hako</a>. Each player has a Sonozai, a set of 4 dice on a rope. Merveillans have been making their own sets:</p>
<ul>
    <li><a href='https://merveilles.town/@nff/107854983461917482' target='_blank'>recycled construction wood set</a></li>
    <li><a href='https://merveilles.town/@cassvs/107873045589387586' target='_blank'>3d-printed bracelet set</a></li>
    <li><a href='https://merveilles.town/@FredBednarski/107817076522474670' target='_blank'>3d-printable concept</a></li>
</ul>

<p><a href='https://nchrs.xyz/site/home.html' target='_blank'>Rostiger</a> has been making illustrated notes for Uxn, and they are <a href='https://nchrs.xyz/site/uxn_notes.html' target='_blank'>fabulous</a>.</p>

<h3>Pino book club</h3>

<p>We're reading <b>Underland</b> by Robert Macfarlane.</p>

<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/2022.html#jan2022'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for January</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/2022.html#jan2022</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>2022.html#jan2022</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of January. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.</p>
<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>

<ul>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/left.html' target='_blank'>Left</a></b>, re-wrote documentation, redesigned the UX for save-as/open-as.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/orca.html' target='_blank'>Orca</a></b>, re-wrote documentation, and added the operators manual on launch.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/thousand_rooms.html' target='_blank'>Thousand Rooms</a></b>, released <a href='https://hundredrabbits.itch.io/thousand-rooms/devlog/339627/epub-version-plus-3-new-languages' target='_blank'>3 new languages</a>: Polish, Hungarian and Serbian. Now offering book as an ePUB.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/uxn.html' target='_blank'>Uxn</a></b>, re-wrote entire documentation, and started a <a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/uxn_devlog.html' target='_blank'>project devlog</a>.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/nasu.html' target='_blank'>Nasu</a></b>, improved zoom tool, it is now possible <a href='https://merveilles.town/@neauoire/107697043487251948' target='_blank'>to move between tiles</a>(Masto) while zoomed.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://hundredrabbits.itch.io/yufo' target='_blank'>Yufo</a></b>, released a small game for the <a href='https://itch.io/jam/virtual-pet-jam' target='_blank'>Virtual Pet Jam</a>.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/' target='_blank'>100r</a></b>, added new page: <a href='https://100r.co/site/cooking.html#cast_iron_cookware' target='_blank'>cast-iron cookware</a>, and updated <a href='https://100r.co/site/off_the_grid.html#medical' target='_blank'>medical</a>.</li>
</ul>

<h3>News</h3>

<p>On January 28th Uxn turned 1 year old! We'd like to thank everyone who has contributed code, ideas, time and laughs to help this project grow into what it is now. It was a wonderful year for smol ordinators. See an image that Rek made for <a href='https://100r.co/media/content/stream/2022_01uxn_bday.jpg' target='_blank'>uxn's birthday</a>.</p>

<p>We finally released versions of the Uxn emulator for <a href='https://100r.co/site/uxn.html' target='_blank'>all major systems</a>(Linux, OS X and Windows), with the option of a version bundled with a few starter roms. We simplified <a href='https://100r.co/site/uxn_guide.html' target='_blank'>the guide</a> too, to make it easier to install and use.</p>

<p>Our lion's mane mushroom grew another full head, we harvested it and made some <a href='https://100r.co/media/content/stream/2022_01lionmane_tempura.jpg' target='_blank'>mushroom pakoras</a>.</p>

<p>In other news, Devine was interviewed on <a href='https://anonradio.net/' target='_blank'>Anonradio</a>, listen to it <a href='https://archives.anonradio.net/202201181600_gef.mp3' target='_blank'>here</a>. Also, <a href='https://compudanzas.net/'>Compudanzas</a> released an <a href='https://compudanzas.net/introduction_to_uxn_programming_book.html'>Introduction to Uxn Programming</a> book, with a foreword by Devine.</p>

<h3>Pino book club</h3>

<p>We're reading <b>The Complete Cosmicomics</b> by Italo Calvino, and <b>The Dawn of Everything: A New History of Humanity</b> by David Graeber.</p>

<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/2022.html#jan2022'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for December</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/2021.html#dec2021</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>2021.html#dec2021</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of December. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.</p>
<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>

<ul>
    <li><b><a href='https://grimgrains.com'>Grimgrains</a></b>, published a <a href='https://grimgrains.com/site/soy_flour_tofu.html' target='_blank'>tofu from soy flour</a> recipe, and reduced the amount of ingredients appearing on the main page so it loads faster.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/left.html' target'_blank'>Left</a></b>, created <a href='https://100r.co/site/left.html#graphic'>inline image support</a>, and implemented a <a href='https://twitter.com/hundredrabbits/status/1466832328462790656?s=20' target='_blank'>search feature</a>(Birdsite) inspired by the Canon Cat(1987)'s LEAP™ key.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/catclock' target='_blank'>Cat Clock</a></b>, released our very own <a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/catclock.html' target='_blank'>cat clock</a>.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/turye' target='_blank'>Turye</a></b>, released a <a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/turye.html' target='_blank'>font editor</a>.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/tga_format.html' target='_blank'>TGA parser</a></b>, released a tool to make it easier to bring images into the Uxn ecosystem.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/wunderrabbits.html' target='_blank'>Wunderland Rabbits</a></b>, released a <a href='https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/wunderland_7.jpg' target='_blank'>new image</a>.</li>
</ul>

<h3>News</h3>

<p>It is snowing, and we are cocooning. Our little <a href='https://100r.co/site/woodstove.html' target'_blank'>woodstove</a> is working hard. This month, we finally decided to release a <a href='https://www.lulu.com/en/us/shop/rekka-bellum-and-devine-lu-linvega/busy-doing-nothing/paperback/product-rqgmdj.html?page=1&pageSize=4' target='_blank'>paperback version</a> of <a href='https://100r.co/site/busy_doing_nothing.html' target='_blank'>Busy Doing Nothing</a>.</p>

<p>In our last update log, we mentioned that we were trying to grow Lion's Mane mushroom, and we are happy to report that it was a success! It <a href='https://100r.co/media/content/cooking/fungi2.jpg'>grew beautifully</a>. Rek was so excited about the mushroom that they decided to <a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/vanislandmushroom.html' target='_blank'>draw some</a> this month, this series focuses on varieties that grow on Vancouver Island.</p>

<p>In other news, we had an interview with the founder of <a href='https://sourcehut.org/' target='_blank'>Sourcehut</a>, read it <a href='https://sourcehut.org/blog/2021-12-08-100-rabbits-interview/' target='_blank'>here</a>. Also, our good friend Alderwick make us a very cool <a href='https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=i83FTGk24JM' target='_blank'>gift</a>(YouTube).</p>

<h3>Pino book club</h2>

<p>We're reading <b><a href='https://fantomeszine.com/' target='_blank'>Fantômes: Issue 1</a></b>, with work by 18 talented artists, put together by <a href='https://ritualdust.com/' target='_blank'>Lizbeth</a>. It is a eerie, and gorgeous zine, we strongly recommend the Mike Wolf version.</p>

<p><b>Pino's location:</b> 48° 42.230'N, 123° 36.900'W</p>

<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/2021.html#dec2021'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for November</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/2021.html#nov2021</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>2021.html#nov2021</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of November. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.</p>
<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>

<ul>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/donsol.html'>Donsol</a></b>, designed a <a href='https://100r.co/media/content/projects/donsol.turnip.png'>donsol turnip</a>.</li>
    <li><b><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/uxn.html'>Uxn</a></b></b>, wrote a <a href='https://merveilles.town/@neauoire/107242490491463187' target='_blank'>file browser rom</a>(Mastodon), improved on uxn utilities (<a href='https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4ghtdaoqghA' target='_blank'>clock</a>, <a href='https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GGGzWRWGIq4' target='_blank'>calculator</a>.</li>
    <li><b><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/nasu.html'>Nasu</a></b></b>, added <a href="https://100r.co/site/nasu.html#nametable">nametable</a> to preview items on the spritesheet, and added <a href="https://100r.co/site/nasu.html#blendview">option to flip a sprite horizontally or vertically</a> in the blend view.</li>
    <li><b><b><a href='https://100r.co/'>100r</a></b></b>, added an information section on <a href="https://100r.co/site/drownspire" target="_blank">Drownspire</a>, the studio we had prior to hundredrabbits.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/oquonie.html'>Oquonie</a></b>, started tests to <a href='https://twitter.com/hundredrabbits/status/1461009105750003723' target="_blank">port the game to Uxntal</a>(Birdsite).</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/left.html'>Left</a></b>, fixed bugs and improved speed.</li>
</ul>

<h3>News</h3>

<p>This month, there was an <a href='https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LrNuq_JgaOA' target='_blank'>intro to Uxn Programming</a>(YouTube) workshop by <a href='https://compudanzas.net/' target='_blank'>Compudanzas</a>, an event by <a href='https://www.babycastles.com/academy' target='_blank'>Babycastles Academy</a>. Give it a watch!</p>

<p>November was a very rainy month in Victoria, a perfect time for experiments in the galley. We are growing Lion's Mane mushrooms currently (a first for us), and we are continuing to lacto-ferment vegetables like kohlrabi, turnips, daikon, cauliflower and red onion. To learn how to do it, see our <a href='https://grimgrains.com/site/lactofermentation.html' target='_blank'>guide to lactofermentation</a>.</p>

<h3>Pino book club</h2>

<p>We're reading <b>The Summer Book</b> by Tove Jansson (it's such a lovely book).</p>

<p><b>Pino's location:</b> 48° 42.230'N, 123° 36.900'W</p>

<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/2021.html#nov2021'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for October</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/2021.html#oct2021</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>2021.html#oct2021</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of October. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.</p>
<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>

<ul>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/donsol.html' >donsol</a></b>, ported our Famicom(6502) code to Varvara(<a href='https://100r.co/site/uxn.html' >uxn</a>).</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/uxn.html' >uxn</a></b>, wrote a <a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/uxntal_reference.html' target='_blank'>reference guide</a> and created a list of <a href='https://github.com/hundredrabbits/awesome-uxn' target='_blank'>community projects</a>.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/noodle.html' >noodle</a></b>, added guides for the line and rectangle tool and <a href='https://100r.co/site/noodle.html#controls'>updated shortcuts</a> in the documentation.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/grimgrains.html' >grimgrains</a></b>, optimized images and published a <a href='https://grimgrains.com/site/chunky_apple_jam.html' target='_blank'>Chunky Apple Jam<a> recipe.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/'>100r</a></b>, optimized images (see Rek's <a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/leanimages.html'>notes</a>). Added new pages: <a href='https://100r.co/site/boom_tent.html' >boom tent</a>, <a href='https://100r.co/site/grinder.html' >grinder</a> and <a href='https://100r.co/site/small_space.html' >small space</a>.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/left.html' >left</a></b>, optimized code.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/nasu.html' >nasu</a></b>, fixed crashing bug with large selections.</li>
</ul>

<h3>News</h3>

<p>This month, we found a used <a href='https://100r.co/site/grinder.html'>grain mill</a> for Pino! Flour doesn't keep as well as whole grains, so we decided to start milling flour (wheat berries, soy beans or chickpeas) only as we need it. We only released a <a href='https://grimgrains.com/site/lactofermentation.html'>Guide to Lacto-fermenting vegetables</a> on <a href='https://100r.co/site/grimgrains.html' >grimgrains</a>.</p>

<p>Donsol is now available as an <a href='https://100r.co/site/uxn.html' >uxn</a> rom on <a href='https://hundredrabbits.itch.io/donsol' target='_blank'>itchio</a>.</p>

<p>See Devine's <a href='https://merveilles.town/web/statuses/107033448028097574' target='_blank'>daily drawings series</a> for October.</p>

<h3>Pino book club</h2>

<p>We're continuing our readings of <b>The Stories of Ray Bradbury</b> by Ray Bradbury. Favorite shorts this month include <b>The Long Rain</b>, <b>The City</b> and <b>Kaleidoscope</b>.</p>

<p><b>Pino's location:</b> 48° 42.230'N, 123° 36.900'W</p>

<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/2021.html#oct2021'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for September</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/2021.html#sep2021</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>2021.html#sep2021</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of September. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.</p>
<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>

<ul>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/orca.html' target='_blank'>Orca</a></b>, added way for instances of Orca to <a href='https://twitter.com/hundredrabbits/status/1437152929606033408?s=20' target='_blank'>talk to each other</a>.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/uxn/tree/main/item/projects/software/calc.tal' target='_blank'>Calc</a></b>, wrote <a href='https://twitter.com/hundredrabbits/status/1440841581641097223?s=20' target='_blank'>a little graphical calculator</a> to help with learning binary and hexadecimal.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/dexe/' target='_blank'>Dexe</a></b>, added <a href='https://twitter.com/hundredrabbits/status/1441833098828681220?s=20' target='_blank'>option</a> to copy the textual value of a selection.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/uxn.html' target='_blank'>Uxn</a></b>, updated <a href='https://twitter.com/hundredrabbits/status/1442188840110678016?s=20' target='_blank'>UxnDS emulator</a>.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/wiktopher.html' target='_blank'>Wiktopher</a></b>, added <a href='https://wiktopher.ca/site/chapter_16.html' target='_blank'>Chapter 16: The Big Dark</a>.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/' target='_blank'>100R</a></b>, added new pages: <a href='https://100r.co/site/western_canada.html' target='_blank'>Western Canada</a>, <a href='https://100r.co/site/alcohol_stove.html' target='_blank'>alcohol stove</a>, <a href='https://100r.co/site/decorations.html' target='_blank'>decorations</a> and <a href='https://100r.co/site/shore_power_cord_repair.html' target='_blank'>shore power cord repair</a>. The site also has a <a href='https://100r.co/site/home.html'>new splash</a>.</li>
</ul>

<h3>News</h3>

<p>It is an early announcement, but end of June 2022 we will be giving a keynote presentation, alongside Khyam Allami, at <a href='https://nime2022.org/' target='_blank'>NIME</a>(New Interfaces for Musical Expression).</p>

<p>Rek wrote an article on <a href='https://www.noonsite.com/report/insights-how-to-save-energy-when-cooking-onboard/' target='_blank'>Saving Energy When Cooking Aboard</a> for <a href='https://www.noonsite.com' target='_blank'>Noonsite</a>.</p>

<p>Check out Eli's guide on <a href='https://eli.li/2021/09/27/how-to-install-uxn-on-macos' target='_blank'>installing Uxn on OS X</a>, and Keijiro's version of <a href='https://twitter.com/hundredrabbits/status/1440092877950914563?s=20' target='_blank'>Flappy Bird</a> in <a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/uxntal.html' target='_blank'>UxnTal</a>.</p>

<p>Our friends at Compudanzas have released <a href='https://compudanzas.net/uxn_tutorial_day_6.html' target='_blank'>part 6</a> of their <a href='https://compudanzas.net/uxn_tutorial.html' target='_blank'>Introduction to Uxn Programming tutorial</a>. This new chapter basically shows you how to build Pong!</p>

<h3>Pino book club</h2>

<p>We started reading <b>The Stories of Ray Bradbury</b> by Ray Bradbury. Favorite shorts so far include <b>There Will Come Soft Rains</b>, <b>The Coffin</b> and <b>There Was an Old Woman</b>.</p>

<p><b>Pino's location:</b> 48° 42.230'N, 123° 36.900'W</p>

<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/2021.html#sep2021'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for August</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/2021.html#aug2021</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>2021.html#aug2021</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of August. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.</p>
<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>

<ul>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/nasu.html' target='blank'>Nasu</a></b>, implemented a way to <a href='https://twitter.com/hundredrabbits/status/1424081933802172420?s=20' target='_blank'>shift multiple tiles at once</a>, and added a <a href='https://twitter.com/hundredrabbits/status/1423392879649574913?s=20' target='_blank'>snarf buffer</a> to copy/paste data between instances of Nasu.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/niju.html' target='blank'>Niju</a></b>, completed, and released the project on <a href='https://hundredrabbits.itch.io/niju' target='_blank'>itch.io</a>.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/orca.html' target='blank'>Orca</a></b>, implemented <a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/snarf.html' target='_blank'>snarf buffer</a> to easily bring patches in and out of it (uxn version).</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/uxn.html' target='blank'>Uxn</a></b>, massive <a href='https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/uxn/tree/main/item/src/uxn.c' target='_blank'>re-write</a> of the Uxn VM, and <a href='https://t.co/sNNb1fnTnT?amp=1' target='_blank'>CollapseOS</a> now <a href='https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/uxn-collapse' target='_blank'>runs on Uxn</a>.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/paradise.html' target='blank'>Paradise</a></b>, started on a <a href='https://twitter.com/hundredrabbits/status/1430677266879565827?s=20' target='_blank'>Uxn-native version</a>.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/noodle.html' target='blank'>noodle</a></b>, created a <a href='https://twitter.com/hundredrabbits/status/1431666810139537408?s=20' target='_blank'>mascot</a>, and added a tiny <a href='https://twitter.com/hundredrabbits/status/1428472855382003715?s=20' target='_blank'>animation toolkit</a>.</a>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/' target='blank'>100r.co</a></b>, added various <a href='https://100r.co/site/cooking.html#insulation_cooking'>hand drawn images</a> to the knowledge base.</li>
</ul>

<h3>News</h3>

<p>This month, our little engine was fixed (read about it <a href='https://100r.co/site/engine_rebuild.html'>here</a>) we've been sailing around the Gulf Islands, working from anchor. We also found Iggy's successor, a used fiberglass dinghy that we've named <a href='https://100r.co/site/teapot.html' target='_blank'>Teapot</a>. We've been rowing it from ship to shore, and it's so, so nice. We stopped by Saltspring Island and got to meet the sailors on <a href='https://t.co/6uPzFcUSvf?amp=1' target='_blank'>BosunBird</a>, a couple who have traveled around the world on a Vancouver27. Their blog was an invaluable resource for us on our travels through Japan. </p>

<p>We've released a solid version of <a href='https://100r.co/site/noodle.html' target='blank'>noodle</a>, our drawing tool. Follow the <a href='https://100r.co/site/noodle.html#setup' target='_blank'>tutorial</a> on our website, or check out this amazing <a href='https://hundredrabbits.itch.io/noodle/community' target='_blank'>quick start guide</a> by Polyducks. We also released <a href='https://100r.co/site/niju.html' target='blank'>niju</a>, our little kana-learning game. Niju was a trial to see if we could design, write and assemble a project entirely within the Uxn computer.</p>

<p>Our friends at Compudanzas have released part <a href='https://compudanzas.net/uxn_tutorial_day_3.html' target='_blank'>3</a>, <a href='https://compudanzas.net/uxn_tutorial_day_4.html' target='_blank'>4</a> and <a href='https://compudanzas.net/uxn_tutorial_day_5.html' target='_blank'>5</a> of their <a href='https://compudanzas.net/uxn_tutorial.html' target='_blank'>Introduction to Uxn Programming tutorial</a>.</p>

<h3>Pino book club</h2>

<p>Help. We still haven't finished <b>The Swarm</b> by Frank Schatzing. It is terrible, but we can't stop.</p>
<p><b>Pino's location:</b> 48° 53.370'N, 123° 23.734'W</p>

<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/2021.html#aug2021'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for July</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/2021.html#july2021</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>2021.html#july2021</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of July. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.</p>
<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>
<ul>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/nasu.html' target='blank'>Nasu</a></b>, implemented the <a href='https://twitter.com/hundredrabbits/status/1418608908273295364' target='_blank'>export of .theme files</a>, and <a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/theme.html' target='_blank'>theme support</a>.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/left.html' target='blank'>Left</a></b>, worked on <a href='https://t.co/FOqVPdZiSO' target='_blank'>Uxn-native version</a>, and implemented <a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/theme.html' target='_blank'>theme support</a>.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/niju.html' target='blank'>Niju</a></b>, progressed on <a href='https://twitter.com/hundredrabbits/status/1419370785794256896' target='_blank'>animations</a> and started <a href='https://merveilles.town/web/statuses/106642679616263419' target='_blank'>implementing controls</a>.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://grimgrains.com/'>Grimgrains</a></b>, added a new recipe: <a href='https://grimgrains.com/site/stovetop_blackberry_cake.html'>Stovetop Blackberry Cake</a>.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/wiktopher.html' target='blank'>Wiktopher</a></b>, added a new chapter: <a href='https://wiktopher.ca/site/chapter_15.html'>Lupin's Logbook</a>.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/uxn.html' target='blank'>Uxn</a></b>, created a <a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/ufx_format.html' target='_blank'>proportional font format</a> for Uxn, and improved documention for <a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/varvara.html' target='_blank'>Varvara</a>.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/orca.html' target='blank'>Orca</a></b>, implemented <a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/theme.html' target='_blank'>theme support</a></li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/noodle.html' target='blank'>Noodle</a></b>, published <a href='https://100r.co/site/noodle.html' target='_blank'>tutorial</a>, and implemented <a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/theme.html' target='_blank'>theme support</a>
</ul>

<h3>News</h3>

<p>This month, Calcifer is being re-built. While we wait for that, we're working on more projects aboard. We added <a href='https://100r.co/site/insulation.html' target='blank'>insulation</a> to the v-berth, an attempt to keep Pino warm this winter. We created a new portal called <a href='https://100r.co/site/boat_projects.html' target='blank'>boat projects</a> on our wiki that covers most of the major construction projects we've done to the boat.</p>
<p>Our friends at Compudanzas have started writing an <a href='https://compudanzas.net/uxn_tutorial.html' target='_blank'>Introduction to Uxn Programming tutorial</a>. We recommend it to anyone interested in programming for the Uxn Computer. No prior understanding of stack-machines, or Assembly, required! The first covers <a href='https://compudanzas.net/uxn_tutorial_day_1.html' target='_blank'>basics</a>, and the latest chapter focuses on learning to <a href='https://compudanzas.net/uxn_tutorial_day_2.html' target='_blank'>draw pixels on the screen</a>.</p>
<p>If you missed Devine's performance at <a href='https://flashcrash.net/' target='_blank'>Flash Crash</a>, you can watch it <a href='https://youtu.be/N_00rAa8o24' target='_blank'>here</a>.</p>

<h3>Pino book club</h2>

<p>We're reading <b>Mingming & the Art of Minimal Ocean Sailing</b> by Roger Taylor and <b>The Swarm</b> by Frank Schatzing.</p>

<p><b>Pino's location:</b> 48° 40.768'N, 123° 24.802'W</p>
<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/2021.html#july2021'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Dry Toilet Installation</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/dry_toilet_installation.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>dry_toilet_installation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<img src='https://100r.co/media/content/boat_projects/drytoilet.jpg' width='600'/><p>The work is done. Building a dry toilet was more work than we had anticipated, but we still prefer it over the ready-made models. We learned tons doing it, and now our toilet is perfectly suited to our space. The pandemic has pushed more people into boat and van living (to travel within their own countries) and towards simple systems. Looking at the Nature's Head website, they've had a 8-week waiting list for ages. It's either you wait for the thing, or you build the thing.</p>
<p>Dry toilets are simple to use and have few parts, but it doesn't mean that they are simple to build. Simple is hard, it costs time, and requires a ton of creativity.</p>
<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/dry_toilet_installation.html'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for June</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/2021.html#june2021</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>2021.html#june2021</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of June. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.</p>
<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>
<ul>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/nasu.html'>Nasu</a></b>, released a <a href='https://100r.co/site/nasu_guide.html'>nasu guide</a>, and updated the look of the <a href='https://100r.co/media/content/tools/nasu/nasu.turnip.png' target='_blank'>icon</a>. We have also discontinued the old javascript version.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/uxn.html'>Uxn</a></b>, released an <a href='https://100r.co/site/uxn_guide.html'>uxn guide</a>.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/orca.html'>Orca</a></b>, working on the <a href='https://twitter.com/hundredrabbits/status/1409923644076085249' target='_blank'>Uxn port</a>.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/niju.html'>Niju</a></b>, started work on <a href='https://merveilles.town/@rek/106427430345464918' target='_blank'>sprites</a>. Implemented <a href='https://merveilles.town/@neauoire/106501211625815384' target='_blank'>hover states</a>.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/noodle'>Noodle</a></b>, made Noodle responsive for small screens and added highlight to save state</li>
</ul>

<h3>News</h3>

<p>Pino and crew spent the first half of the month in the boatyard. We splashed back into the water on the 14th and moved to North Saanich to have access to a workshop with the goal of completing our <a href='https://100r.co/site/dry_toilet.html'>dry toilet</a>. We are documenting the entire <a href='https://100r.co/site/dry_toilet_installation.html'>installation</a>, with plans to update the page when we begin to use it. We are ALMOST done with this project.</p>

<p>We started working on Niju, a hiragana/katakana review application. We used this project to test our the latest iteration of Nasu so we could finalize the <a href='https://100r.co/site/nasu_guide.html'>documentation</a>.</p>

<p>On June 26 2021, Devine met up with the London SF reading group to <a href='https://twitter.com/hundredrabbits/status/1407718927656919053' target='_blank'>talk about solarpunk</a>, see their <a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/solarpunk.html' target='_blank'>notes</a>. On July 10th UTC 20:00, Devine will also perform with  <a href='https://100r.co/site/orca.html'>Orca</a> for <a href='https://flashcrash.net/' target='_blank'>flash crash</a>.</p>

<p>See Uxn running on the <a href='https://merveilles.town/web/statuses/106482004195786910' target='_blank'>ESP32</a>. It is TOO adorable!</p>

<p>

<h3>Pino book club</h2>

<p>We're reading <b>Nature as Measure</b> by Wes Jackson, <b>The Strange Last Voyage of Donald Crowhurst</b> by Nicholas Tomalin and Ron Hall and <b>Labyrinths</b> by Jorge Luis Borges.</p>

<p><b>Pino's location:</b> 48° 40.768'N, 123° 24.802'W</p>
<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/2021.html#june2021'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for May</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/2021.html#may2021</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>2021.html#may2021</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of May. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.</p>
<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>
<ul>
    <li><b><a href='https://t.co/FE3f7zKC2R?amp=1' target='_blank'>Noodle</a></b>, released <a href='https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/noodle' target='_blank'>Uxn version</a>. <a href='https://twitter.com/hundredrabbits/status/1396941515994198020?s=20' target='_blank'>Improved UX</a> to resize the canvas and fixed <a href='https://twitter.com/hundredrabbits/status/1395795883015303168?s=20' target='_blank'>stylus picking</a> for Nintendo DS version.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://git.sr.ht/~rabbits/nasu' target='_blank'>Nasu</a></b>, completed <a href='https://twitter.com/hundredrabbits/status/1395126409798901760?s=20' target='_blank'>port to Uxn</a>.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/uxn.html'>Uxn</a></b>, runs on <a href='https://twitter.com/hundredrabbits/status/1394417389656174592?s=20' target='_blank'>9front</a> and <a href='https://twitter.com/hundredrabbits/status/1392192734899761152?s=20' target='_blank'>Raspberry pi</a>.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://grimgrains.com/site/buckwheat_dumplings.html' target='_blank'>GrimGrains</a></b>, added <a href='https://grimgrains.com/site/buckwheat_dumplings.html' target='_blank'>Buckwheat Dumpling</a> recipe.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/wunderrabbits.html' target='_blank'>Wunderland Rabbits</a></b>, added two new travel pics: <a href='https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/wunderland_5.jpg' target='_blank'>Rhodo Ravine</a> and <a href='https://kokorobot.ca/media/content/wunderland_6.jpg' target='_blank'>Patricia Bay</a>.</li>
</ul>

<h3>News</h3>

<p>There has been a lot of activity on Uxn this month! It's exciting to see it work on a variety of devices, like the <a href='https://twitter.com/hundredrabbits/status/1396474870070792195?s=20'>PS vita</a>, <a href='https://git.badd10de.dev/uxngba/about/' target='_blank'>Gameboy Advance</a> and the <a href='https://twitter.com/hundredrabbits/status/1395463655882313728?s=20' target='_blank'>Nintendo DS</a>. We love the idea that most people already have the all hardware necessary to run our software.</p>

<p>We hosted a small cooking jam on Merveilles, feel free to peruse <a href='https://merveilles.town/web/timelines/tag/thegalley' target='_blank'>The Galley</a> tag to see the recipes.</p>

<p>In Pino related news, we are moving north. First stop, the boatyard. We'll be doing a bunch of changes to the studio this week, like removing and replacing old thru-hulls and installing a dry toilet.</p>

<h3>Pino book club</h2>

<p>We're reading <b>Farenheit 451</b> by Ray Bradbury.</p>

<p><b>Pino's location:</b> 48° 40.768'N, 123° 24.802'W</p>
<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/2021.html#may2021'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
</description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for April</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/2021.html#apr2021</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>2021.html#apr2021</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of April. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.</p>
<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>
<ul>
    <li><b><a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/uxn.html'>Uxn</a></b>, improved <a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/uxntal.html' target='_blank'>documentation</a>, implemented <a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/uxnemu.html' target='_blank'>MIDI and sound chip</a>, and drew some <a href='https://merveilles.town/web/statuses/106083402525675331' target='_blank'>new art</a> for the documentation.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/bifurcan.html' target='_blank'>Birfucan</a></b>, <a href='https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5U4cAs_gTE8' target='_blank'>ported</a> to Uxn.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/nasu.html'>Nasu</a></b>, general <a href='https://merveilles.town/web/statuses/106081729955211474' target='_blank'>improvements</a>.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://wiktopher.ca' target='_blank'>Wiktopher</a></b>, released <a href='https://wiktopher.ca/site/chapter_14.html' target='_blank'>Chapter 14: Tarka</a>.</li>
</ul>

<h3>News</h3>

<p>This month, we converted the old static version of our website into a <a href='https://100r.co/site/index.html'>wiki</a>, with pages for each of the various projects we've been working on aboard Pino. We hope you like it!</p> 

<p>We also finished installing our <a href='https://100r.co/site/woodstove_installation.html' target='_blank'>wood stove</a>. Our timing could have been better (it's summer now), but we'll be able to keep warm while at anchor next winter. We have many projects to do, including the removal and replacement of many thru-hulls and plumbing, as well as the installation of a dry toilet. Looks like Pino will have to come out of the water again this year!</p>

<h3>Pino book club</h2>

<p>We're reading <b>Terre des Hommes</b> by Antoine de Saint-Exupéry and <b>Sylvie and Bruno</b> by Lewis Carroll.</p>

<p><b>Pino's location:</b> 48° 42.230'N, 123° 36.900'W</p>
<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/2021.html#apr2021'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Wood stove installation</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/woodstove_installation.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>woodstove_installation.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<img src='https://100r.co/media/content/boat_projects/woodstove_01.jpg' width='600'/><p>It was our dream to have a little wood stove aboard Pino. After researching stoves, we decided that the best model was the cast iron Sardine from Navigator Stoveworks.</p>
<p>Our Espar forced air diesel heater broke on our last passage, and we decided not to replace it. There are few low-power alternatives to a gas/diesel heater for heating a boat when off the grid. A wood stove was our best low-tech option. We also like that it doubles as a cook top...</p>
<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/woodstove_installation.html'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for March</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/2021.html#mar2021</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>2021.html#mar2021</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of March. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.</p>
<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>
<ul>
    <li><b><a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/uxn.html'>Uxn</a></b>, lots of progress on Uxn, started documenting the <a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/uxntal.html' target='_blank'>assembly syntax</a>, built a <a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/uxnemu.html' target='_blank'>Uxn emulator</a> with a handful of devices, from date/time support, to graphics, mouse, and soon audio and midi support. Rek designed some additional <a href='https://merveilles.town/@neauoire/105874063074976605' target='_blank'>mascots</a> for the project.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/noodle.html' target='_blank'>Noodle</a></b>, implemented <a href='https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=39ixX7Ixvnw' target='_blank'>Noodle into Uxn</a>, with presentation modes, save/load and various patterns to create 1-bit graphics.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co/site/busy_doing_nothing.html' target='_blank'>Busy Doing Nothing</a></b>, fixed type and formatting errors, and removed the fixed font. It is now easier to read on phones.</li> 
    <li><b><a href='https://grimgrains.com' target='_blank'>Grimgrains</a></b>, added a <a href='https://grimgrains.com/site/sourdough_spelt_flatbread.html' target='_blank'>Sourdough spelt flatbread</a> recipe.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/wunderrabbits.html' target='_blank'>Wunderland rabbits</a></b>, released a small photo project involving traveling, and rabbits.</li>
</ul>

<h3>News</h3>

<p>This month, the rabbits have been busy making new holes in Pino, cutting metal, and building a support platform for their new <a href='https://twitter.com/hundredrabbits/status/1372001452898488321' target='_blank'>tiny woodstove</a>. When the installation is complete, we have plans to write a blog post about the process.</p>

<p>If you're seeing this update on the 100r.co website, you'll notice that all logs are now in the <a href='log.html'>same file</a>. It is easier for us to manage, and we think, more pleasant for you to read.</p>

<p>We have received a lot of really good feedback and corrections for our book <a href='https://100r.co/site/busy_doing_nothing.html' target='_blank'>Busy Doing Nothing</a>, thank you for reading it. Rek has updated their notes on <a href='https://kokorobot.ca/site/pandoc.html' target='_blank'>creating e-books with Pandoc</a> to include exports to epub and mobi (for those interested).</p>

<h3>Pino book club</h2>
<p>We're reading <b>The Complete Rigger’s Apprentice</b> by Brion Toss and <b>Thinking Forth</b> by Leo Brody.</p>

<p><b>Pino's location:</b> 48° 42.230'N, 123° 36.900'W</p>
<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/2021.html#mar2021'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for February</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/2021.html#feb2021</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>summary_of_changes_2021_feb</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of February. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.</p>
<h2>Summary Of Changes</h2>
<ul>
    <li><b><a href='https://wiki.xxiivv.com/site/uxn.html'>Uxn</a></b>, started working on a <a href='https://merveilles.town/web/statuses/105795639316214608' target='_blank'>fantasy console</a> called Uxn, and designed a <a href='https://merveilles.town/@neauoire/105658287273107103' target='_blank'>mascot</a>.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://100r.co' target='_blank'>100r.co</a></b>, added a <a href='https://twitter.com/hundredrabbits/status/1360681748770611201' target='_blank'>dark mode</a> as an accessibility feature, and added new drawings to <a href='https://100r.co/site/cooking.html#a_floating_kitchen'>cooking</a> and <a href='https://100r.co/site/sailing.html#slow_and_steady'>sailing</a>.</li> 
    <li><b><a href='https://grimgrains.com' target='_blank'>Grimgrains</a></b>, also added a <a href='https://merveilles.town/@rek/105721363161966256' target='_blank'>dark mode</a>.</li>
    <li><b><a href='https://wiktopher.ca' target='_blank'>Wiktopher</a></b>, what is this? Another <a href='https://merveilles.town/@rek/105732319713413045'>dark mode</a>. Now our eyes are happy.</li>
</ul>
<h2>News</h2>
<p>This month, we released the e-book version of the North Pacific Logbook titled <a href='https://hundredrabbits.itch.io/busy-doing-nothing' target='_blank'>Busy Doing Nothing</a>. The book is 217 pages long, and is available as a PDF, mobi or EPUB. We're happy it's out, and hope that you like it!</p>
<p>In other news, Esoteric.Codes <a href='https://esoteric.codes/blog/100-rabbits' target='_blank'>interviewed</a> our studio, and we heard that the Toronto Public Library was hosting an <a href='https://twitter.com/hundredrabbits/status/1364419919547228162?s=20' target='_blank'>online Orca workshop</a> on March 1st—how cool is that?</p>
<h2>Pino book club</h2>
<p>We're reading <b>A Sand County Almanac</b> by Aldo Leopold.</p>
<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/2021.html#feb2021'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for January</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/2021.html#jan2021</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>summary_of_changes_2021_jan</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of January. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.</p><p><a href='https://100r.co/site/log.html#jan2021.html'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for December</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/2020.html#nov2020</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>summary_of_changes_2020_dec</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of December. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.</p><p><a href='https://100r.co/site/2020.html#nov2020'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for November</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/2020.html#oct2020</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>summary_of_changes_2020_nov</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of November. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.</p><p><a href='https://100r.co/site/2020.html#oct2020'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Summary of changes for October</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/2020.html#sep2020</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>summary_of_changes_2020_oct</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Hey everyone! This is the list of all the changes we've done to our projects and apps during the month of October. We'll also be reporting in our on position in the world, and on our future plans.</p><p><a href='https://100r.co/site/2020.html#sep2020'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Working offgrid efficiently</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/working_offgrid_efficiently.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>working_offgrid_efficiently</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<img src='https://100r.co/media/content/blog/workingefficiently_04.jpg' width='600'/><p>Our traveling studio has operated off-the-grid for 4 1/2 years.</p><p>For the first 3 years we tested the limits of our space, and at first, it was difficult to create new things, as we had to make time to learn how to solve underlying problems. Our boat was not just an office, it was also our house and transport. As for us, we were artists, but also plumbers, deckhands, electricians, captains, janitors and accountants.</p><p>Our main problems as a studio were internet scarcity, power management, data storage as well as hardware and software failures. Overtime we found ways to balance work, pleasure and maintenance. Here are some of the lessons we learnt.</p><p><a href='https://100r.co/site/working_offgrid_efficiently.html'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>North Pacific Logbook</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/north_pacific_logbook.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>north_pacific_logbook</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<img src='https://100r.co/media/content/blog/logbook_01.jpg' width='600'/><p>The passage from <b>Japan</b> (Shimoda) to <b>Canada</b> (Victoria) took <b>51 days</b>, and it was the hardest thing we've ever done. We decided to keep a logbook, to better remember it and so it can help others who wish to make this trip.</p><p><a href='https://100r.co/site/north_pacific_logbook.html'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Typhoons and mold</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/typhoons_and_mold.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>typhoons_and_mold</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<img src='https://100r.co/media/content/travel/typhoons_12.jpg' width='600'/><p>For every traveling sailor, comes a time when the boat has to stay alone in a foreign country. For us, this happened this year in <a href='https://100r.co/site/sailing_in_japan.html'>Japan</a>. We'd never left <a href='https://100r.co/site/pino.html'>Pino</a> alone before, never for more than a week. We were apprehensive at first, but decided it would be a good learning experience, for us and our beloved.</p><p>Whenever we mentioned leaving our boat in Japan, people would say, 'Aren't you afraid of typhoons?' Our 6 month leave coincided with the time of year when typhoons affect Japan, with August to October being the worse months. We were worried, but knew that if we prepared well, Pino would be fine. We spent weeks planning our departure, doing research on how to keep a boat safe in a storm, but also, how to keep mold and insects at bay in our absence.</p><p>While in Canada, I had anxiety at night, vivid dreams about what was happening to Pino. These dreams involved us returning to the boat, only to find it turned into a moldy, water-logged cockroach motel. Having no experience leaving our home behind, I had no guarantee that we had done enough.</p><p>When we returned 6 months later, we found no mold, no bugs and little to no damage, in fact, we slept in that same night. Pino endured weeks of hot Japanese summers, tropical rain and typhoon-strength winds. We're happy to say that overall, our preparations were indeed enough.</p><p>Below is a short list of things to remember, things we learned, when came time to prepare our boat for long-term storage:</p><ul class='bullet'><li>Ventilation is key.</li><li>Clear the decks.</li><li>Don't keep food.</li><li>Clean everything.</li><li>Store away everything.</li><li>Don't leave openings.</li><li>Tie everything down.</li></ul><p><a href='https://100r.co/site/typhoons_and_mold.html'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>a home for pino</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/a_home_for_pino.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>a_home_for_pino</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>We left Shimizu on a sunny morning, pushing off the dock at 6am. Early. We wanted to make sure we'd arrive at our destination on time. There was 126nm between us and Shima Yacht harbor, a distance we needed to do in part at night. This wasn't ideal. We knew that. Many people warned us about sailing at night in these waters, but as the Japanese say: 'Shoganai' (it is what it is!). We needed to cross a big stretch of water called Enshu Nada, an area with a lot of traffic. In truth, the entire coastline is full of ships, but it gets very busy north of the Kii Peninsula.</p><p>We left Shimizu on a sunny morning, pushing off the dock at 6am. We discussed our plans with our friends Masa and Shu from Dawntreader, they too recommended a non-stop trip because the ports between Omaezaki and Mie are few. There is the port of Fukuda 福田, located at the mouth of Ota Kawa, but the depth of the water is  inconsistent and prone to silting. Locals also warned us it wasn't very yacht-friendly, and so we put an X on Fukuda.</p><p>Shu instructed us to stay 10nm from shore, to avoid the many nets lining the coast, and to avoid small fishing vessels idling there at night. We did as told.</p><p>Coming out of Shimizu port, we came face to face with a large container ship named 'One'. A beautiful ship. Red, with a peculiar shape. The marina had warned us about its coming, that its entrance into Shimizu port was scheduled at 6am during our exit. Avoiding it was not a problem.</p><p>We powered out of the harbor and into Suruga Bay. There was no wind, but we raised the mainsail anyway. We wanted to test our new slugs (what keeps the mainsail attached to the mast). It was the first time since Fiji that we'd raised a full main. The black moon shook off its wrinkles, presenting its belly to the sun.</p><p><a href='https://100r.co/site/a_home_for_pino.html'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>tools ecosystem</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/tools_ecosystem.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>tools_ecosystem</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>How did the Hundredrabbits ecosystem come into being? It's a long story, but here's a summary.</p><p>In 2016, we left Canada, armed with our two iPhones and 2 MacBooks Pros. We didn't know the wattage of any of the devices we owned,  and even less about the amount of solar needed to power them. When living on land we didn't pay attention to how many amps our devices required daily. Electricity felt limitless.</p><p>When we started sailing in BC, we had no dinghy and so we'd go from dock to dock. When we purchased Iggy in Nanaimo, we spent more days on the hook. The first anchorage we went to was a small bight east of Eagle Point, it offered a great view of metro Vancouver. From that point on we spent more and more time at anchor, moving every 5 days or so. We had no power concerns because our route always included marinas, or guest slips at yacht clubs. Our batteries were always topped up.</p><p>Life off-grid was new to us then, as was spending lots of time outdoors. We liked it, a lot. When at anchor we'd go explore, spend a few hours working, cooking, then we'd read or play card games in evenings. When living on land, we'd work from 8h-19h, sitting in front of our respective screens, but now things were different. We wanted to do less of that, to take long bike ride around islands or to sit on the deck in evenings to watch the sun set. Then, at marinas where we had both power and  internet, we'd go back to working longer hours to get things done. This was a fine setup, we thought, but, there was problem: what happens when we start living AND working at anchor full time? We liked being outdoors, but that's not all we wanted to do. We're creatives, and we need to make things. We were relying on powered docks to work, and so we never got to test our current power setup off-grid. If we had spent a month or so away from  civilization, we would have learnt that we had to change something.</p><p>And so, to continue with the story, we left Canada and cruised down the coast of the US. True to our old habits, we continued to alternate between staying in a marina and at anchor. The longest we spent off-grid during that time was 3 weeks in San Francisco, anchored off Treasure Island. During that time we discovered that working aboard, running two Macbook Pros, a refrigerator and our phones was not possible. To save on power, we started turning the fridge off at night, and taking trips into town during the day to work from cafes. SF was grey on most days, our solar couldn't keep up with our demanding work schedules. Going to work from cafes in town worked well for us, most had outlets we could use. Our routine started with working from cafes until lunch, then wandering around in the afternoons. We would return home before dark to turn the fridge off, but doing it didn't make sense because the constant shifts in temperatures produced too much moisture. Moisture meant rot and mold. We decided that keeping it off was a better idea for both our batteries and our produce. With the fridge out of the equation, we figured that we'd have more power left-over for our laptops.</p><p><a href='https://100r.co/site/tools_ecosystem.html'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>hello fujisan</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/hello_fujisan.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>hello_fujisan</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>It's 8h00 pm on a cold dark winter night, we are outside of Shimizu harbor motoring in circles and waiting for a response from Shimizu Port Control. The temperature is 4 °C, the wind is blowing hard and our clothes are wet and caked with salt. We’re tired and hungry, waiting for permission to enter the Port. Prior to this, we had a rough 4-day passage, riding under 30-40 knot winds on the nose. This passage was a true test of strength, for us and for Pino... but first, let’s go back and see exactly what happened…</p><p>We'd planned to go to Wakayama, riding on the back of a passing low with winds from the NE, shifting to the S and then to the SW, but the wind decided to turn earlier making it impossible for us to go east. We found ourselves close-reaching in 40 knot winds, heading straight north. Looking at the weather we could see that it would blow from the W for 3-4 days, so we made a new plan to head to Omaezaki. We'd read of other sailors taking refuge there in big weather and thought it would be possible to go, but again, the wind kept pushing us further and further east. The next port on our list was Shimizu, tucked in deep into the bay. We were able to point Pino to the cape just past Shimizu, but we weren't sure if again the wind and current would allow us to make some easting.</p><p>At that point both of us were frozen solid. Wave after wave splashed over the boat and into the cockpit. The starboard rail was constantly submerged, our starboard side lee cloth was gone and the diesel bins were threatening to fall overboard. We had 3 reefs in our main, but 5 slides had snapped off (yet again), I wondered when the rest would break.</p><p><a href='https://100r.co/site/hello_fujisan.html'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>goji no chaimu</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/goji_no_chaimu.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>goji_no_chaimu</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>After a long 21-day passage, seeing the shape of the island of Chichijima in the distance was unreal; this was our prize, our first step onto Japanese soil. We used to make many trips to Japan by plane, but getting there by our own efforts — by sailboat — is a lot slower and harder. If we had stuck to our plan of sailing there via Hawaii, we would have been there sooner, but I’m glad we took the long route. We passed through 9 countries, learned a lot about the world and, through it all, we've surpassed ourselves.</p><p>During that time, we often talked about what it would be like to arrive in Japan, about what would happen when we did. You have to remember that this was a big deal for us, a milestone in our lives and the culmination of 3 years of hard work. A fantasy made real is a hell of an achievement. A part of me couldn’t believe we’d made it — anytime now I’d wake up mid-ocean in transit in the South Pacific. Even when I’d have my feet planted on the ground, with a Japanese flag flying above my head, I knew I’d be anxious, waiting for something horrible to happen that would rob us of our victory.</p><p>'They’ll turn us away.', 'We’ve landed on the wrong island.' or 'We died in the pacific some months ago, and this is limbo.'</p><p>My eyes were set on the phantasmic island ahead. The sun fell out of the sky then, drawing down a star-studded curtain; the wind blew itself out, leaving the sea to settle into an unmoving and creepy oil slick. <b>Limbo.</b></p><p>A bright circle appeared on the horizon then. It isn’t the first or the last time that I mistake the moonrise for a ship, or the bright eye of some mythological beast.</p><p>At this point, it looked like we’d be entering Futami port at night, but at least we had the eye of Sauron to light the way. The island in the distance stopped being a vague black patch, and we began to see details in it.<p><a href='https://100r.co/site/goji_no_chaimu.html'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>the promise of pancakes</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/the_promise_of_pancakes.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>the_promise_of_pancakes</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>As soon as we'd tied to our mooring ball in Majuro's lagoon, the worries of the previous 24 days had vanished only to replaced by the crushing weight of responsibility. Devine, being worry-free, wanted to have pancakes, sleep and check-in tomorrow, but Devine knows how uptight I am, and that this was not what we'd be doing first (even if it is what I wanted too *sigh*). My thinking was that I'd rather get the paperwork out of the way first, to get all of that worrying out of me so I can then eat pancakes in peace.</p><ul><li>'Shut up and get dressed.'</li></ul><p>We needed to be presentable for the officials, we had to wear clean clothes with pants that reach over your knees. A lot of countries in the pacific don't want to see your knees — I get it, knees are weird. We dug out some clothes from our bins, and then went back on deck to give Iggy the dinghy the kiss of life.</p><p><a href='https://100r.co/site/the_promise_of_pancakes.html'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>doldrumming</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/doldrumming.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>doldrumming</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Here we go again, time for another passage. We left Fiji on <b>October 23rd 2018</b>, eager to spend some time on the water again. Our plan, was to stop by Tuvalu, maybe Kiribati, before arriving in Majuro in the Marshall islands where we'd be spending two months before moving off west to Micronesia. We left, knowing that this was wasn't going to be an easy ride...</p><p>Two areas of calms lie north of Fiji: the SPCZ (south pacific convergence zone) and the ITCZ (intertropical convergence zone). If you look at <a href='http://windy.com' target='_blank' class='external'>windy</a>, hovering around the countries of <b>Tuvalu</b> and <b>Kiribati</b> are two bands of blue - blue means there is no wind. The size and location of these bands varies from day to day, week to week.. they phase in and out of existence with the weather and influence of the trade winds.</p><p>Sailors fear these blue bands because the weather there is difficult, not only do you suffer calms, but also a continuous ballet of squalls and thunderstorms. We've been through the doldrums (the ITCZ) once already when we crossed from Mexico to the Marquesas.</p><p><a href='https://100r.co/site/doldrumming.html'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>leleuvia</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/leleuvia.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>leleuvia</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>We've never been on a tiny island, a place you can run the width of under just a few minutes. We found a place like this, <b>Leleuvia</b>, an island in the Lomaitivi archipelago in Fiji.</p><p>This island went through many hands over the years, it now belongs to a resort that too bears the name of the island. We decided to make a stop there on our way to Suva, to wait for favorable winds to go south.</p><p>Also, we wanted a taste of tiny-island living.</p><p>We arrived at <b>Moturiki pass</b> around 1pm. SY Scoots gave us a number to phone the resort on arrival, so they could send a boat to guide us through the reef. We realized then, that our phone plan didn't include calls within Fiji, all we had was data — woops! That's ok! We still had the option of calling them on VHF. I hailed them repeatedly on CH10 — no luck.</p><p>I had waypoints for the entrance, but not all the way to the anchorage. Many areas in Fiji aren't charted well, you can find yourself navigating over an area with the depth sounder reading '10m' but the chart will display a patch of green, an area too shallow to pass. It's always disconcerting, to find yourself anchored in a patch of green, like sitting in a negative space, a secret place that you didn't think existed.</p><p>We got closer and closer to the green area, growing ever-so nervous, and continuing to try and hail the resort. Eventually, they picked up my call.</p><ul><li>'Vessel calling, this is Leleuvia resort.'</li><li>'This is sailing vessel Pino, d'you have any moorings available?'</li><li>'Yes. When you come near the pier we'll send a boat to escort you to it.'</li><li>'Great, thanks!'</li></ul><p>We wouldn't be entering the anchorage in the blind after all. We would have eyes to guide us to a safe spot.</p><p>We motored on, nearing the pier, and spotted the escort boat. The driver came within shouting range, instructing us to follow, which we promptly did. They led us to a mooring, and assured us it was strong and that it could take our weight — not that Pino is heavy. We grabbed the line from the water, with a bit of difficulty, sometimes the mooring 'eye' for the buoys are submerged, and you need to figure out which bit to grab to get to it. We missed the mooring ball the first time, the whole endeavour was made worse by the up and down motion of the bow — there was a bit of swell coming into the anchorage from the north at the time. We rounded again to grab the mooring ball, i spied a thin loop at the top of the ball, and thrusted the boat hook in it. I hurriedly pulled the float out of the water, and my hands and the line found the mooring loop. This is not my favorite type of mooring ball, where you need to pull the ball up itself to find the rope hanging far underneath it, usually they'll put a separate float on the line to keep it buoyant. All moorings are different.</p><p>The northerly swell would stop soon, the forecast called for 20-25kts out of the SE tomorrow. On the chart, the area looked protected from swell, with a reef belt around it, but looking around now, aside from the tiny spit of land that is Leleuvia, there was only water. At low tide the reef became evident, as the water receded sand banks came into view, fencing us in from all directions but from the North. Phew. The reef would break most of the waves, but at high tide some swell would make it past it for sure — not ideal, but we would have some protection.</p><p>The next day the wind did freshen, and as expected, at high tide the waves spilled into the anchorage. It was bumpy, but not overly so.</p><p><a href='https://100r.co/site/leleuvia.html'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>where is the turtle farm</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/where_is_the_turtle_farm.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>where_is_the_turtle_farm</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Pino spent a long time in <b>Savusavu</b>, but by then, we were growing tired of this scenery, not of the market, or of the company to be found here, but just of having that same view every morning. We love this city, but when it's time to go, it's time to go!</p><p>We left our mooring at 9am, and moved along over to <b>Cousteau's resort</b> to anchor (16 48.623S, 179 17.331E). The water was unclear, and the clouded sky made it difficult to see bommies beneath us. Devine dove in and checked out our anchor, which was set in sand, and we weren't near any huge coral that we could see, that is, unless the wind shifted - it was hard to see that far in cloudy water to be honest.</p><p>SV Privateer arrived shortly after us, having made the short passage by sail, we saw them manoeuver around, looking for a place to drop the hook.</p><ul><li>'What's the bottom like?' Lila shouted, baby Chance strapped to her back.</li><li>'Sand. A few bommies!' I shouted back.</li></ul><p>They hovered around some more, opening the headsail, furling it, in and out again, and moving the main in and out to make their way around the anchorage. It's always impressive to watch, not many will rely on wings alone to do this. They'll do as many tacks as necessary to get where they need to go - engines be damned!</p><p>We tried swimming at the beach that afternoon, but it was full of seaweed and unclear, we much preferred staying on the tiny slab of beach lining the shore to watch the hundreds of tiny hermit crabs moving about. They were different sizes, wearing a grand variety of shells - some spirally, others conical, stained with purples and whites, oranges and cream. We sat there in silence, listening to the sound of their shells rubbing against bits of broken coral. Such a pleasant sound, small scratching noises. Crkk, crkk... crkk.</p><ul><li>'Move along little ones - move along now! Tide's rising!'</li></ul><p>We left our hermit crab friends behind, and went back aboard Pino. Tomorrow morning we had to get up at 4am to sail to Makogai (pronounced ma-kon-guy), 49NM away.</p><p>The wind changed in the night, we could hear the chain rubbing against bit of coral, catching, before coming off again with a jerk, the sound traveling to us by the chain through the hull. We should have probably buoyed the chain, we thought then, but it was dark, and too late to think of doing this now. Hopefully, the chain wouldn't have this macramé thing going on with the bits of coral down there.</p><p><a href='https://100r.co/site/where_is_the_turtle_farm.html'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>projects and pain</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/projects_and_pain.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>projects_and_pain</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>We arrived in New Zealand with a long scary list of things to fix or replace on Pino. We needed new batteries, a new mainsail, a fresh coat of bottom-paint, galley plumbing, new intermediates shrouds, new backstay, new top hatch, new windows, new control cables etc.</p><ul><li>'If we can't finish all of these projects, then we can't leave.'</li></ul><p>That was the deal. There was too much ocean between us and Japan. Our vessel needed to be made safe to endure it, and to ensure our safe passage.</p><p>When we landed in the country, we had grand ideas, 'grand illusions' I should say, about what we thought we could get done by ourselves. We wanted to learn, but we also wanted to save money. By now, we knew how much it cost to offload the work to others, and it's not something we knew we could do.</p><p>Below, is a detailed account of all the repairs we did on Pino during the 9 months we spent in New Zealand. This is a technical post, interspersed with bits of story, present and past. For those who don't know the terms, but that are interested, I'll do my best to explain them all throughout the text.</p><p>Here I go!</p><p><a href='https://100r.co/site/projects_and_pain.html'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>an island to oneself</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/an_island_to_oneself.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>an_island_to_oneself</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>Traveling to <b>New Zealand</b>, after a year of unknown, was a great comfort to us. There are a few things Devine and I were really looking forward to, like a good latte, craft beer, a fresh food market and a bulk food store. I found a city that checked all of the boxes.</p><p>Many of the cruisers we know want to arrive in <b>Opua</b> – with reason. It's warm, damn gorgeous, and you know you'll find friends there, because that's where everyone goes during the cyclone season. Arriving in a strange place, with familiar faces, always makes the experience better, but knowing this, we still chose <b>Whangarei</b>.</p><p>I first pronounced Whangarei as 'one-gah-rey', but the proper way to say it is: 'fah-ngah-rey'. A friend corrected me early on, sparing me the embarrassment of mispronouncing it aloud in public. I know that no one would think me a fool for making a mistake like this, but I do like learning the correct way to say things.</p><p>Why did we choose to go there? Because staying in the Whangarei Town Basin is inexpensive, convenient, with everything just a short walk away. We'd also read that it was a good place for boat projects, and since Pino needed a lot of attention, this too, we thought, tipped the scale in its favor. We also noted that it was close to <b>Auckland</b> — well, it looked closer on a map. We became very familiar with that stretch of land, and of the actual distance between the two places during the 8 months we spent there.</p><p>The first thing we did when we arrived, was to replenish our store of dried goods at Bin Inn, a really great bulk food store. The second thing, was purchasing a home brew kit - priorities amirite? The third thing, was to get a latte.</p><p>I'll never forget the look on Devine's face after taking a sip of a cup of freshly brewed beans, a delicious pool of dark liquid topped with a pillowy cloud of plant milk.</p><p>Joy incarnate.</p><p><a href='https://100r.co/site/an_island_to_oneself.html'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>captain what is this</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/captain_what_is_this.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>captain_what_is_this</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p>After 15 days on the water, we were to get into port. It was the 27th of June, and we'd left Opua on the 12th. We hove-to for the night, waiting for sunrise before entering Savusavu bay. 'Entering a strange harbor at night is for morons and fools,' people told us. We didn't listen right away, but they were right. In this particular case, there was no point in arriving early, considering yachts cannot anchor in Fiji waters before checking in, and that check-in is only possible after 8am.</p><p>At dawn, we pointed towards the island of Vanua Levu and sailed on, with the wind at our backs. I went below to make some coffee, as both of us needed a boost. Devine was in the cockpit, keeping an eye on a large storm cloud ahead. The wind increased as we neared it, but it did not trouble us long. We made our way inside the reef, which offered some protection from the building swells, and moved closer to land. We could see rows of hills ahead, and caught the perfume of greenery. After that, came a sure sign of civilization: buildings, low, with green and red roofs. As we got nearer, came an even more obvious sign of civilization: cars, and small power boats. We'd arrived.</p><p>We neared the entrance to Nakama creek around 9am, and radio'ed the authorities on channel 16.</p><p>I hailed them 3 times, no answer. We slowed down, awaiting a reply. The commercial wharf lay ahead, we could see boats on moorings, some abandoned, others belonging to people we'd seen or met accross the Pacific. Eventually, they replied and asked us about the details of our trip, and if we had sent a pre-arrival notice. Sending it ahead of time was mandatory, and was about 10 pages too long. I'd sent it to the proper people by email, although half of the messages bounced back, and other cruisers reported the same thing happening. With the document being so large, it's no wonder their inboxes are always full. I even tried sending it again while underway, no luck. No matter. I'd received a reply from the custom office, at least one of the messages made it. They told us to look for a white building on our starboard side.</p><p><a href='https://100r.co/site/captain_what_is_this.html'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>the rock of polynesia</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/the_rock_of_polynesia.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>the_rock_of_polynesia</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p><b>Niue</b>, pronounced 'New-ay', a rock in the Pacific, one of the largest coral islands on earth. It's the first country to offer free, state-funded, wireless internet to all its residents and has a goal of being completely solar powered— uuuh... wow?</p><p>We'd also heard that the school gave all of the kids laptops, this, with free internet, makes it a paradise for people like us. Already then, we made plans to move there — like all places in the tropics with a good connection and supply of coconuts and beer. I remember when we were speaking of staying in <b>Nuku Hiva</b> too, and in La Paz. We make a home everywhere we go. This, makes it hard to leave, but this ease of adaptation also makes us eager to go forward, to see where else we could live. This is what we do, we set up house in different places, sometimes for 8 months at a time.</p><p>We weren't going to be staying long in Niue though, but not by choice.</p><p>Alofi Bay, the only anchorage on the island, is not protected in any wind other than east. If the wind turns in an unfavorable direction, staying could be dangerous and we'd be forced to leave.</p><p>One other troublesome thing about the 'rock of Polynesia', is that they hiked the departure fees from 35$ to 80$ per person. Anyone who enters Niue, when leaving, need pay this fee. That's a lot of money, we thought, to visit a place so small.</p><p>In the end I'm glad we went, because of all the places we'd been, Niue was our favorite.</p><p>We arrived at 6am in the morning, rounding the island to Alofi bay that lay on the west side. A squall lay between me and the anchorage, a puffy cloud with a thick wet skirt. I pulled my hood on, grabbed the helm firmly and quickly skipped through songs on my phone till I landed on anything by Purity ring. Ah! Sea castles. Yes, perfect.</p><p>WOOSH! A gust of wind comes, but I'm ready. The song begins then too... <i>'I could build a machine—'</i> The boat heels, <i>'—draw pictures for the walls.'</i> Then comes the rain, heavy droplets, washing the salt crystals away. It left as quickly as it came, giving way to the sun, its face reflected in a thousand wet pools on the deck. <i>'Hang up all my fragile frights—'</i> I point Pino towards the anchorage. Tall masts ahead, signs of life. The water, a deep blue, spotted with brightly-colored floaters. <i>'—Display that you may see.'</i> I sing aloud, turning the music off. 'We're here!' I shout to Devine.</p><p><a href='https://100r.co/site/the_rock_of_polynesia.html'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>internet in paradise</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/internet_in_paradise.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>internet_in_paradise</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p><b>Huahine</b>, one of the many grouped islands in French Polynesia. Our plans for future ocean voyaging could have ended here, because we almost crashed onto a reef.</p><p>Because we always time our arrival with the morning sun, I always get the first look of every island. Huahine stood in front of us, a series of volcanic peaks marked by deep valleys and blanketed in green, an island that came into being million of years ago.</p><p>We were heading for Baie d'Avea, to the south of the island.</p><p><a href='https://100r.co/site/internet_in_paradise.html'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
  </description>
</item>
<item>
  <title>rainy with a chance of mosquitoes</title>
  <link>https://100r.co/site/rainy_with_a_chance_of_mosquitoes.html</link>
  <guid isPermaLink='false'>rainy_with_a_chance_of_mosquitoes</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rek Bell]]></dc:creator>
  <description>
<![CDATA[<p><b>Nuku Hiva</b>, a green mountainous island in the Pacific, straight out of Jurassic Park. Just as foreign and just as wild, except instead of hungry lizards there are mosquitoes, also known as the vampires of the Marquesas.</p><p>Before arriving, we didn't know what it was going to be like there, we'd barely read anything about it. We knew where we'd anchor, that people there spoke french and that there would be tropical fruit, but beyond that it was a blur, a black spot in our minds. We read the book <b>Fourteen</b> during our 28-day transit from La Paz. In this book, the family sailed to Nuku Hiva, but their experience there was not so good. It wasn't bad because of the Marquesans, or the island itself, but because of no-no's, little biting bugs that hide in sand. We took a mental note of this: "Avoid sand beaches, and you will have a great time!"</p><p>On day 27 of our voyage, I could see the outline of the island in the distance. I stood at the bow, trying to take footage of the event, but was disappointed with the shot. Far-away wonders have a way of looking unimpressive on camera. I was about to put the camera away, when I heard a 'wooshing' sound. I looked over the side, and saw an orca whale swimming next to Pino, its length matching our own. It stayed with us for a long while, it's white belly making it easy to spot it in the water. This unusual encounter was a great start to our Marquesian adventure.</p><p>Pino arrived at the entrance to Taiohae bay. I sat on the bow with Iggy's deflated corpse. I pumped life back into it, while it, sucked mine out. I was sweaty, a constant stream of body water oozing down my back. We had no dinghy pump, having broken it ages ago. All we had was a jury-rigged contraption using a bike pump, a bike tube and the hose from the old pump. It worked, but it took twice as long to put air into anything.</p><p>A super yacht was anchored in the mouth of the bay, called 'Ethereal'. "How fitting", I thought.</p><p>It's as if the yacht was a sign, a warning of the view to come — one, that was definitely ethereal.</p><p>A chain of mountains, green and fuzzy, and ahead a bay filled with boats flying flags from all over the world. We found a spot in 12 m of water, mud bottom, and dropped anchor. The sky was clear, but clouds clung to the peaks of every mountain. It was a rare thing, we realized afterwards, for the skies to be clear. Most days were grey. While grey often means rain, it also means less sun. It was over 30 degrees every day, so hot that at times we couldn't work, our bodies shiny with sweat, driving us mad. Mad to the point that we seriously considered flooding the cockpit with water to turn it into a pool.</p><p><a href='https://100r.co/site/rainy_with_a_chance_of_mosquitoes.html'>Continue Reading</a></p>]]>
  </description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>