<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">

<channel>
  <title>Hundred Rabbits — Journal</title>
  <link><![CDATA[https://100r.co/blog]]></link>
  <description>The Rabbits'Journal</description>
  <generator>Oscean - Riven</generator>
  
  <item>
    <title>The rock of polynesia</title>
    <link>https://100r.co/blog.html</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink='false'>IV0</guid>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
    <description>
      &lt;img src="media/blog/niue1.jpg"&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;&lt;b&gt;Niue&lt;/b&gt;, pronounced 'New-ay', a rock in the pacific, one of the largest coral islands on earth. It's the first country to offer free, state-funded, wireless internet to all its residents and has a goal of being completely &lt;a href='https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Niue' class='external' target='_blank'&gt;solar powered&lt;/a&gt; - uh. Wow?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;We'd also heard that the school gave all of the kids laptops, this, with free internet, makes it a paradise for game devs. Already then, we made plans to move there, like all places in the tropics with a good connection and supply of coconut and beer. I remember when we were speaking of staying in &lt;a class='local' href='#nuku+hiva' title='Nuku Hiva' onclick="app.load('Nuku Hiva')"&gt;Nuku Hiva&lt;/a&gt; too, and in La Paz. We make a home everywhere we go. This, makes it hard to leave, but this ease of adaptation also makes us eager to go forward, to see where else we could live. This is what we do, we set up house in different places, sometimes for 8 months at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://100r.co/blog.html'&gt;Continue Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    </description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>Rainy with a chance of mosquitoes</title>
    <link>https://100r.co/blog.html</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink='false'>IV1</guid>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
    <description>
      &lt;img src="media/blog/nukuhiva1.jpg"&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;&lt;b&gt;Nuku Hiva&lt;/b&gt;, a green island in the pacific, straight out of Jurassic Park, just as foreign and just as wild, except instead of hungry lizards there are hungry, angry mosquitoes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;I had no idea what it was going to be like there, I'd barely read anything about it. I knew where we'd anchor, that people spoke french and that there would be baguettes, but beyond that it was a blur, a black spot in my mind. I read the book &lt;b&gt;Fourteen&lt;/b&gt; during our 28-day transit from La Paz. In this book, the family had sailed to Nuku Hiva, but all in all their experience there was not so good. It wasn't made bad because of the Marquesans, or the island itself, but because of no-no's – little bugs that bite that hide in sand. I took a mental note of this:&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://100r.co/blog.html'&gt;Continue Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    </description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>Captain, what is this?</title>
    <link>https://100r.co/blog.html</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink='false'>IV2</guid>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
    <description>
      &lt;img src="media/blog/savusavu3.jpg"&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;After 15 days on the water, you can imagine how eager we were to get into port. It was the 27th of June, we left on the 12th from Opua. We hove-to for the night, waiting for sunrise before entering &lt;a href='https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Savusavu' class='external' target='_blank'&gt;Savusavu bay&lt;/a&gt;. After repeated mistakes, we learned that entering a strange harbour in the dark is most unwise. There is no point in arriving early, considering yachts cannot anchor in Fiji waters before checking in, and check-in is only possible after 8am.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;At dawn, we pointed towards Vanua Levu and started sailing again, the wind at our backs. I went below to make some coffee, both of us needed a boost. Devine was in the cockpit, keeping a wary eye on a large storm cloud ahead. The wind increased as we neared it, but it did not trouble us long. We made our way inside the reef, which offered some protection from the building swells. Now closer to land, we could see rows of hills ahead, and caught the perfume of greenery with it. After that, came a sure sign of civilization: buildings, low, with green and red roofs. As we got nearer, came an even more obvious marker of civilization: cars, and small power boats. We'd arrived.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://100r.co/blog.html'&gt;Continue Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    </description>
  </item>

</channel>

</rss>