<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">

<channel>
  <title>Hundred Rabbits — Journal</title>
  <link><![CDATA[https://100r.co/blog]]></link>
  <description>The Rabbits'Journal</description>
  <generator>Oscean - Riven</generator>
  
  <item>
    <title>Rainy with a chance of mosquitoes</title>
    <link>https://100r.co/blog.html</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink='false'>IV0</guid>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[&lt;img src='media/blog/nukuhiva1.jpg'/&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;Nuku Hiva, a green island in the pacific, straight out of Jurassic Park, just as foreign and just as wild, except instead of hungry lizards there are hungry, angry mosquitoes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;I had no idea what it was going to be like there, I'd barely read anything about it. I knew where we'd anchor, that people spoke french and that there would be baguettes, but beyond that it was a blur, a black spot in my mind. I read the book "Fourteen" during our 28-day transit from La Paz. In this book, the family had sailed to Nuku Hiva, but all in all their experience there was not so good. It wasn't made bad because of the Marquesans, or the island itself, but because of no-no's – little bugs that bite that hide in sand. I took a mental note of this:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;"Avoid sand beaches and you will have a great time!"&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;We arrived at the entrance to Taioha'e bay. I sat on the bow with Iggy's deflated corpse, I pumped life back into it, while it, seemed to draw the very life out of me. I was sweating, a constant stream sliding down my back. We had no dinghy pump, no, we broke ours ages ago. All we had was a jury-rigged contraption using a bike pump, a bike tube and the hose from the old pump. It worked, but it took twice as long to put air into anything.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;A super yatch was anchored in the mouth of the bay, its name was 'Ethereal'.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;list class=''&gt;&lt;ln class=''&gt;"How fitting." I thought.&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;/list&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;It's as if the yatch was a sign, a warning of the view to come – one, that is definitely ethereal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;A chain of mountains, green and fuzzy, and ahead a bay filled with boats flying flags from all over the world. We found a spot in 12m of water, mud bottom, and dropped anchor. The sky was clear, but clouds clung to the peaks of every mountain. It was a rare thing, we realized afterwards, for the skies to be clear. Most days were grey. While grey often means rain, it also means less sun. It was over 30 degrees every day, so hot that at times we couldn't work, our bodies shiny with sweat, driving us mad. Mad to the point that we seriously considered flooding the cockpit with water to turn it into a pool.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src='media/blog/nukuhiva4.jpg'/&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;Everyday, we'd get up with the sun. The mornings were cooler, but around 10am, when it was too warm in the boat we went ashore to work from the snack bar. Snack Vaeki was an open-air restaurant with seating outside, the kitcken was in a tiny building with a counter. There were with many tables, occupied by locals but most of all by boaters. There was free internet there, but getting something to drink or to eat was encouraged. We would always get the same thing, a freshly squeezed glass of pamplemousse juice. Pamplemousse is nothing like the grapefruit we have in Canada, they're 3 times as big, green inside and out, and sweet-tasting. The seating area was covered with a plastic canopy, euro-style outlets hung on every post, sharing the space with stalks of bananas. Many animals would hang around the snack bar, dogs lay under the tables, hiding from the sun, but these did little to shield them from the constant onslaught of flies. There were also chickens, lot of chickens and roosters. I thought roosters only crowed in the morning, but no, they crow for no reason, at all hours of the day, endless b'gawking and cluck-clucking. We'd also seen horses walk around, but they didn't care to hang around the pier and much preferred nibbling on bits of tall grass further inland.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;We sat at the Snack everyday, catching a bit of internet before everyone else would come ashore to use it. Uploading anything was a challenge. We found an internet lounge in the village, a small building with walls covered in popular (but old) xbox and playstation titles. There were tables, with a few old computers, televisions and consoles. Kids sat playing games, while 3 giant fans helped to cool the place down. The owner was friendly, we got along well enough, so much that he let us leave our laptop there overnight to get a big file online. It took 3 days to upload a 10 minute video, and this is with, apparently, the fastest internet on the island. Many locals would come to the internet place to ask for movies, or series. Even all the way out here, people follow game of thrones, the walking dead, or other popular media.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src='media/blog/nukuhiva2.jpg'/&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;Even if it was really hot, we didn't swim here. It rained everyday, and the run-off from the mountain made the water brown and unclear. It wasn't inviting. And not just this, the first day when we took the dinghy ashore, we noticed a lot of angry splish-splashing near the concrete pier, then our eyes moved to someone, tossing bits of something pinkish into the water...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;Then I saw fins.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;And tails.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;Sharks. Many sharks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;While I think them wonderful, my monkey brain still fears teeth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;Devine and I gulped. We cared little to swim after that, even after seeing kids leaping off that same pier for a swim a few hours later.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;list class=''&gt;&lt;ln class=''&gt;"We led sheltered lives haven't we?"&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;/list&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;Devine said, wide-eyed still.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;These kids were fearless. They made a game of it, just like they made a game of swimming where the waves break on the shore. The island doesn't have a reef, so when the tide and wind-driven waves come in, the water races to shore, unhindered, and explodes onto the sea wall with a cloud CLAP! There was no beach there, at low-tide the bottom was just mud and rocks, mostly rocks, polished after years of being caressed by the sea. The waves hitting the wall were considerable, even so, the kids took to the sea! They grabbed street signs, bits of wood, whatever they could find that could be used as a body-board, then they'd sit in the water, waiting for the waves to come. The waves always did come, and buried them all in an instant. The kids laughed, they'd played this game a hundred times.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;We were impressed, and again, felt we'd led very sheltered lives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;The people in Nuku Hiva are exceptionally nice. Because we could speak french, we had an edge over those who couldn't, it was easier to befriend locals, a lot of them even recognized our accent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;list class=''&gt;&lt;ln class=''&gt;"You're from Quebec!"&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;/list&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;They would say in french.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;list class=''&gt;&lt;ln class=''&gt;"Yea, from Montreal!"&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;ln class=''&gt;"I love the the accent!"&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;ln class=''&gt;"Poutine. Bobette. Tabarnak."&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;/list&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;While the locals speak French, they also speak Marquesan, a language of many vowels. When first seeing it written down, I remembered a song in 'national lampoon's christmas vacation', the scene when Clark imagines a woman on a diveboard, about to dive in his imaginary pool. A song is playing in the background, it goes: "Mele kalikimaka."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;It was very similar to the writing I'd seen in the village. I wondered then, is Hawaiian that different from Marquesan? The two sets of islands are so close! After much reading, I found out that both fall under central eastern polynesian, which is sub-divided into Marquesic – encompassing Marquesan AND Hawaiian – and Tahitic. All Polynesian languages show strong similarity, particularly in vocabulary. 'Mele kalikimaka' is Hawaiian, and means 'merry christmas', or at least that's what the song says it means. I learned then, that the only central eastern polynesian words I knew were actually the Hawaiian equivalent of katakana in Japanese. The polynesians had no notion of religion or christmas, that is, until the missionaries arrived. Because the word didn't exist, Hawaiians opted for a phonetic translation of merry christmas instead of making a new word for it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;But now, I was down to knowing no Polynesian at all, Hawaiian or Marquesan, but that changed quickly enough. When walking down the street, people smiled at us and said:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;list class=''&gt;&lt;ln class=''&gt;"La Orana!"&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;/list&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;Which we promptly repeated, and which means "Hello!". This word is similar in all central eastern polynesian countries:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;French polynesia - La orana! (yo-rah-nah)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;Cook islands - Kia orana!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;New Zealand - Kia ora!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;We did mix these up on occasion, we always counted on the fact that they'd assumed we said the correct thing. In doubt, you could say the words quickly, under your breath, no one would know, or if they did, they were too damn polite to say anything about it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;Marquesans are really keen on tattoos, a lot of people had them, and were very pleased to see ours! A lot of foreigners come here to get tattoos, including an old salt we met, the captain of a 70-foot steel boat. If you asked him about tattoos, he would tell you, in a broken english accent, that he cared little for them. Don't ask me how, but he ended up with some ink on his shoulder, even then, he wasn't too fond of my black-out tattoo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;list class=''&gt;&lt;ln class=''&gt;"What does it mean?"&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;/list&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;He asked me one day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;list class=''&gt;&lt;ln class=''&gt;"It has no meaning, it's purely aesthetic,"&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;/list&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;Then, after realizing that I'd reached the limit of his english, I simplified.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;list class=''&gt;&lt;ln class=''&gt;"It means nothing, I just like it."&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;/list&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;He spoke good enough french, but whenever I tried to talk to him his eyes went real small, as if doing this would sharpen his hearing. I always spoke to him in french first, but I'd switch to english afterwards – it's entirely possible that my accent was just too pronounced. He always did understand me in the end. The answer I gave him, about the meaning of my tattoo, in simple english, displeased him, and he began to lecture me on how silly it was to bear something permanent on your person that had no meaning. People love to lecture me about this, and I love to ignore them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src='media/blog/nukuhiva3.jpg'/&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;In the afternoon, after spending the first part of the day at the Snack, we went on walks around the island. The place had fruit trees at every corner, bearing mangos, papayas, sugar apples, coconut, pamplemousse, passion fruit and breadfruit. All of the houses were camouflaged in green, there was plenty to eat on their property. It is why in some places it was hard to find fruit, stores just don't sell them because the locals have no need of them. There was a market near the concrete pier that sold fruit, frequented by those who came on boats, planes or cruiseships. The market sold fresh vegetables too, brought by cargo ships every week. On days when the cargo ships arrived, the stands were full of fresh produce, many of them in high demand and of short supply. If you wanted tomatoes, you had to get up early at 5am to get them. We didn't care to do that. We bought local fruit instead, fresh papaya makes a good substitute for tomatoes in &lt;a href='http://grimgrains.com/#papaya+bruschetta+topping' class='external'&gt;bruschetta&lt;/a&gt;. Our staples were eggplant, sweet potato, daikon radish and cabbage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;We soon adopted the local produce too, like &lt;a href='http://grimgrains.com/#breadfruit' class='external'&gt;breadfruit&lt;/a&gt;, there is so much to say about this humble plant. It is a species of the jackfruit family, it has a potato-like flavour, but the more ripe it is the sweeter the taste. Breadfruit is a good medium, and can be made into a number of things, we experimented a lot with this during our stay in the islands. Many of the locals looked at us funny when we asked to buy them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;list class=''&gt;&lt;ln class=''&gt;"Breadfruit? That's what my grandparents eat."&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;/list&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;Not so cool with the youngsters apparently.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;During our walks on the island, we almost always regretted walking so far because of how warm it was. The deeper you walk, the more humid, and the less wind there is, and the more you ooze. A walk to the hardware store, or to the pharmacy, always resulted in us coming back looking like we'd gone for a swim.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;It's during one of these walks, that Devine contracted dengue fever. Devine had bad headaches and muscle pains, sleeping was difficult and moving was near impossible at times. We'd read about dengue and knew what it was, plus the symptoms matched up, but we weren't sure and it worried us, and so Devine went to the hospital to get a second opinion. On return, a 300$ bill to be paid in hand, Devine appeared confused.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;list class=''&gt;&lt;ln class=''&gt;"They didn't say I had dengue, but made me take scans, thinking the pains I had were maybe due to scoliosis."&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;ln class=''&gt;"What? That makes NO sense."&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;ln class=''&gt;"No. It really doesn't."&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;/list&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;Devine did have dengue, but the hospital didn't want to diagnose anyone with it. The reason for that was simple, if there is a certain number of reports, they have to declare an epidemic, which can in turn, scare all of the visitors away. Dengue is bad for business, and the polynesians depend on tourism. I understand this, Devine was healthy otherwise and in no real risk, but did wish they hadn't billed us 300$ to cover up the lie.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;Everyone in the bay knows when a cruiseship is coming, because the locals make a show of it, dressing in traditional wear and playing music. The cruiseships, the blue whale equivalent of Pino, ferry people back and forth in vessels that resemble little space shuttles, they do this all day, to and fro, morning till evening. The tourists look like tourists, pale, camera or ipad in hand, they'd buy their souvenirs, something authentic, take tours around the island and then return to their ocean castle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;Going to work at the Snack was a bad idea with a cruiseship around, it was crowded with tourists, all trying to skype to their family, a continent or two away, while in the background, chickens comically clucked and b'gawked extra harder – I suspected they knew what they were doing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;Devine did recover from dengue, but days later spotted a good friend who suffered the same. The hospital said the same thing, about it not being dengue, minus the warning about it possibly being scoliosis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;We stayed in Nuku Hiva for a long while, which permitted us to start and complete the production of our book &lt;a href='https://hundredrabbits.itch.io/thousand-rooms' class='external'&gt;Thousand rooms&lt;/a&gt;. It wasn't easy to work on this here, we seriously overerestimated our tolerance to warm weather, but we got it done still! Our open-air office, Snack Vaeki, wasn't such a bad place to work from after all, we had unlimited pamplemousse juice and the company of other sailors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;By the end of the month, we were getting restless, and decided to move to the next bay. Before doing that, we had to get some diesel. Getting diesel was not the easiest, we took our dinghy to another concrete pier at low tide (due to poor planning). Concrete piers don't float up and down but stay right where they are, to our great displeasure, we had a 6-foot ladder to climb to get onto it. I brought a rope, figured we could lower the jerry cans down into the dinghy that way. First, we got all 4 cans up, and tied Iggy to a step in the ladder. We had them filled up at the gas station, just a short walk away.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;I stood on the pier while Devine was in the dinghy below, I tied a rope to the handle of the first jerry can and lowered it, while Devine was trying to keep Iggy steady in the waves. We dropped none, operation diesel-pickup was a success.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src='media/blog/nukuhiva6.jpg'/&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;We also had to fill our water, Taioa bay was just a short sail away and was the best place to do it. The anchorage was beautiful, smaller, with high cliffs on one side, if you looked carefully you could see goats walking on its ridges, we could hear them too, bleating in succession. We asked our neighbour, a german sailor, where to get water. He smiled, and told us that he was going there now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;list class=''&gt;&lt;ln class=''&gt;"You'll have to follow me very closely, many rocks in the entrance, and current, and waves. Do like me, and you'll be okay."&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;/list&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;We followed him into the mouth of the river. There was a lot of current and swell, and the water was shallow, if we weren't careful we'd end up on the rocks for sure. The german guy was ahead of us, proceeding slowly, every now and then he pulled up his outboard, avoiding rocks no doubt. We mirrored his movements.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;list class=''&gt;&lt;ln class=''&gt;"Do like him, yes. He knows. He must know!"&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;/list&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;We said to ourselves, nervously, all the while wondering how it is he knew where the rocks were. The water wasn't any clearer here. We preferred not to dwell on this, not because it made us nervous, but because we had to focus on what was happening now. We went past the ugly bit of the river, and arrived into the calm bit, relieved. The river was long and narrow, bordered by many trees, it felt like being on the Amazon. Not that I've been on the Amazon, say, it's my mind's memory of a film about what it was like to be on the Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;The german guy arrived near a grassy shore, and tied the dinghy to a tree. We did the same.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;list class=''&gt;&lt;ln class=''&gt;"Watch your head you two, you die if you get hit in the head by a falling coconut."&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;/list&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;We looked up at the top of the tree we had moored onto, and there was, indeed, a lot of them up there, waiting to kill us perhaps, we thought, or maybe they just didn't feel like it today.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;There was a tap nearby, just a pipe sticking out of the ground with a faucet at the end of it. It didn't belong there at all. It looked like an anomaly, a glitch in the matrix.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;list class=''&gt;&lt;ln class=''&gt;"Water is very clean, very good. Best water in french polynesia!"&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;/list&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;The german guy said. Soon, a Marquesan named Paul joined us, a jolly and friendly-looking fellow. Our guide and he knew each other, in fact, the german guy gave him a hinano beer, which they cracked opened in front of us. Paul explained that the water came from the mountain, and as the german guy had said, many times already, it was very good and very clean.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;list class=''&gt;&lt;ln class=''&gt;"You sell fruit here?" We then asked.&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;ln class=''&gt;"Yes, yes! Oh! I like your tattoos! Come, I'll introduce you to my uncle, he likes tattoos too!"&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;/list&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;He also said he'd take us to pick some fruit, all from trees on his property, which was the queen's land – or something along those lines. We walked up to an old house, with skulls attached to the wood beams, and other trinkets hanging about. This was his uncle's house. The first thing we saw upon entering, was a kitten on a leash.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;list class=''&gt;&lt;ln class=''&gt;"Uncle?"&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;/list&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;But Uncle turned out to be human after all – how boring.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;Paul appeared older than Uncle, we wondered then if we'd misunderstood something, we never did find out. Uncle had long black hair, tied into a high bun, and of course, he had tattoos. He shook our hand, but didn't say much, in fact, the cat had meowed more than he'd spoken.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;Now both began to walk around the property, picking fruits for us. Uncle climbed up a tree, while Paul used a long stick to pick off mangos. In the end, we had about 10 pamplemousses, 2 papayas, 6 mangos, 3 soursops and 1 giant stalk of bananas. I looked at the stalk of bananas, trying to imagine how many banana breads I'd have to make once they'd all decide to ripen at the same time, because that's what bananas do, they synchronize, they enjoy the look of terror on our faces as their skin gets spottier, and darker with every passing day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;Iggy was very full then, with much water and fruit, we were ready for our transit to the Tuamotus. We had to ride in the ugly part of the river again to get to Pino, without our german guide this time. We managed well enough, our eyes widening with every coming swell. What a shame it would be, if all of these fruits fell into the deep.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;Our time in Nuku Hiva was at an end, but other islands and challenges lay ahead.&lt;/p&gt;]]>
    </description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>Captain, what is this?</title>
    <link>https://100r.co/blog.html</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink='false'>IV1</guid>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
    <description>
      <![CDATA[&lt;img src='media/blog/savusavu3.jpg'/&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;After 15 days on the water, you can imagine how eager we were to get into port. It was the 27th of June, we left on the 12th from Opua. We hove-to for the night, waiting for sunrise before entering &lt;a href='https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Savusavu' class='external'&gt;Savusavu bay&lt;/a&gt;. After repeated mistakes, we learned that entering a strange harbour in the dark is most unwise. There is no point in arriving early, considering yachts cannot anchor in Fiji waters before checking in, and check-in is only possible after 8am.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;At dawn, we pointed towards Vanua Levu and started sailing again, the wind at our backs. I went below to make some coffee, both of us needed a boost. Devine was in the cockpit, keeping a wary eye on a large storm cloud ahead. The wind increased as we neared it, but it did not trouble us long. We made our way inside the reef, which offered some protection from the building swells. Now closer to land, we could see rows of hills ahead, and caught the perfume of greenery with it. After that, came a sure sign of civilization: buildings, low, with green and red roofs. As we got nearer, came an even more obvious marker of civilization: cars, and small power boats. We'd arrived.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;We neared the entrance to Nakama creek around 9am, and radio'ed the authorities on channel 16.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;list class=''&gt;&lt;ln class=''&gt;"Savusavu port authority, Savusavu port authority, this is sailing vessel Pino, over."&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;/list&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;This, I repeated 3 times, no answer. We slowed down, awaiting a reply. The commercial wharf lay ahead, we could see boats on moorings, some abandonned, others belonging to people we'd seen or met accross the pacific.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;list class=''&gt;&lt;ln class=''&gt;"Sailing vessel Pino, this is Coprashed marina. There is no port authority in Savusavu, how can I help you today?"&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;ln class=''&gt;"We're looking to check in," I said.&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;ln class=''&gt;"Where did you sail from?"&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;ln class=''&gt;"Opua, New Zealand."&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;ln class=''&gt;"Did you send your advance arrival notice?"&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;ln class=''&gt;"I did send it yes, and received confirmation for it too."&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;/list&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;We'd heard they were all too severe about the advance arrival notice, which was about 10 pages too long. I'd sent it to the proper people by email, although half of the messages bounced back and other cruisers reported the same thing happening. With the document being so large, it's no wonder their inboxes are always full. I even tried again while underway, no luck. No matter, I'd received a reply from the custom office, at least one of the messages made it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;list class=''&gt;&lt;ln class=''&gt;"Continue into the harbour, past the wharf, and over to our building which stands on your starboard side. It is a white building. Once you arrive closer hail us again."&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;/list&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;We moved deeper into the creek, looking for a white building on the shore. Once we were past the wharf I called them again, they mentioned a dock and instructed us to tie to it. I didn't expect to have to dock the boat, from what we'd read online we didn't have to do that! Things do change from year to year, and from boat to boat. The fenders weren't ready, and neither were the docking lines. I ran around the boat, gathering everything, all the while trying to figure out where that damned dock was. We spotted one ahead then, with a ramp, but with no building near it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;list class=''&gt;&lt;ln class=''&gt;"Do you think that's it?"&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;ln class=''&gt;"I don't know – looks shallow, plus there's people with dive suits on it. It's probably for the locals."&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;/list&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;We glimpsed another free dock further ahead, a finger, part of the marina, it looked like a regular slip. Getting there meant moving inbetween a few boats, channel markers and moorings – the floating dock seemed a better option in comparison. Then, we saw two persons on the marina finger, waving us over. This is where we'd have to dock. Docking is always a nerve-wrecking experience, we didn't have current to contend with but perpendicular to the dock, was a large power boat, with nothing between it and our bow. If we came in too fast, we'd bump into it for sure – bumping into still objects is always embarassing. I was still attaching fenders at this point, while Devine manoeuvered Pino around various obstacles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;list class=''&gt;&lt;ln class=''&gt;"Sailing vessel Pino, this is Coprashed marina."&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;/list&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;They couldn't have picked a worse time to hail us, the dock lay ahead and two of the lines weren't yet set up. I ran inside, sweating from all the running, it was also 26C out, and I was in full foul-weather gear. Couldn't they see that we were right there and that they could ask us questions later?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;list class=''&gt;&lt;ln class=''&gt;"This is Pino."&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;/list&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;I said to them on the radio, trying to peel part of my foul weather gear off because I was cooking inside it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;list class=''&gt;&lt;ln class=''&gt;"Where was your last port again?"&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;ln class=''&gt;"Opua, New Zealand," I said.&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;/list&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;I shut off the VHF off, determined to not answer if they asked anything else. I darted back outside. We were right near the quarantine dock, I set up the last two dock lines, and threw the ends to the marina staff. We slowed to a stop, our bow drawing all too near to the boat ahead. I noticed then, the name on its side, a New Zealand boat, we'd seen them power past us on AIS on the way up here.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;All went well in the end, Pino was at the dock and we could relax. The marina staff were friendly, one of the line handlers shook our hand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;list class=''&gt;&lt;ln class=''&gt;"Bula! Bula! Welcome to Savusavu!"&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;ln class=''&gt;"Bula!" we repeated.&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;/list&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;We wished we'd bothered to learn some Fijian before arriving here. Bula could mean welcome, or hello, we hoped for the latter, us repeating "Welcome!" would be awkward indeed. We waited for the proper authorities to visit, and noticed then that the new zealand power boat had bands of yellow with 'crime scene' written all over it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;list class=''&gt;&lt;ln class=''&gt;"Is that what happens when they find undeclared veggies aboard?"&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;/list&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;We wondered, all the while becoming paranoid about the bit of ginger and pumpkin we'd hidden away. We saw police walking the docks, everyone we'd met so far was all smiles, but these guys looked serious. They wandered off for a second, I stepped off Pino, moving a few feet away, to try and take a photo of Devine and the boat to show others we'd arrived. I took a photo, but a second after, Devine motioned for me to return, a marina attendant was walking towards us as if to say that we had to stay on the boat. With the stone-faced police walking about, it was best to heed their warning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src='media/blog/savusavu.jpg'/&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;It was some time before the authorities came to see us. The first, in the long line of officials, was the health inspector. He was a friendly fellow, dressed in casual wear, a colorful blouse and sandals. He had us sign and fill papers – writing down Pino's info and our passport numbers is second nature now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;list class=''&gt;&lt;ln class=''&gt;"Is it just you two? Did anyone die aboard this vessel?"&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;ln class=''&gt;"Uh, yes and no."&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;/list&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;Important not to get those mixed up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;list class=''&gt;&lt;ln class=''&gt;"Any animals? Insects?"&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;ln class=''&gt;"Do sea birds count?"&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;/list&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;I did not say this aloud, but at sea, the thought of having a gannet friend always crossed my mind.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;list class=''&gt;&lt;ln class=''&gt;"No animals, no."&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;/list&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;Saying this, my mind screamed 'gannet friend' over and over again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;list class=''&gt;&lt;ln class=''&gt;The officer nodded. "Are you sick?"&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;ln class=''&gt;"No."&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;ln class=''&gt;"Are you sure?"&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;ln class=''&gt;"No. I mean, yes! Sure! So sure. We're so healthy."&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;/list&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;I could see him writing this down now, Rekka and Devine: "so healthy". He then began to talk to us about the mosquitoe situation. While Fiji doesn't have it as bad as other places, there have been instances of dengue. Ah, dengue, we'd first heard of it while in Japan, there was an outbreak and no one could visit the parks. I didn't know what it was back then, just that it's something you didn't want to get. Since then, we came to be very familiar with dengue, Devine contracted it in Nuku Hiva. You can say we weren't keen on a repeat, dengue is no joke. The health officer wanted to make sure we understood that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;list class=''&gt;&lt;ln class=''&gt;"Fiji doesn't want you sick." Fair enough.&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;/list&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;Then, we had a visit from the quarantine officer, an indian-fijian, who was very excited to hear that we didn't consume dairy or animals. He admitted to consumming some meat, and aspired to lessen it to none. We had a long conversation about this, and even showed him a book we had on cooking in India. We spoke about the consumption of meat, and he mentioned a lot of the health risks associated with it. Like in the west, people in Fiji too suffered because of it. I'd almost finished filling out papers, when two fijian women arrived with more. They were the customs and bio security officials. They asked to come inside. The boat was a mess, I went in and shoved everything we had in the v-berth to make room in the saloon. I also set up the table, since it appeared as though we had many more documents to fill – yay. The two women gave us the first wave of sheets to read and sign, and began to look through our lockers, asking us questions about our stores. One of them took our passports, and began to look through every page, matching the exit stamps with what we'd written on our advance arrival notice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;list class=''&gt;&lt;ln class=''&gt;"You came from Opua."&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;ln class=''&gt;"Yes."&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;ln class=''&gt;"Before this?"&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;ln class=''&gt;"Tonga."&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;ln class=''&gt;"Before this?"&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;ln class=''&gt;"Niue, cook islands, french polynesia, mexico, USA and then Canada."&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;/list&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;She looked for the stamps in our passports.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;list class=''&gt;&lt;ln class=''&gt;"Where is the mexico stamp?"&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;/list&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;Mexico and US don't stamp Canadian passports on entry and exit, it's how it is, but it was hard to make her understand this. The other woman was opening every locker, pulling out bags and asking us questions about their contents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;list class=''&gt;&lt;ln class=''&gt;"Captain, what is this?"&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;ln class=''&gt;"Lots and lots of coffee."&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;ln class=''&gt;"Beans?"&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;ln class=''&gt;"Yes, it's better kept as beans."&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;/list&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;Then the quarantine officer pushed another paper for us to sign, all while making a mess of our galley and asking questions about where we'd been. It was a dizzying experience, having so many people aboard, with the table covered in pieces of writing: 'sign this, sign that!' This moment, was made even more chaotic, with them exchanging pleasantries (we hope) in Fijian. Devine and I smiled at one another, what a strange scene, sometimes they didn't even pay attention to us at all.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;list class=''&gt;&lt;ln class=''&gt;"So, you left from Mexico when?" one of the women asked.&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;/list&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;She was inspecting every inch of our passports and had noticed how the numbers on our passports followed each other, and decided that this was suspicious. It is odd, but it's what happens when you have new passports processed together.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;list class=''&gt;&lt;ln class=''&gt;"Captain."&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;/list&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;The other woman began, she was on her hands and knees, head under the sink. She pulled away, holding the end of a hose with a bottle of mexican dry salsa wedged into it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;list class=''&gt;&lt;ln class=''&gt;"What is this?"&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;/list&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;In Rarotonga, we disconnected the water pressure hoses since we no longer had a pressure faucet. We didn't have any plugs around the boat to close them up, but what we did have, were many sample-sized bottles of mexican dry salsa, or Tajín. The bottle end was a perfect fit, and we'd since forgotten to replace them with something else.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;Devine and I looked at each other, supressing a laugh, we never thought we'd ever have to justify this crappy fix to anyone. Now we had 3 Fijian officials onboard, all looking at the bottle of salsa en polvo, waiting for an explanation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;list class=''&gt;&lt;ln class=''&gt;"It's dry salsa, from Mexico."&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;/list&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;They said nothing, and didn't ask any more about it, which was good considering there was little more we did want to say. I'm sure they've stumbled upon worse things, or it's possible that all foreign yachts stuff salsa bottles, or other oddities up their hoses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;We thought they'd only be looking through the galley cupboards and lockers, but they decided they needed to look through everything, and I do mean everything. I remembered then the pumpkin and ginger root we'd hidden, one lay under clothes in a bin, the other stuffed deep inside our dirty laundry bag. We hadn't mentioned we had these left-over, because we wanted to eat them – I care deeply about my rhizomes and squashes. I became paranoid, would they fine us for not declaring them? I could see it now, one of the women pulling a large pumpkin out of our laundry bag, eyes on us and asking, "Captain, what is this?".&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;They looked in our bilge, under the settee cushions, and in all the bags stacked up in the quarter berth too. All the while, getting nearer to the v-berth, where I had my illegal vegetables. They looked in the head, and at the plastic bags of medicines we'd inherited from Asma and Herbert from Maya. They didn't care about most of the medicines we had, but the woman did find a stack of sealed needles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;list class=''&gt;&lt;ln class=''&gt;"Captain, what is this?"&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;ln class=''&gt;"They're needles."&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;ln class=''&gt;"Why so many?"&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;/list&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;I wished I could remember why Maya had this many so I could repeat and sound like I knew what I was talking about. I didn't know what to say, but no matter, the woman found some other item of interest: our tattoo needles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;list class=''&gt;&lt;ln class=''&gt;"It's for tattoos."&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;/list&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;Then we showed them a plastic box with our tattoo machine and gear.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;list class=''&gt;&lt;ln class=''&gt;"Do you like tattoos?" Devine asked.&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;/list&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;The woman looked at Devine's neck, and at my arm.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;list class=''&gt;&lt;ln class=''&gt;"No" she said, unimpressed.&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;/list&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;The other official began telling me if I knew how to remove tattoos, as if to make sure I knew there were options in case I did change my mind about having them. This was a big contrast to the people in French Polynesia, who gave us a thumbs up as we walked past.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;The officials spent a lot of time on Pino, they were a pleasant bunch but at this point in the day we were running on fumes. We'd slept 3 hours that night, this, plus the accumulated exhaustion from 15 days of sailing. They did leave eventually, and didn't bother checking out the v-berth. By then, we'd decided they cared little about our secret stash of veggies. We later found out that the reason they did such a thorough search, was because the owners of the boat that arrived before us, the one with the 'crime scene' tape, were in jail for arriving into the country with undeclared ammunition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img src='media/blog/savusavu2.jpg'/&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;We made lunch, but could not sleep yet, we had fees to pay to the quarantine and health officers and had to go into town to get some money to do it. They told us where to find their respective offices, that Savusavu was a one-street town and that they'd be easy to find. They gave us general direction, we didn't take notes thinking we'd remember, severely overestimating the capabilities of our tired brains. We also moved our boat off the dock and onto a mooring, and pumped some air into Iggy the dinghy before going into town.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;We were looking for a green building, but none we passed looked like a proper office. This was our first excursion into town, our first look at Fiji. The city, while small, was very animated and busy, there were people everywere. Everyone we passed waved at us, "Bula!" We returned their wave and greeting – by now, we knew bula meant hello. We passed by an area packed with windowless buses, with vendors outside trying to sell its passengers soft drinks and snacks. Wild dogs roamed the streets, we passed a green space with people, sitting while chatting and sharing food. We caught a glimpse of the digicel booth, we'd have to come here later to get some data for our phones. The fresh vegetable market was right next to the bus station, looking very much like the one in Tonga, but bigger, with stalls selling indian staples. We couldn't wait to get some paw paw and breadfruit! The town had many stores: lots of hardware shops selling more or less the same content, a hideously pink grocery store called Max value, a chinese bakery etc.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;We arrived at the edge of town then, or the part of town where the street transitions from buildings to bush, and still no health or quarantine office in sight. We remembered them saying that the customs office was on the other side of town, where there were less buildings. This one, we figured, we couldn't miss. We found it straight away, picked up our passports, and asked for directions to the health and quarantine offices again. They assured us that if we kept walking the other way, that we'd find the green building.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;Devine and I dragged our tired bodies back over there, and did find a green building. The quarantice office wasn't on the street, but at the back of it. The quarantine officer took a liking to us and we talked for a long while, but our bodies longed for a rest. We must have said goodbye 10 times before he agreed to let us go. He told us how to find the health office – hopefully this time, we wouldn't forget. We walked out, and about 5 minutes into our walk, we realized that we had contradicting information.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;list class=''&gt;&lt;ln class=''&gt;"He said it's on the left and past a round-about," I said.&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;ln class=''&gt;"No, he said it's on the right close to the customs office"&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;/list&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;I felt my skin getting warmer, I couldn't believe we'd forgotten again. Dead on our feet, Devine volunteered to return to ask the chatty man about the health office again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;We did eventually find it, but we did forget something again, they couldn't provide change, we had to pay the exact amount. This, they'd told us, although neither of us remembered – a feeling all too familiar at this point. We stood there, ready to drop, I considered faking a tear then too – that's how desperate I was. Our exhaustion must have been obvious to them, because he took pity on us. He went around the office, and asked other employees for change – what a guy, oh what a guy!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;On the way out, we stopped by the Digicel booth to get some data. I would have preferred we'd go tomorrow, but Devine insisted on it. We took some amazing shots while becalmed on the ocean during our passage, and Devine wanted to put them online. We'd heard internet in Fiji was cheap, but we didn't expect to get 25G for 25$, this equates to 15$ cad. In Tonga, all we could get was 5G for 25$ (Tongan dollars). We couldn't believe it. The Digicel employees welcomed us to Savusavu, all the while staring at Devine's lip piercings like they weren't of this earth. We had a chat, and told them we came on a yacht, and right then all the employees turned to us.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;list class=''&gt;&lt;ln class=''&gt;"Did you hear of the boat with weapons? Do you know what happened?"&lt;/ln&gt;
&lt;/list&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;The ammunition boat was the talk of the town! They asked us about it and we told them what we knew, amused by how fast news traveled here. We left the stall, data in hand, brains melting, but walked past the market – we'd made enough stops for today. Arriving back on the boat, we made some dinner, I can't remember what we ate because seconds after eating it we passed out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;We're here, and we can sleep for more than 3 hours at a time - oh how grand a feeling!&lt;/p&gt;]]>
    </description>
  </item>

</channel>

</rss>