<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">

<channel>
  <title>Hundred Rabbits — Journal</title>
  <link><![CDATA[https://100r.co/blog]]></link>
  <description>The Rabbits'Journal</description>
  <generator>Oscean - Riven</generator>
  
  <item>
    <title>Where is the turtle farm?</title>
    <link>https://100r.co/blog.html</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink='false'>IV0</guid>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
    <description>
      &lt;img src="media/blog/makogai1.jpg"&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;Pino spent a long time in &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href='https://100r.co/blog.html#captain+what+is+this' class='external' target='_blank'&gt;Savusavu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;, but by then, we were growing tired of this scenery, not of the market, or of the company to be found here, but just of having that same view every morning. We love this city, but when it's time to go, it's time to go!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;We left our mooring at 9am, and moved along over to &lt;b&gt;Cousteau's resort&lt;/b&gt; to anchor (16 48.623S, 179 17.331E). The water was unclear, and the clouded sky made it difficult to see bommies beneath us. Devine dove in and checked out our anchor, which was set in sand, and we weren't near any huge coral that we could see, that is, unless the wind shifted - it was hard to see that far in cloudy water to be honest.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://100r.co/blog.html'&gt;Continue Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    </description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>Pino, projects and pain</title>
    <link>https://100r.co/blog.html</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink='false'>IV1</guid>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
    <description>
      &lt;img src="media/blog/nz2.haulout.4.jpg"&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;We arrived in New Zealand with a long, scary list of things to fix, or replace on Pino: New batteries, new mainsail, bottom-paint, galley plumbing, replace intermediates and backstay, replace top hatch, replace windows, replace control cables... etc, etc...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;If we can't finish all of these projects then we can't leave, that was the deal. There is too much ocean between us and Japan, our vessel needs to be made safe to endure it and to ensure our safe passage.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://100r.co/blog.html'&gt;Continue Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    </description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>An island to oneself</title>
    <link>https://100r.co/blog.html</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink='false'>IV2</guid>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
    <description>
      &lt;img src="media/blog/nz9.jpg"&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;Traveling to &lt;b&gt;New Zealand&lt;/b&gt;, after a year of unknown, was a great comfort to us. There are a few things Devine and I were really looking forward to, like a good latte, craft beer, a fresh food market and a bulk food store. I found a city that checked all of the boxes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;Many of the cruisers we know want to arrive in &lt;b&gt;Opua&lt;/b&gt; – with reason. It's warm, damn gorgeous, and you know you'll find friends there because that's where everyone goes during typhoon season. Arriving in a strange place with familiar faces always makes the experience better, but knowing this, we still chose &lt;b&gt;Whangarei&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://100r.co/blog.html'&gt;Continue Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    </description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>Captain, what is this?</title>
    <link>https://100r.co/blog.html</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink='false'>IV3</guid>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
    <description>
      &lt;img src="media/blog/savusavu3.jpg"&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;After 15 days on the water, you can imagine how eager we were to get into port. It was the 27th of June, we left on the 12th from Opua. We hove-to for the night, waiting for sunrise before entering &lt;a href='https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Savusavu' class='external' target='_blank'&gt;Savusavu bay&lt;/a&gt;. After repeated mistakes, we learned that entering a strange harbour in the dark is most unwise. There is no point in arriving early, considering yachts cannot anchor in Fiji waters before checking in, and check-in is only possible after 8am.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;At dawn, we pointed towards Vanua Levu and started sailing again, the wind at our backs. I went below to make some coffee, both of us needed a boost. Devine was in the cockpit, keeping a wary eye on a large storm cloud ahead. The wind increased as we neared it, but it did not trouble us long. We made our way inside the reef, which offered some protection from the building swells. Now closer to land, we could see rows of hills ahead, and caught the perfume of greenery with it. After that, came a sure sign of civilization: buildings, low, with green and red roofs. As we got nearer, came an even more obvious marker of civilization: cars, and small power boats. We'd arrived.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://100r.co/blog.html'&gt;Continue Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    </description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>The rock of polynesia</title>
    <link>https://100r.co/blog.html</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink='false'>IV4</guid>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
    <description>
      &lt;img src="media/blog/niue1.jpg"&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;&lt;b&gt;Niue&lt;/b&gt;, pronounced 'New-ay', a rock in the pacific, one of the largest coral islands on earth. It's the first country to offer free, state-funded, wireless internet to all its residents and has a goal of being completely &lt;a href='https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Niue' class='external' target='_blank'&gt;solar powered&lt;/a&gt; - uh. Wow?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;We'd also heard that the school gave all of the kids laptops, this, with free internet, makes it a paradise for game devs. Already then, we made plans to move there, like all places in the tropics with a good connection and supply of coconut and beer. I remember when we were speaking of staying in &lt;a class='local' href='#nuku+hiva' title='Nuku Hiva' onclick="app.load('Nuku Hiva')"&gt;Nuku Hiva&lt;/a&gt; too, and in La Paz. We make a home everywhere we go. This, makes it hard to leave, but this ease of adaptation also makes us eager to go forward, to see where else we could live. This is what we do, we set up house in different places, sometimes for 8 months at a time.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://100r.co/blog.html'&gt;Continue Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    </description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>Internet in paradise</title>
    <link>https://100r.co/blog.html</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink='false'>IV5</guid>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
    <description>
      &lt;img src="media/blog/huahine1.jpg"&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;&lt;b&gt;Huahine&lt;/b&gt;, one of the many grouped islands in &lt;a href='https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/French_Polynesia' class='external' target='_blank'&gt;French Polynesia&lt;/a&gt;. Our plans for future ocean voyaging could have ended there though, because we almost crashed onto a reef.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;Since we always time our arrival with the morning sun, I almost always get the first look of every island. Huahine stood in front of us, a series of volcanic peaks marked by deep valleys and blanketed in green, an island that came into being million of years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://100r.co/blog.html'&gt;Continue Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    </description>
  </item>

  <item>
    <title>Rainy with a chance of mosquitoes</title>
    <link>https://100r.co/blog.html</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <guid isPermaLink='false'>IV6</guid>
    <dc:creator><![CDATA[Rekka Bellum]]></dc:creator>
    <description>
      &lt;img src="media/blog/nukuhiva1.jpg"&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;&lt;b&gt;Nuku Hiva&lt;/b&gt;, a green island in the pacific, straight out of Jurassic Park, just as foreign and just as wild, except instead of hungry lizards there are hungry, angry mosquitoes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class=''&gt;I had no idea what it was going to be like there, I'd barely read anything about it. I knew where we'd anchor, that people spoke french and that there would be baguettes, but beyond that it was a blur, a black spot in my mind. I read the book &lt;b&gt;Fourteen&lt;/b&gt; during our 28-day transit from La Paz. In this book, the family had sailed to Nuku Hiva, but all in all their experience there was not so good. It wasn't made bad because of the Marquesans, or the island itself, but because of no-no's – little bugs that bite that hide in sand. I took a mental note of this:&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='https://100r.co/blog.html'&gt;Continue Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    </description>
  </item>

</channel>

</rss>